<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
  <author xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Heroes Patch Notes</name></author>
  <title type="text">Full Patches - Heroes Patch Notes.com</title>
  <updated>2018-04-24T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
  <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/feed/full-patches.xml</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/feed/full-patches.xml" />
  <icon>https://heroespatchnotes.com/favicon-32x32.png</icon>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-04-24 Patch Notes</title>
    <published>2018-04-24T16:15:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-04-24T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-04-24-patch-notes.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-04-24-patch-notes.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-patch-notes-april-24-2018">Heroes of the Storm Patch Notes – April 24, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1494956881/patchlogo2017-05-16.jpg"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21719349" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21719349" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.32.0</small></div>

<p>Deckard Cain has joined the Nexus with our latest Heroes of the Storm patch!
Read on to learn more about the new Support Hero, as well as a number of new
balance changes, skins, mounts, and more.</p>

<p><span class="text-warning"><strong>NOTE: Orange text indicates a difference between the PTR and Live patch notes.</strong></span></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="general">General</h3>

<p><strong>Home Screen Rework</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Heroes of the Storm’s Home Screen has received significant improvements.</span>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">A secondary navigation bar has been added near the top of the Home Screen, beneath the existing Play, Collection, Loot, and Watch buttons.</span>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Click each tab on the Home Screen navigation bar to switch among different categories of Heroes-related news.</span></li>
<li><span class="text-warning">Home Screen tabs will be updated regularly, and will commonly include information about the latest Hero, the current in-game event, Heroes Esports, and more.</span></li>
</ul></li>
<li><span class="text-warning">Each Home Screen tab features additional news items near the bottom of the screen, which can be clicked to find out more details about that topic.</span>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">For example: Home Screen buttons may link to Heroes and other items in the Collection, the latest Hero Spotlight Video, the Heroes Global Championship Schedule, and more.</span></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="new-hero-deckard">New Hero: Deckard</h3>

<p>An avid scholar, Deckard Cain has dedicated his life to the pursuit of
knowledge. He has been an advisor, storyteller, and friend to Sanctuary’s
greatest heroes, guiding them through peril time and again. When Deckard
speaks, it’s wise to stay awhile and listen.</p>

<p><strong>Trait</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Fortitude of the Faithful</strong>
<ul>
<li>When at least 1 other allied Hero is nearby, Deckard gains 10 Armor and his Basic Abilities recharge 50% faster.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Basic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Healing Potion (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Toss a Healing Potion on the ground that heals the first allied Hero that comes in contact with it for 230.</li>
<li>Limit 5 active Potions.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Horadric Cube (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Throw the Horadric Cube, dealing 80 damage to all enemies in the area and Slowing them by 40% for 1.75 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Scroll of Sealing (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Unfurl an enchanted scroll, forming a triangle that deals 150 damage to enemies inside and Roots them for 1.5 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Stay Awhile and Listen (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>After 1 second, Channel for 3 seconds, putting enemy Heroes in front of Deckard to Sleep while Channeling, and for 2 seconds after.</li>
<li>Enemies can only be put to Sleep once per cast, and Sleep’s effects end instantly if they take damage.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Lorenado (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Vector Targeting.</li>
<li>Create a swirling lorenado that travels in the targeted direction, continually knocking away any enemies that come into contact with it.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="art">Art</h3>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Gul’dan:</strong> Has received updated visual effects to make his Abilities easier to spot during battle.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="user-interface">User Interface</h3>

<p><strong>Draft Mode</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Hero portraits in Draft Lobbies will now use 2D Base Hero art rather than animated 3D Hero Skin models in order to help make Hero picks easier to differentiate from one another at a glance.
<ul>
<li>For example: It should now be easier to tell whether a teammate has selected Falstad or Muradin during a draft.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="design">Design</h3>

<p><strong>Quests</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Skillshots, as well as other Abilities and Talents that search for targets, will now pass through Invulnerable targets without granting quest progress.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="battlegrounds">Battlegrounds</h3>

<p><strong>Warhead Junction</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning"><strong>Neutral Swarm Host Boss</strong></span>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Will no longer burrow while defending its camp.</span></li>
<li><span class="text-warning"><strong>Slime Pods</strong></span>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Pod impact locations will now display warning indicators on the terrain.</span></li>
<li><span class="text-warning">Pods now explode immediately on impact, and no longer spawn Podlings.</span></li>
<li><span class="text-warning">Increased the number of Pods launched per cast.</span></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><span class="text-warning"><strong>Captured Swarm Host Boss</strong></span>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">All of the above changes also apply to captured Swarm Hosts.</span></li>
<li><span class="text-warning"><strong>Slime Trail</strong></span>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Removed.</span></li>
</ul></li>
<li><span class="text-warning"><strong>Slime Pods</strong></span>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Pods can now target Structures.</span></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><span class="text-warning"><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> We believe the Warhead Junction boss is a cool
  variant of the standard golem boss found on most maps, but it had some
  inconsistencies that needed addressing. These changes essentially make the
  boss a better version of itself—its neutral and captured versions are closer
  in power, and its Slime Pods create a cooler moment than its Podlings did
  previously.</span></p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="heroes">Heroes</h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><a href="#assassin">Assassin</a></th>
  <th><a href="#specialist">Specialist</a></th>
  <th><a href="#warrior">Warrior</a></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#cassia">Cassia</a></td>
  <td><a href="#sylvanas">Sylvanas</a></td>
  <td><a href="#blaze">Blaze</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#fenix">Fenix</a></td>
  <td><a href="#zagara">Zagara</a></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#genji">Genji</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="assassin">Assassin</h3>

<h4 id="cassia">Cassia</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Surge of Light (Active)
<ul>
<li>Now has a 0.25 second cooldown between uses.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="fenix">Fenix</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mobile Offensive (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Now grants its Basic Attack damage bonus after any movement, rather than only after unmounted movement.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="genji">Genji</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Health increased from 1550 to 1620.</li>
<li>Health Regen increased from 3.2304 to 3.3750.</li>
<li>Basic Attack damage increased from 42 to 44.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Cyber Agility (Trait) (D)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 10 to 12 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Swift Strike (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Range reduced from 14 to 12.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Dragonblade (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage increased from 220 to 240.</li>
<li>Removed functionality:
<ul>
<li>Killing an enemy Hero who was recently hit by Dragonblade no longer resets Swift Strike’s cooldown.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Agile Dismount (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduction increased from 5 to 7 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Double Jump (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>No longer increases Cyber Agility’s cooldown.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Dragon Becomes Me (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Additional Functionality:
<ul>
<li>Now also resets Swift Strike’s cooldown if an enemy Hero dies within 2 seconds after being hit by Dragonblade.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> We’re making some changes to Genji to try and make
  him less frustrating to play against and give opponents more options with
  which to counter him. While we think resetting Swift Strike’s cooldown after
  killing enemy Heroes with Dragonblade made for cool, flashy plays, it shut
  down too many other Heroes too often. It also caused too many games to become
  about how much value Genji was able to get out of Dragonblade and little else.
  We like the flashiness that Dragonblade resets can provide, so we’re keeping
  that functionality, but we’re now adding it to his Level 20 Storm Talent
  version of the Heroic. We’re also increasing his Health and Basic Attack
  damage, reducing the range of Swift Strike, and increasing the cooldown of
  Cyber Agility to reduce his mobility while boosting his base stats to
  compensate.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="specialist">Specialist</h3>

<h4 id="sylvanas">Sylvanas</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Shadow Dagger (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shadow Dagger now briefly reveals enemies upon spreading to them.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="zagara">Zagara</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Nydus Network (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>The player can now exit Nydus Worms in a direction of their choosing by right-clicking.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="warrior">Warrior</h3>

<h4 id="blaze">Blaze</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Bunker Drop (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Players can now exit Blaze's Bunker in the direction of their choosing by right-clicking.</li>
<li>The Bunker’s hitbox has been adjusted to more closely match its model. This should reduce situations in which players could unintentionally enter Blaze’s bunker when clicking nearby.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="collection">Collection</h3>

<p><strong>New Bundles</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The following new bundles are available for a limited time! Be sure to check out the latest <a href="https://battle.net/heroes/blog/21671839">In-Development blog</a> for more details.
<ul>
<li>Deckard Heroic Bundle</li>
<li>Nephalem Bundle</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Announcers</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Deckard</li>
<li>Raven Lord</li>
<li>Grave Keeper</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Skins</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Deckard</strong>
<ul>
<li>Afflicted Deckard</li>
<li>Angelic Deckard</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Wastewalker Deckard</strong>
<ul>
<li>Diesel Wastewalker Deckard</li>
<li>Scourged Wastewalker Deckard</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Cassia</strong>
<ul>
<li>Soaring Cassia</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Johanna</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nephalem Johanna</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Kharazim</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nephalem Kharazim</li>
<li>Northern Kharazim</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Li-Ming</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nephalem Li-Ming</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Malthael</strong>
<ul>
<li>Sinuous Grave Warden Malthael</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Nazeebo</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nephalem Nazeebo</li>
<li>Ceremonial Nazeebo</li>
<li>Rain Nazeebo</li>
<li>Sunrise Nazeebo</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Sonya</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nephalem Sonya</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>The Butcher</strong>
<ul>
<li>Petrified Butcher</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Valla</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nephalem Valla</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Mounts</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Road Chariot</strong>
<ul>
<li>Exalted Road Chariot</li>
<li>Hoarfrost Road Chariot</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Mount Removal</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Lucky Piggy Bank</strong></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Portraits and Sprays</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>We've once again teamed up with Carbot Animations to add even more HeroStorm-themed portraits and sprays in their signature art style! Catch a preview in the latest <a href="https://battle.net/heroes/blog/21671839">In-Development blog</a>.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fixed a number of typo and tooltip errors across several aspects of the game.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>A.I.</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause A.I. Hanzo to repeatedly Channel and cancel Storm Bow.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Art</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> Icon art has been swapped for the Adhesive Petroleum and Oil Dispersal Talents.</li>
<li><strong>Lunar Sylvanas:</strong> Fixed an issue causing Lunar Sylvanas to play an incorrect animation on the Most Played screen.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Battlegrounds</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Checkpoint: Hanamura (Brawl):</strong> The Brawl Info tooltip now correctly states that Health Packs restore 35% Health and Mana.</li>
<li><strong>Tomb of the Spider Queen:</strong> The left-side team’s bottom Fort can no longer attack enemy Heroes who are just beyond the Gate.</li>
<li><strong>Try Mode:</strong> Tychus’ Dash Talent now correctly grants its Movement Speed reward after using the Complete Quests button.</li>
<li><strong>Try Mode:</strong> Uther’s Silver Touch Talent now correctly grants its second Mana cost reduction reward to Holy Light after using the Complete Quests button.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Abathur:</strong> The number of Minions Absorbed stacks no longer appear inconsistent in the Buff bar after Abathur dies while a Monstrosity is active.</li>
<li><strong>Abathur:</strong> Fixed an issue causing Spike Burst’s visual effects to appear much larger than intended when cast while targeting a Mercenary with Symbiote.</li>
<li><strong>Alarak:</strong> Free Lightning Surge casts granted by the Lightning Barrage Talent now correctly display its cast range indicator.</li>
<li><strong>Ana:</strong> Nano Boost’s duration bar now appears next to, rather than replaces, any existing Ability duration bars for the targeted Ally, like Sonya’s Whirlwind.</li>
<li><strong>Brightwing:</strong> Can now correctly cast Blink Heal on Turrets and Biotic Emitters that were placed by Brightwing herself.</li>
<li><strong>Cho:</strong> Entering a Stasis effect, like Zeratul’s Void Prison, while Surging Fist is charging no longer places Surging Fist on full cooldown.</li>
<li><strong>Fog of War:</strong> Hitting an enemy with certain targeted, ranged Abilities, like Sylvanas’ Shadow Dagger, just before the target enters Fog of War or a Line of Sight Blocker now correctly reveal that enemy.</li>
<li><strong>Fog of War:</strong> Fixed an issue in which attempting to cast a targeted Ability through the Fog of War on a snapshot of a unit that no longer exists could cause the Hero to path into the terrain and become stuck.</li>
<li><strong>Greymane:</strong> Partial progress earned toward the Wizened Duelist Talent’s next attack damage bonus will no longer persist after dying.</li>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Natural Agility now activates correctly after being hit by Phase Prism near a tower.</li>
<li><strong>Illidan:</strong> Can now correctly cast Dive on Ragnaros in Molten Core form.</li>
<li><strong>Kel’Thuzad:</strong> Phylactery can no longer be activated before its animation completes.</li>
<li><strong>Li-Ming:</strong> Spell Armor granted by the Force Armor Talent is now correctly consumed when hit by Ability damage from non-Heroic sources.</li>
<li><strong>Rexxar:</strong> The tooltip for Misha, Focus! no longer lists a cooldown.</li>
<li><strong>Rexxar:</strong> Switching seats in a Triglav Protector no longer causes Rexxar to become unresponsive.</li>
<li><strong>The Lost Vikings:</strong> Stealth granted by the Spy Games Talent is now correctly applied for 3 seconds after Erik moves.</li>
<li><strong>Thrall:</strong> Killing Minions who were hit by Chain Lightning now correctly causes Echo of the Elements quest progress visual effects to appear near Thrall, rather than allies.</li>
<li><strong>Uther:</strong> Fixed an issue in which Uther could briefly use activated Talents after death, but prior to entering Eternal Vanguard form.</li>
<li><strong>Uther:</strong> The Silver Touch Talent’s quest rewards no longer incorrectly benefit Flash of Light.</li>
<li><strong>Zagara:</strong> The Infest Talent now correctly boosts nearby Ranged Minion damage by 100%.</li>
<li><strong>Zeratul:</strong> After death, Zeratul’s body will no longer teleport to the location of his last Vorpal Blade target.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Sound</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Gul’dan:</strong> The voiceover line that plays while idling on Gul’dan’s Hero page in the Collection no longer ends early.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>User Interface</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Pings:</strong> Fixed an issue in which muting a player would not prevent icons related to that player’s pings from appearing.</li>
<li><strong>Hotkeys:</strong> Fixed an issue that could occasionally cause Heroes to ignore Force Move commands.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<p><strong><a href="https://battle.net/forums/heroes/index">Click here to discuss this post with other players in the official Heroes of the Storm forums</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-04-16 PTR Patch Notes</title>
    <published>2018-04-16T17:39:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-04-16T17:39:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-04-16-ptr-patch-notes.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-04-16-ptr-patch-notes.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-ptr-patch-notes-april-16-2018">Heroes of the Storm PTR Patch Notes – April 16, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1494956881/patchlogo2017-05-16.jpg"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21671838" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21671838" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.32.0</small></div>

<p>Our next Heroes of the Storm patch has just hit the Public Test Realm and will
be available for playtesting until April 23. As always, if you encounter any
bugs during your PTR play sessions, please stop by the <a href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en/forum/20013840/">PTR Bug Report
forum</a> to let us know about
your experiences.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="new-hero-deckard">New Hero: Deckard</h3>

<p>An avid scholar, Deckard Cain has dedicated his life to the pursuit of
knowledge. He has been an advisor, storyteller, and friend to Sanctuary’s
greatest heroes, guiding them through peril time and again. When Deckard
speaks, it’s wise to stay awhile and listen.</p>

<p><strong>Trait</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Fortitude of the Faithful</strong>
<ul>
<li>When at least 1 other allied Hero is nearby, Deckard gains 10 Armor and his Basic Abilities recharge 50% faster.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Basic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Healing Potion (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Toss a Healing Potion on the ground that heals the first allied Hero that comes in contact with it for 230.</li>
<li>Limit 5 active Potions.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Horadric Cube (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Throw the Horadric Cube, dealing 80 damage to all enemies in the area and Slowing them by 40% for 1.75 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Scroll of Sealing (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Unfurl an enchanted scroll, forming a triangle that deals 150 damage to enemies inside and Roots them for 1.5 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Stay Awhile and Listen (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>After 1 second, Channel for 3 seconds, putting enemy Heroes in front of Deckard to Sleep while Channeling, and for 2 seconds after.</li>
<li>Enemies can only be put to Sleep once per cast, and Sleep’s effects end instantly if they take damage.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Lorenado (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Vector Targeting.</li>
<li>Create a swirling lorenado that travels in the targeted direction, continually knocking away any enemies that come into contact with it.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="art">Art</h3>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Gul’dan:</strong> Has received updated visual effects to make his Abilities easier to spot during battle.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="user-inteface">User Inteface</h3>

<p><strong>Draft Mode</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Hero portraits in Draft Lobbies will now use 2D Base Hero art rather than animated 3D Hero Skin models in order to help make Hero picks easier to differentiate from one another at a glance.
<ul>
<li>For example: It should now be easier to tell whether a teammate has selected Falstad or Muradin during a draft.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="design">Design</h3>

<p><strong>Quests</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Skillshots, as well as other Abilities and Talents that search for targets, will now pass through Invulnerable targets without granting quest progress.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="heroes">Heroes</h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><a href="#assassin">Assassin</a></th>
  <th><a href="#specialist">Specialist</a></th>
  <th><a href="#warrior">Warrior</a></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#cassia">Cassia</a></td>
  <td><a href="#sylvanas">Sylvanas</a></td>
  <td><a href="#blaze">Blaze</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#fenix">Fenix</a></td>
  <td><a href="#zagara">Zagara</a></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#genji">Genji</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="assassin">Assassin</h3>

<h4 id="cassia">Cassia</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Surge of Light (Active)
<ul>
<li>Now has a 0.25 second cooldown between uses.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="fenix">Fenix</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mobile Offensive (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Now grants its Basic Attack damage bonus after any movement, rather than only after unmounted movement.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="genji">Genji</h4>

<p><strong>PTR Note:</strong> <em>Shortly before releasing today’s patch we discovered a bug affecting Genji’s Shuriken (Q). This will likely result in difficult gameplay experiences for those attempting to test Genji’s changes in the PTR. We are working to resolve the issue before this patch is released to the live version of Heroes of the Storm next week. We apologize for any inconvenience this may cause.</em></p>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Health increased from 1550 to 1620.</li>
<li>Health Regen increased from 3.2304 to 3.3750.</li>
<li>Basic Attack damage increased from 42 to 44.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Cyber Agility (Trait) (D)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 10 to 12 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Swift Strike (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Range reduced from 14 to 12.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Dragonblade (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage increased from 220 to 240.</li>
<li>Removed functionality:
<ul>
<li>Killing an enemy Hero who was recently hit by Dragonblade no longer resets Swift Strike’s cooldown.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Agile Dismount (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduction increased from 5 to 7 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Double Jump (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>No longer increases Cyber Agility’s cooldown.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Dragon Becomes Me (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Additional Functionality:
<ul>
<li>Now also resets Swift Strike’s cooldown if an enemy Hero dies within 2 seconds after being hit by Dragonblade.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> We’re making some changes to Genji to try and make
  him less frustrating to play against and give opponents more options to
  counter him. While we think resetting Swift Strike’s cooldown after killing
  enemy Heroes with Dragonblade made for cool, flashy plays, it shut down too
  many other Heroes too often. It also caused too many games to become about how
  much value Genji was able to get out of Dragonblade. We like the flashiness
  that Dragonblade resets can provide, so we’re keeping that functionality, but
  we’re now adding it to his Level 20 Storm Talent version of the Heroic. We’re
  also increasing his Health and Basic Attack damage, reducing the range of
  Swift Strike, and increasing the cooldown of Cyber Agility to reduce his
  mobility while boosting his base stats to compensate.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="specialist">Specialist</h3>

<h4 id="sylvanas">Sylvanas</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Shadow Dagger (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shadow Dagger now briefly reveals enemies upon spreading to them.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="zagara">Zagara</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Nydus Network (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>The player can now exit Nydus Worms in a direction of their choosing by right-clicking.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="warrior">Warrior</h3>

<h4 id="blaze">Blaze</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Bunker Drop (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Players can now exit Blaze's Bunker in the direction of their choosing by right-clicking.</li>
<li>The Bunker’s hitbox has been adjusted to more closely match its model. This should reduce situations in which players could unintentionally enter Blaze’s bunker when clicking nearby.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="collection">Collection</h3>

<p><strong>New Bundles</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The following new bundles are available for a limited time! Be sure to check out the latest <a href="https://battle.net/heroes/blog/21671839">In-Development blog</a> for more details.
<ul>
<li>Deckard Heroic Bundle</li>
<li>Nephalem Bundle</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Announcers</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Deckard</li>
<li>Raven Lord</li>
<li>Grave Keeper</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Skins</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Deckard</strong>
<ul>
<li>Afflicted Deckard</li>
<li>Angelic Deckard</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Wastewalker Deckard</strong>
<ul>
<li>Diesel Wastewalker Deckard</li>
<li>Scourged Wastewalker Deckard</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Cassia</strong>
<ul>
<li>Soaring Cassia</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Johanna</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nephalem Johanna</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Kharazim</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nephalem Kharazim</li>
<li>Northern Kharazim</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Li-Ming</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nephalem Li-Ming</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Malthael</strong>
<ul>
<li>Sinuous Grave Warden Malthael</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Nazeebo</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nephalem Nazeebo</li>
<li>Ceremonial Nazeebo</li>
<li>Rain Nazeebo</li>
<li>Sunrise Nazeebo</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Sonya</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nephalem Sonya</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>The Butcher</strong>
<ul>
<li>Petrified Butcher</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Valla</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nephalem Valla</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Mounts</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Road Chariot</strong>
<ul>
<li>Exalted Road Chariot</li>
<li>Hoarfrost Road Chariot</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Mount Removal</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Lucky Piggy Bank</strong>
<ul>
<li>The Lucky Piggy Bank Mount, which can only be purchased using gold, will be removed from the Collection when this patch is released to the live version of Heroes next week.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Portraits and Sprays</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>We've once again teamed up with Carbot Animations to add even more HeroStorm-themed portraits and sprays in their signature art style! Catch a preview in the latest <a href="https://battle.net/heroes/blog/21671839">In-Development blog</a>.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fixed a number of typo and tooltip errors across several aspects of the game.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>A.I.</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause A.I. Hanzo to repeatedly Channel and cancel Storm Bow.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Art</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> Icon art has been swapped for the Adhesive Petroleum and Oil Dispersal Talents.</li>
<li><strong>Lunar Sylvanas:</strong> Fixed an issue causing Lunar Sylvanas to play an incorrect animation on the Most Played screen.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Battlegrounds</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Checkpoint: Hanamura (Brawl):</strong> The Brawl Info tooltip now correctly states that Health Packs restore 35% Health and Mana.</li>
<li><strong>Tomb of the Spider Queen:</strong> The left-side team’s bottom Fort can no longer attack enemy Heroes who are just beyond the Gate.</li>
<li><strong>Try Mode:</strong> Tychus’ Dash Talent now correctly grants its Movement Speed reward after using the Complete Quests button.</li>
<li><strong>Try Mode:</strong> Uther’s Silver Touch Talent now correctly grants its second Mana cost reduction reward to Holy Light after using the Complete Quests button.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Abathur:</strong> The number of Minions Absorbed stacks no longer appear inconsistent in the Buff bar after Abathur dies while a Monstrosity is active.</li>
<li><strong>Abathur:</strong> Fixed an issue causing Spike Burst’s visual effects to appear much larger than intended when cast while targeting a Mercenary with Symbiote.</li>
<li><strong>Alarak:</strong> Free Lightning Surge casts granted by the Lightning Barrage Talent now correctly display its cast range indicator.</li>
<li><strong>Ana:</strong> Nano Boost’s duration bar now appears next to, rather than replaces, any existing Ability duration bars for the targeted Ally, like Sonya’s Whirlwind.</li>
<li><strong>Brightwing:</strong> Can now correctly cast Blink Heal on Turrets and Biotic Emitters that were placed by Brightwing herself.</li>
<li><strong>Cho:</strong> Entering a Stasis effect, like Zeratul’s Void Prison, while Surging Fist is charging no longer places Surging Fist on full cooldown.</li>
<li><strong>Fog of War:</strong> Hitting an enemy with certain targeted, ranged Abilities, like Sylvanas’ Shadow Dagger, just before the target enters Fog of War or a Line of Sight Blocker now correctly reveal that enemy.</li>
<li><strong>Fog of War:</strong> Fixed an issue in which attempting to cast a targeted Ability through the Fog of War on a snapshot of a unit that no longer exists could cause the Hero to path into the terrain and become stuck.</li>
<li><strong>Greymane:</strong> Partial progress earned toward the Wizened Duelist Talent’s next attack damage bonus will no longer persist after dying.</li>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Natural Agility now activates correctly after being hit by Phase Prism near a tower.</li>
<li><strong>Illidan:</strong> Can now correctly cast Dive on Ragnaros in Molten Core form.</li>
<li><strong>Kel’Thuzad:</strong> Phylactery can no longer be activated before its animation completes.</li>
<li><strong>Li-Ming:</strong> Spell Armor granted by the Force Armor Talent is now correctly consumed when hit by Ability damage from non-Heroic sources.</li>
<li><strong>Rexxar:</strong> The tooltip for Misha, Focus! no longer lists a cooldown.</li>
<li><strong>Rexxar:</strong> Switching seats in a Triglav Protector no longer causes Rexxar to become unresponsive.</li>
<li><strong>The Lost Vikings:</strong> Stealth granted by the Spy Games Talent is now correctly applied for 3 seconds after Erik moves.</li>
<li><strong>Thrall:</strong> Killing Minions who were hit by Chain Lightning now correctly causes Echo of the Elements quest progress visual effects to appear near Thrall, rather than allies.</li>
<li><strong>Uther:</strong> Fixed an issue in which Uther could briefly use activated Talents after death, but prior to entering Eternal Vanguard form.</li>
<li><strong>Uther:</strong> The Silver Touch Talent’s quest rewards no longer incorrectly benefit Flash of Light.</li>
<li><strong>Zagara:</strong> The Infest Talent now correctly boosts nearby Ranged Minion damage by 100%.</li>
<li><strong>Zeratul:</strong> After death, Zeratul’s body will no longer teleport to the location of his last Vorpal Blade target.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Sound</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Gul’dan:</strong> The voiceover line that plays while idling on Gul’dan’s Hero page in the Collection no longer ends early.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>User Interface</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Pings:</strong> Fixed an issue in which muting a player would not prevent icons related to that player’s pings from appearing.</li>
<li><strong>Hotkeys:</strong> Fixed an issue that could occasionally cause Heroes to ignore Force Move commands.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-04-12 Hotfix Patch</title>
    <published>2018-04-13T01:41:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-04-13T01:41:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-04-12-hotfix-patch.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-04-12-hotfix-patch.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-hotfix-notes-april-12-2018">Heroes of the Storm Hotfix Notes – April 12, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1494956881/patchlogo2017-05-16.jpg"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/" target="_blank"></a><a href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.31.3</small></div>

<p>We’ve just released a new hotfix for Heroes of the Storm in order to apply a bug fix.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Nova:</strong> Fixed an issue in which Perfect Shot’s cooldown reduction could be applied to Snipe multiple times per cast after learning Explosive Round.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<p>We also released a patch on April 11, which included many balance changes and bug fixes. <a href="https://battle.net/heroes/blog/21656682">You can review those patch notes by clicking here</a>.</p>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-04-11 Balance Update</title>
    <published>2018-04-12T01:25:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-04-12T01:25:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-04-11-balance-update.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-04-11-balance-update.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-patch-notes-april-11-2018">Heroes of the Storm Patch Notes – April 11, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1485586192/balanceupdate.png"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21656682" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21656682" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.31.2</small></div>

<p>Our most recent Heroes of the Storm patch is now live containing a number of
balance changes and bug fixes.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="heroes">Heroes</h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><a href="#assassin">Assassin</a></th>
  <th><a href="#multiclass">Multiclass</a></th>
  <th><a href="#specialist">Specialist</a></th>
  <th><a href="#support">Support</a></th>
  <th><a href="#warrior">Warrior</a></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#falstad">Falstad</a></td>
  <td><a href="#varian">Varian</a></td>
  <td><a href="#medivh">Medivh</a></td>
  <td><a href="#kharazim">Kharazim</a></td>
  <td><a href="#chen">Chen</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#fenix">Fenix</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td><a href="#sylvanas">Sylvanas</a></td>
  <td><a href="#malfurion">Malfurion</a></td>
  <td><a href="#dehaka">Dehaka</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#hanzo">Hanzo</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
  <td><a href="#leoric">Leoric</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#li-ming">Li-Ming</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
  <td><a href="#tyrael">Tyrael</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#nova">Nova</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
  <td><a href="#zarya">Zarya</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#tracer">Tracer</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="assassin">Assassin</h3>

<h4 id="falstad">Falstad</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Gathering Storm (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Added functionality:
<ul>
<li>Every Hero Hammerang hits also returns 10 Mana.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Wingman (Active)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Added functionality:
<ul>
<li>Reduces Lightning Rod’s cooldown by 3 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Updraft (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Added functionality:
<ul>
<li>Removes the duration of Shields granted by Barrel Roll.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="fenix">Fenix</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Basic Attack damage reduced from 96 to 86.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Plasma Cutter (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 145 to 135.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Planet Cracker (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage increased from 105 to 108.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Advanced Targeting (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage bonus reduced from 0.75 to 0.5.</li>
<li>Maximum bonus damage reduced from 75 to 60.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Arsenal Synergy (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage bonus increased from 100% to 175%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Emergency Protocol (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Movement Speed bonus reduced from 30% to 25%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Combat Advantage (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage bonus against Slowed targets reduced from 50% to 40%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Auxiliary Shields (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shield regeneration reduced from 20% to 15% of Basic Attack damage dealt.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Dampening Field (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Spell Armor increased from 15 to 20.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Rapid Recharge (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shield recharge increased from 20% to 40% of healing received.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Singularity Charge (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Repeater Cannon bonus Attack Speed increased from 50% to 100%.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Unconquered Spirit (Passive)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shield amount increased from 600 to 800.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> Fenix has proven himself quite powerful, mainly due
  to his capability for consistent damage output. While we’re happy with how he
  plays, we’re making a few changes to bring his damage in line and address
  Talent imbalances.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="hanzo">Hanzo</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Natural Agility (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 20 to 25 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Dragon Strike (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage increased from 64 to 70.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Serrated Arrows (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Bonus damage granted versus Minions, Mercenaries, and Monsters reduced from 150% to 100%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="li-ming">Li-Ming</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Aether Walker (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Reduced the time required after taking damage from 5 to 4 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Dominance (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Adjusted functionality:
<ul>
<li>Takedowns now restore 30% of missing Health.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="nova">Nova</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Perfect Shot (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Added functionality:
<ul>
<li>Each Hero hit also grants an additional Precision Sniper stack.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ionic Force Field (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Armor duration increased from 2 to 3 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Double Tap (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Added functionality:
<ul>
<li>Also increases Pinning Shot’s cooldown by 2 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Lethal Decoy (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Holo Decoy damage bonus reduced from 35% to 30%.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Crippling Shot (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Armor negation reduced from 25 to 20.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Explosive Round (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Area of effect damage increased from 50% to 70%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="tracer">Tracer</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Health reduced from 1350 to 1280.</li>
<li>Health Regeneration reduced from 5.625 to 5.332.</li>
<li>Basic Attack damage reduced from 29 to 28.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="multiclass">Multiclass</h3>

<h4 id="varian">Varian</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Health increased from 1850 to 1924.</li>
<li>Health Regeneration increased from 3.8554 to 4.0078.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Taunt (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Bonus Health and Health Regeneration reduced from 30% to 25%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="specialist">Specialist</h3>

<h4 id="medivh">Medivh</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Force of Magic (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Bonus Spell Power increased from 20% to 25%.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Arcane Explosion (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Base damage reduced from 90 to 80.</li>
<li>Maximum additional damage reduced from 350 to 315.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Circle of Protection (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Now also increases Force of Will’s cooldown by 2 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Reabsorption (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Heal amount increased from 60% to 70%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="sylvanas">Sylvanas</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Basic Attack damage increased from 85 to 90.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Black Arrows (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Abilities no longer disable Structures.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> As part of our ongoing quest to increase counter-play
  and curb frustration when playing against certain Heroes, we’re changing
  Sylvanas’ Black Arrows trait so that her Abilities no longer disable
  Structures. This effect is incredibly powerful and, in the past, has limited
  how Battlegrounds can be designed and played. We realize that turning off
  enemy Structures is an important part of Sylvanas’ identity, so rather than
  removing this functionality completely, we’re addressing it in such a way that
  she now has to put herself in danger to get maximum value. This should allow
  more counter-play for opponents when Sylvanas is pushing, and enable us to
  improve her teamfight capabilities, which we’re doing initially via a small
  Basic Attack damage buff. We’ll be keeping an eye on her performance, and are
  ready to make further tuning changes as needed.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="support">Support</h3>

<h4 id="kharazim">Kharazim</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Health increased from 1949 to 2027.</li>
<li>Health Regeneration increased from 4.0585 to 4.2226.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Transcendence (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Healing increased from 98 to 104.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="malfurion">Malfurion</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Regrowth</strong>
<ul>
<li>Heal amount reduced from 400 to 380.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Moonfire</strong>
<ul>
<li>Heal amount reduced from 140 to 135.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Strangling Vines (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Heal reduction duration increased from 2 to 3 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="warrior">Warrior</h3>

<h4 id="chen">Chen</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Accumulating Flame (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Adjusted quest reward functionality:
<ul>
<li>Gain 15 Armor per Hero ignited with Breath of Fire. This lasts 3 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Freshest Ingredients (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Health Regeneration granted by gathering Regeneration Globes no longer caps at 30.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Keg Toss (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Bonus damage per Hero hit increased from 3 to 4.</li>
<li>Bonus damage maximum increased from 60 to 80.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Purifying Brew (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Added functionality:
<ul>
<li>Spell Armor persists as long as Chen has Fortifying Brew Shields.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="dehaka">Dehaka</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Adaptation (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 90 to 80 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Enduring Swarm (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Spell Armor increased from 40 to 50.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Lurker Strain (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Slow duration increased from 2 to 3 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Hero Stalker (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Added functionality
<ul>
<li>Enemy Heroes hit by Dark Swarm grant 1 Essence.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ferocious Stalker (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Bonus damage increased from 40% to 50%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="leoric">Leoric</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Basic Attack damage increased from 105 to 109.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Drain Hope (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 11 to 10 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="tyrael">Tyrael</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ardent Restoration (Passive)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Healing increased from 13.75 to 15 per stack.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Stalwart Angel (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Armor increased from 20 to 25.</li>
<li>Armor duration reduced from 3 to 2 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Purge Evil (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Basic Attack damage bonus increased from 35% to 45%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Burning Halo (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage increased from 15 to 18.</li>
<li>Bonus damage after teleporting increased from 100% to 150%.</li>
<li>Bonus damage duration reduced from 3 to 2 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Smite the Wicked (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown recharge rate increased from 100% to 125%.</li>
<li>Cooldown recharge rate duration after teleporting reduced from 3 to 2 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> We’re making adjustments focused on the viability of
  some of Tyrael’s Talents. In particular, Sword of Justice was not picked very
  often, and was underperforming. We’re addressing this by taking a few Talents
  (Stalwart Angel, Burning Halo, and Smite the Wicked) and increasing their
  synergy with Sword of Justice by increasing the bonuses that Tyrael receives
  while El’druin is out, but reducing the bonuses for teleporting. This should
  enhance Sword of Justice’s playstyle, by allowing players to teleport into a
  fight, but still having an active El’druin’s.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="zarya">Zarya</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Health increased from 2225 to 2292.</li>
<li>Health Regeneration increased from 4.6406 to 4.7750.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Particle Grenade (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage increased from 71 to 75.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Graviton Surge (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 80 to 60 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fixed a pair of issues that could cause the game client to crash.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Art</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Johanna:</strong> Learning Holy Renewal and casting Shield Glare while using one of Johanna’s Enforcer Skins no longer causes placeholder art to appear at her feet.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Ana:</strong> After learning Grenade Calibration, Biotic Grenade’s floating combat text now displays the correct amount of Healing received with each tick.</li>
<li><strong>Auriel:</strong> Bestow Hope’s buff and visual effects will no longer be removed if the target enters a Stasis effect, like Zagara’s Devouring Maw.</li>
<li><strong>Cassia:</strong> After learning Martial Law, Basic Attacks now correctly apply bonus damage against Slowed Heroes.</li>
<li><strong>Fenix:</strong> Fixed an issue that could prevent the Rapid Recharge Talent from providing its Shield recharge effect when Healed.</li>
<li><strong>Fenix:</strong> Plasma Cutter is now correctly interrupted by Stasis effects, like Stitches’ Gorge and Anub’arak’s Cocoon.</li>
<li><strong>Fenix:</strong> Casting Plasma Cutter on an Invulnerable target no longer grants quest progress for the Advanced Targeting Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Fenix:</strong> After learning Singularity Charge, the Talent description that is appended to the Weapon Mode Ability tooltip now states the correct amount of bonus range provided to Phase Bomb Basic Attacks.</li>
<li><strong>Greymane:</strong> The Wizened Duelist Talent’s Basic Attack counter no longer continues to update after achieving maximum quest progress.</li>
<li><strong>Leoric:</strong> Fixed an issue preventing Leoric from casting Hearthstone while in Undying form.</li>
<li><strong>Malthael:</strong> After learning Black Harvest, quest progress indicators now correctly appear every second while a target is affected by Reaper’s Mark.</li>
<li><strong>Medivh:</strong> Fixed an issue in which Medivh could create four Portals at once after learning Portal Mastery.</li>
<li><strong>Medivh:</strong> Is no longer dismounted after casting Arcane Brilliance.</li>
<li><strong>Probius:</strong> Disruption Pulse no longer gains bonus damage from the Particle Accelerator Talent when it passes through non-targetable units, like Gazlowe’s Scrap.</li>
<li><strong>Varian:</strong> Learning Colossus Smash no longer reduces Varian’s Health Regeneration by more than the intended 10%.</li>
<li><strong>Zeratul:</strong> Casting Void Prison on Blaze’s Bunker while players are inside no longer halts their Ability cooldowns indefinitely after Void Prison expires.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-03-30 Hotfix Patch</title>
    <published>2018-03-30T18:55:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-03-30T18:55:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-30-hotfix-patch.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-30-hotfix-patch.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-hotfix-notes-march-30-2018">Heroes of the Storm Hotfix Notes – March 30, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1494956881/patchlogo2017-05-16.jpg"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21670794" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21670794" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.31.1</small></div>

<p>We’ve just released a new hotfix for Heroes of the Storm to apply a few bug
fixes.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>Battlegrounds</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Structures:</strong> Fixed an issue in which certain Abilities could be used to move Structures.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Diablo:</strong> Fixed a visual issue affecting Fenix’s walk animations after being hit by Overpower.</li>
<li><strong>Fenix:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Fenix’s model to visually disjoint from his actual position in-game.</li>
<li><strong>Fenix:</strong> Issuing a movement command during Purification Salvo will no longer cancel Fenix’s firing animation for the duration of the Ability.</li>
<li><strong>Fenix:</strong> Purification Salvo’s visual and sound effects will no longer continue to play if the Ability is cancelled due to its target becoming invalid, such as when Gul’dan casts Demonic Circle to teleport far beyond Purification Salvo’s range.</li>
<li><strong>Fenix:</strong> Unconquered Spirit’s icon in the Activated Talent hotbar is now visually consistent with other passive Talents, and no longer appears activatable.</li>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> The Target Practice Talent will now correctly grant 30% increased Storm Bow range upon completing its first quest requirement.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Sound</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Announcers:</strong> Fixed a processing issue affecting one of the Mira Han Announcer’s voiceover lines in the Chinese game client.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-03-27 Patch Notes</title>
    <published>2018-03-27T16:15:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-03-27T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-27-patch-notes.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-27-patch-notes.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-patch-notes-march-27-2018">Heroes of the Storm Patch Notes – March 27, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1494956881/patchlogo2017-05-16.jpg"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21646098" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21646098" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.31.0</small></div>

<p>Fenix joins the Nexus with our most recent Heroes of the Storm patch, and
we’re celebrating StarCraft’s 20th anniversary with new rewards, bundles,
portraits, and more!</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="starcraft-20th-anniversary">StarCraft 20th Anniversary</h3>

<p>Join us in celebrating StarCraft’s 20th anniversary with new StarCraft-themed
portraits you can earn just by logging into Heroes of the Storm from March 27
through April 23.</p>

<p><strong>StarCraft 20th Anniversary Portrait Rewards</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1521495761/protoss.jpg" alt="Protoss" title="Protoss" /> <img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1521495760/terran.jpg" alt="Terran" title="Terran" /> <img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1521495761/zerg.jpg" alt="Zerg" title="Zerg" /></p>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="new-hero-fenix">New Hero: Fenix</h3>

<p>As one of the greatest heroes in protoss history, Fenix’s deeds on the
battlefield are legendary. After falling to the zerg during the invasion of
Aiur, his body was recovered and implanted into a dragoon so he could continue
to fight. Not even death can stop Fenix from achieving glory and valor.</p>

<p><strong>Trait</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Shield Capacitor</strong>
<ul>
<li>Fenix has a permanent 800 Shield, which regenerates at 80 per second after not taking damage for 5 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Basic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Plasma Cutter (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Create a laser beam at the target point that circles around Fenix twice, dealing 150 damage to enemies hit and Slowing them by 25% for 4 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Switch Weapon Mode (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Activate to switch between Weapon Mode: Repeater Cannon and Weapon Mode: Phase Bomb.</li>
<li><strong>Weapon Mode: Phase Bomb</strong>
<ul>
<li>Basic Attacks have 1.5 increased range, deal 25% more damage, and splash to nearby enemies.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Weapon Mode: Repeater Cannon</strong>
<ul>
<li>Basic Attack speed increased by 150%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Warp (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Warp to targeted location, phasing out after 0.5 seconds, and arriving 0.75 seconds later.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Purification Salvo (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Channel for 1.5 seconds, sweeping a laser in front of Fenix that locks onto enemy Heroes. Once Channeling finishes, fire 5 missiles at each locked Hero, dealing 86 damage each. Deals 50% increased damage to Slowed targets.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Planet Cracker (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>After 0.5 seconds, Channel a powerful beam that spans across the battleground for 4 seconds, dealing 105 damage every 0.25 seconds to non-Structure enemies hit.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="art">Art</h3>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Heroes will no longer leave a behind a “ghost” that fades away after casting Hearthstone.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="user-interface">User Interface</h3>

<p><strong>In-Game UI</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Party Frames</strong>
<ul>
<li>Muting another player’s pings will now also mute any death timer pings that player issues by ALT + clicking the party frames UI at the top of the screen.</li>
<li>While in Undying form, Leoric’s party frame Health bar will display how much time remains before he respawns.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Score Screen (TAB)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Icons have replaced the column headers on the in-game score screen. Hover the mouse cursor over the icons for a brief description of each column.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Draft Mode</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Hero and player nameplates that appear beneath Hero portraits have swapped positions.
<ul>
<li>Hero names will now appear in the upper nameplate, and player names will appear in the lower nameplate.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Allied Hero names are now visible to teammates before they lock in their picks.
<ul>
<li>The opposing team’s Hero names will not appear until those players lock in their picks.</li>
<li>Spectators cannot see Hero names for either team until each player locks in their pick.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>The opposing team’s player names are no longer visible during a draft.
<ul>
<li>Spectators cannot see player names for either team until all players in the draft lobby have locked in their Hero picks.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="battlegrounds">Battlegrounds</h3>

<p><strong>Try Mode</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Two additional target dummies have been added to Try Mode to assist in testing Abilities and Talents that can hit multiple targets.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes Brawl</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>New Cooperative Brawl: Deadman’s Stand</strong>
<ul>
<li>Deadman’s Port is under siege by the voracious zerg Swarm.
<ul>
<li>Choose one Hero from a curated roster and work together with your allies to defend the Port’s fortifications.</li>
<li>Hold off the invading zerg long enough for Mira Han to activate the Psi Disruptor.</li>
<li>Stay on the lookout for infested Heroes and devastating Infested Archangels, which have been sighted in the area.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Get the complete sit-rep by reading the <a href="https://battle.net/heroes/blog/21646097">Deadman's Stand Preview blog</a> and prepare to stand against the tide when this brawl goes live on Friday, March 30!</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>AzmoDUNK!</strong>
<ul>
<li>Each Gem turned in now grants 3 Taste for Blood stacks.</li>
<li>Killing a Hero with Globe of Annihilation now resets its cooldown and refunds its Mana cost.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> With AzmoDUNK, we want to really reward successful
  dunks. To do so, we’ve added a free throw after a successful kill with a
  Globe. This should allow for some really exciting hot streaks. We’ve also
  updated the Tomb mechanic to give stacks of Taste for Blood, allowing a team
  who plays the mechanic to build stacks quite a bit quicker.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="design">Design</h3>

<p><strong>Shields</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Armor will now mitigate bonus damage dealt to Shields by effects like Varian's Shattering Throw and Kel'Thuzad's Strip Shields.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="heroes">Heroes</h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><a href="#assassin">Assassin</a></th>
  <th><a href="#multiclass">Multiclass</a></th>
  <th><a href="#support">Support</a></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#fenix">Fenix</a></td>
  <td><a href="#varian">Varian</a></td>
  <td><a href="#auriel">Auriel</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#tracer">Tracer</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td><a href="#li-li">Li Li</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="assassin">Assassin</h3>

<h4 id="fenix">Fenix</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Basic Attack damage reduced from 100 to 96</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Plasma Cutter (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 150 to 145.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Advanced Targeting (Q)
<ul>
<li>Damage bonus per stack reduced from 1 to 0.75.</li>
<li>Maximum damage bonus reduced from 80 to 75.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="tracer">Tracer</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Health increased from 1206 to 1350.</li>
<li>Health Regeneration increased from 5.0234 to 5.6250.</li>
<li>Basic Attack damage increased from 27 to 29.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Blink (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Charge cooldown increased from 6 to 8 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Melee (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 254 to 220.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Recall (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 26 to 30 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Pulse Bomb (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 420 to 360.</li>
<li>Secondary damage reduced from 210 to 180.</li>
<li>Scaling damage increased from 5.5% to 6%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Bullet Time (Q)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduction increased from 0.1 to 0.15 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Jumper (Q)
<ul>
<li>Additional functionality:
<ul>
<li>Now also increases the Blink’s cooldown by 2 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 10</strong>
<ul>
<li>Quantum Spike (R)
<ul>
<li>Bonus damage reduced from 10% to 8% maximum Health.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> As part of our ongoing effort to trim the frustration
  of playing against certain Heroes, we are making some tuning changes to
  Tracer. The general philosophy for these changes is threefold: reduce her
  overall mobility over time, reduce her burst damage, and increase the amount
  of time that she needs to stay in range of opponents in order to be effective.
  While we understand that reducing her burst damage via Melee and Pulse Bomb
  are significant nerfs to her power, we are compensating her by increasing her
  Health and Basic Attack damage. This should reward Tracer players who are able
  to bob and weave through opposing skillshots while staying on their target.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="multiclass">Multiclass</h3>

<h4 id="varian">Varian</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Health reduced from 2322 to 1850.</li>
<li>Health Regeneration reduced from 4.8375 to 3.8542.</li>
<li>Health scaling increased from 3% to 4% per level.</li>
<li>Basic Attack damage reduced from 91 to 74.</li>
<li>Basic Attack damage scaling increased from 3.5% to 4%.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Heroic Strike (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 140 to 125.</li>
<li>Damage scaling increased from 3.5% to 4% per level.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Lion’s Fang (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Added functionality:
<ul>
<li>Hitting an enemy heals Varian for 35 (+4% per level), increased to 140 against Heroes.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Parry (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased 8 to 10 seconds.</li>
<li>Mana cost increased from 15 to 20.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Overpower (W)
<ul>
<li>Damage bonus increased from 20% to 30%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Taunt (R)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 10.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Colossus Smash (R)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 10.</li>
<li>Armor reduction decreased from 25 to 20.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Twin Blades of Fury (R)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 10.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>New Talent: Lionheart (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Increases Lion’s Fang healing for damage dealt to Heroes by 50%.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Victory Rush (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Healing reduced from 400 to 350.</li>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 60 to 30 seconds.</li>
<li>Cooldown reduction granted per nearby Minion or Monster death reduced from 15 to 10 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Live by the Sword (W)
<ul>
<li>Removed.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 10</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shield Wall (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 4.</li>
<li>Now also reduces Parry’s cooldown by 5 seconds, but removes 1 charge.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Warbringer (E)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 4</li>
<li>Now also allows Varian to charge to allied Heroes.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li>Demoralizing Shout (Active)
<ul>
<li>Damage reduction increased from 25% to 40%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> We're making a simple change to Varian by moving his
  Heroic Abilities to Level 4, but this will have large impact on the way he
  feels during a game. By allowing Varian to get his Heroic Ability earlier, he
  can fulfill the role his team needs before one team develops a significant
  lead over the other. This increase in Varian’s early-game power justifies
  reducing some of the overwhelming power he gains after level 10, and creates a
  more even experience for Varian and his opponents throughout a game.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="support">Support</h3>

<h4 id="auriel">Auriel</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning"><strong>Sacred Sweep (Q)</strong></span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-27-patch-notes.html" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Center damage to non-Heroes reduced from 180 to 171</span></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="li-li">Li Li</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Wind Serpent (W)
<ul>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Reduces Cloud Serpent’s cooldown by 2 seconds.</li>
<li>Casting Cloud Serpent also launches Blinding Wind at an enemy near the target.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Hindering Winds (E)
<ul>
<li>Slow amount reduced from 30% to 25%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="collection">Collection</h3>

<p><strong>New Bundles</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The following new bundles are available for a limited time! Be sure to check out the latest <a href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en-us/blog/21619852">In-Development blog</a> for more details.
<ul>
<li>Fenix Heroic Bundle</li>
<li>StarCraft 20th Anniversary Bundle</li>
<li>Protoss 20th Anniversary Bundle</li>
<li>Terran 20th Anniversary Bundle</li>
<li>Zerg 20th Anniversary Bundle</li>
<li>Zergling Bundle</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Announcers</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fenix</li>
<li>Adjutant</li>
<li>Mira Han</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Skins</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Fenix</strong>
<ul>
<li>Rusted Fenix</li>
<li>Experimental Fenix</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Ruinwalker Fenix</strong>
<ul>
<li>Colossal Ruinwalker Fenix</li>
<li>Withered Ruinwalker Fenix</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Artanis</strong>
<ul>
<li>Zer’atai Artanis</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Azmodan</strong>
<ul>
<li>Infested Azmodan</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Brightwing</strong>
<ul>
<li>Primal Brightwing</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Dehaka</strong>
<ul>
<li>Feral Dehaka</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Gul’dan</strong>
<ul>
<li>Brooding Gul’dan</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Johanna</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shakuras Johanna</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Tassadar</strong>
<ul>
<li>Chosen Crypt King Tassadar</li>
<li>Exiled Crypt King Tassadar</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Mounts</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Celestial Ursa</strong>
<ul>
<li>This mount will replace the Celestial Raptor as a first-time gem purchase reward. Unlock it by purchasing gems for the first time after this patch has been released.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Umojan Cyber Ram</strong></li>
<li><strong>Zergling</strong>
<ul>
<li>Char Zergling</li>
<li>Kaldir Zergling</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Portraits and Sprays</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>We teamed up with Carbot Animations to create a ton of new HeroStorm-themed portraits and sprays in their signature art style! Catch a preview in the latest <a href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en-us/blog/21619852">In-Development blog</a>.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fixed a number of typo and tooltip errors across several aspects of the game.</li>
<li><strong>Loot Chests:</strong> Fixed a rare issue that could prevent players from receiving a Loot Chest on Hero level-up.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>A.I.</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Chromie:</strong> Fixed an issue preventing A.I. Chromie from casting Sand Blast.</li>
<li><strong>Gazlowe:</strong> A.I. Gazlowe will no longer interrupt its own Doubloon turn-ins on Blackhearts Bay in order to place Rock-It! Turrets.</li>
<li><strong>Leoric:</strong> A.I. Leoric will no longer remain stationary after activating Wraith Walk.</li>
<li><strong>Malfurion:</strong> A.I. Malfurion will no longer attempt to cast Entangling Roots on non-Heroic enemies.</li>
<li><strong>Medivh:</strong> A.I. Medivh wil no longer become stuck after attempting to use a Mine Entrance on Haunted Mines while in Raven Form.</li>
<li><strong>Murky:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause A.I. Murky to repeatedly place Egg in the same location, even if its existing Egg was undamaged.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Art</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Gazlowe:</strong> Dying and respawning after learning Robo-Goblin will no longer remove the player’s selected skin from the Robo-Goblin model.</li>
<li><strong>Malthael:</strong> Reaper's Mark visual effects will no longer persist if the target is killed just before Reaper’s Mark is applied.</li>
<li><strong>Nazeebo:</strong> Choosing the Superstition Talent while Nazeebo is dead will no longer cause Spell Shield visual effects to persist on the terrain after subsequent deaths.</li>
<li><strong>Loot Chests:</strong> The D.Haka portrait will no longer display placeholder art on the Loot Chest rewards screen.</li>
<li><strong>Mecha Tassadar:</strong> Attacking while using the Mecha Morph Mount will no longer cause Distortion Beam to visually originate above Mecha Tassadar’s head.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Battlegrounds</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Battlefield of Eternity:</strong> Destroying a Healing Fountain in the middle lane will no longer cause Minimap icons for Healing Fountains in other lanes to disappear.</li>
<li><strong>Braxis Holdout:</strong> Destroying a Healing Fountain will no longer cause Minimap icons for Healing Fountains in the top lane to disappear.</li>
<li><strong>Haunted Mines:</strong> Queueing movement commands during Hearthstone Channeling while in the Mines will no longer cancel Hearthstone.</li>
<li><strong>Volskaya Foundry:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Heroes who were piloting a Triglav Protector to become unresponsive after the Protector is destroyed by a Damage over Time effect.</li>
<li><strong>Warhead Junction:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Heroes to teleport back to the Hall of Storms after moving to a specific area of terrain before the game begins.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Abathur:</strong> Monstrosities will no longer deal area of effect damage on death if Abathur hasn’t learned the Volatile Mutation Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Alarak:</strong> Rite of Rak’shir can no longer be removed when Samuro casts Mirror Image or Chen casts Storm, Earth, Fire.</li>
<li><strong>Anub’arak:</strong> Cocoon will no longer trap Pilot-form D.Va if she has already successfully cast Call Mech.</li>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> After learning Oil Dispersal, Oil Spill’s targeting indicator now correctly increases in size to reflect the Ability’s new area of effect.</li>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> Casting Flame Stream on a target who is standing in an unignited Oil Spill will now correctly register as two Flame Stream hits, rather than one.</li>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> Unignited Oil Spills will no longer reduce enemy Structures’ Attack Speeds after learning the Nanomachine Coating Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> Flame Stream is no longer visible through the Fog of War when cast near the edge of the enemy team’s vision.</li>
<li><strong>Dehaka:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Drag visual effects to persist indefinitely if the Ability connected across unpathable terrain.</li>
<li><strong>D.Va:</strong> Self-Destruct’s charge percentage will now correctly reset to 0% between rounds during Heroes Brawls.</li>
<li><strong>Gall:</strong> Shove can no longer be cast while Cho is being pulled by Stitches’ Hook.</li>
<li><strong>Genji:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause enemy targeted Abilities to hit Genji rather than the intended target during Dragonblade.</li>
<li><strong>Greymane:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Razor Swipe’s area of effect and damage to become disjointed from Greymane’s location.</li>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Reactivating Dragon’s Arrow via the Play of the Game Talent after the Arrow has traveled beyond Warhead Junction’s playable area will no longer teleport Hanzo to an unreachable location.</li>
<li><strong>Illidan:</strong> Hitting two Heroes with Sweeping Strike at maximum range will now correctly apply the bonus damage granted by the Battered Assault Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Kel’Thuzad:</strong> Chilling Touch can now correctly deal damage to Gall’s Eye of Kilrogg.</li>
<li><strong>Kharazim:</strong> Seven-Sided Strike will now correctly target Stealth enemy Heroes who have been revealed.</li>
<li><strong>Leoric:</strong> Will no longer become permanently Unstoppable if he is affected by Stasis during Wraith Walk.</li>
<li><strong>Li Li:</strong> Casting Cloud Serpent on Pilot-form D.Va just before she casts Call Mech will no longer prevent the Serpent from following Mech-form D.Va.</li>
<li><strong>Lunara:</strong> Queued Leaping Strikes will no longer continue to target an enemy Hero who enters Stealth before the Heroic Ability actually fires.</li>
<li><strong>Malfurion:</strong> Entangling Roots will no longer affect non-Heroic targets.</li>
<li><strong>Malfurion:</strong> Regrowth can no longer be cast on non-Heroic targets.</li>
<li><strong>Ragnaros:</strong> Blind and Evasion effects will no longer cause Empower Sulfuras’s Ability Damage to miss.</li>
<li><strong>Rexxar:</strong> Completing the Hunter-Gatherer Talent’s quest now correctly grants bonus Armor to Misha.</li>
<li><strong>Rexxar:</strong> Misha, Focus! will now correctly grant Misha its passive 15% Movement Speed bonus.</li>
<li><strong>Samuro:</strong> Casting Mirror Image now correctly clears any Move commands that had been queued for the real Samuro.</li>
<li><strong>Stitches:</strong> Hook visual effects will no longer persist indefinitely if the target is thrown by Garrosh’s Wrecking Ball while being pulled toward Stitches.</li>
<li><strong>Stukov:</strong> Will no longer become unresponsive after attempting to cast Lurking Arm behind the allied Hall of Storms.</li>
<li><strong>The Lost Vikings:</strong> Spin to Win! visual effects are no longer visible through the Fog of War near the edge of the enemy team’s vision.</li>
<li><strong>Tracer:</strong> Can no longer cast Pulse Bomb while Channeling to launch a Nuke on Warhead Junction.</li>
<li><strong>Tyrande:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Sentinel’s visual effects to become slightly disjointed from the Ability’s path of travel.</li>
<li><strong>Uther:</strong> Devotion’s tooltip now more clearly communicates that allied Heroes affected by Uther’s Basic Abilities will gain Armor, rather than Heroes Healed by Uther’s Basic Abilities. This is a tooltip correction only; the Trait’s functionality has not been changed.</li>
<li><strong>Valeera:</strong> Activating Crippling Poison, Wound Poison, or Thistle Tea will no longer clear queued orders or Abilities.</li>
<li><strong>Valla:</strong> Fixed an issue that could prevent Hungering Arrow from seeking, or dealing damage to, targets after the first when cast at maximum range.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Sound</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Will no longer play an incorrect voiceover line to allies upon casting Hearthstone.</li>
<li><strong>Illidan:</strong> The volume for Illidan’s voiceover during The Hunt has been reduced to better match other game sounds.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-03-21 Balance Update</title>
    <published>2018-03-21T17:37:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-03-21T17:37:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-21-balance-update.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-21-balance-update.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-balance-patch-notes-march-21-2018">Heroes of the Storm Balance Patch Notes – March 21, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1485586192/balanceupdate.png"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21637154" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21637154" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.30.6</small></div>

<p>Our most recent Heroes of the Storm patch is now live containing a number of
balance changes and bug fixes.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="battlegrounds">Battlegrounds</h3>

<p><strong>Towers of Doom &amp; Haunted Mines</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Increased the respawn timer of Sapper Camps by 30 seconds.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="heroes">Heroes</h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><a href="#assassin">Assassin</a></th>
  <th><a href="#specialist">Specialist</a></th>
  <th><a href="#support">Support</a></th>
  <th><a href="#warrior">Warrior</a></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#greymane">Greymane</a></td>
  <td><a href="#medivh">Medivh</a></td>
  <td><a href="#auriel">Auriel</a></td>
  <td><a href="#artanis">Artanis</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#maiev">Maiev</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td><a href="#malfurion">Malfurion</a></td>
  <td><a href="#blaze">Blaze</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#thrall">Thrall</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
  <td><a href="#sonya">Sonya</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#valla">Valla</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
  <td><a href="#tyrael">Tyrael</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#zuljin">Zul'jin</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="assassin">Assassin</h3>

<h4 id="greymane">Greymane</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Razor Swipe (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 3 to 4 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Visceral Attacks (Q)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduction increased from 1 to 1.5 seconds per Basic Attack</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> We’re increasing the cooldown of Razor Swipe in an
  effort to stem some of Greymane’s effectiveness when taking Mercenaries and
  clearing Minion waves. Currently, Greymane’s play-style is great, but he does
  everything a little too well, which makes him a consistently safe pick. To
  curb this, we’d like to remove some of the PvE-oriented power from his kit.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="maiev">Maiev</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Vault of Wardens (D)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 9 to 12 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Fan of Knives (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 162 to 152</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Containment Disk (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 65 to 50 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Warden’s Cage (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 80 to 100 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Blade Dance (Q)
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 54 to 50</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shadow Armor (E)
<ul>
<li>Armor reduced from 25 to 20</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> Maiev is still a powerhouse in the Nexus. To combat
  this, we’re reducing Maiev’s damage potential by lowering Fan of Knives damage
  and Blade Dance (which has powerful synergy with Armored Assault, another
  overperforming Talent.) We’re also allowing opponents more opportunities to
  punish Maiev by increasing Vault of the Wardens’ cooldown and reducing the
  power of Shadow Armor.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="thrall">Thrall</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Crash Lightning (Q)
<ul>
<li>Maximum damage bonus reduced from 480 to 360</li>
<li>Quest completion reward requirement increased from 20 to 30 stacks</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> With the increased bounce range of Chain lightning,
  the Crash Lightning talent has become overly dominant. While we enjoy the
  build, as it allows Thrall to play outside of the solo-lane, in its current
  state it is simply too powerful. By lowering the maximum stacks, we’re
  reducing the upper damage limit to lessen the impact of the extreme situations
  where Thrall is completely stacked. Additionally, with the Quest Completion
  moving back to 30 stacks, it’s going to be harder for Thrall to finish the
  talent, pushing this power-spike to later in the match.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="valla">Valla</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Multishot (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage increased from 165 to 172</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="zuljin">Zul'jin</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Basic Attack damage increased from 90 to 94</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Ensnare (Active)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 60 to 45 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="specialist">Specialist</h3>

<h4 id="medivh">Medivh</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Arcane Explosion (W)
<ul>
<li>Additional damage from enemy damage absorbed reduced from 365 to 350</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Force of Magic (W)
<ul>
<li>Bonus Spell Power duration increased from 12 to 15 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Reabsorption (W)
<ul>
<li>Healing amount increased from 50 to 60%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="support">Support</h3>

<h4 id="auriel">Auriel</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Basic Attack damage increased from 57 to 68</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Detainment Strike (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 14 to 12 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Resurrect (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Range increased from 5 to 7</li>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 100 to 80 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Energized Cord (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Energy stored from Basic Attacks against non-Heroic targets reduced from 50 to 40%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Blinding Flash (Q)
<ul>
<li>Blind duration reduced from 2.25 to 2 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li>Diamond Resolve (R)
<ul>
<li>Armor increased from 50 to 60</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Angelic Flight (Active)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 45 to 30 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> Auriel has been overlooked in favor of other supports
  recently, so to increase her self-Hope generation and play-making potential,
  we’re increasing her Basic Attack damage and reducing the cooldown of
  Detainment Strike. We’ve also made some Talent adjustments so players feel
  like they have a greater variety of choices at the various tiers.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="malfurion">Malfurion</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nature’s Swiftness (Q)
<ul>
<li>Movement Speed reduced from 5 to 4% per Hero affected by Regrowth</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nature’s Balance (Q/W)
<ul>
<li>Bonus Regrowth duration reduced from 5 to 3 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="warrior">Warrior</h3>

<h4 id="artanis">Artanis</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Blade Dash (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 65 to 55</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Twin Blades (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 25 to 20</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Templar’s Zeal (Q)
<ul>
<li>Faster cooldown rate increased from 200 to 300%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="blaze">Blaze</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Bunker Drop (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 40 to 50 seconds</li>
<li>Exit Bunker now has a 1 second cooldown before it can be used</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> While we love the creative uses of Bunker Drop, at
  the higher levels of play it is slightly too effective. These changes are
  designed to decrease the overall power of the Bunker when it’s used purely to
  dodge enemy abilities and clear debuffs. We’d like to ensure that players who
  get into the Bunker are committed to being inside, if only briefly.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="sonya">Sonya</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Furious Blow (W)
<ul>
<li>Damage bonus increased from 40 to 50%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Battle Rage (Active)
<ul>
<li>Max charges reduced from 3 to 2</li>
<li>Charge use cooldown increased from 5 to 8 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mystical Spear (Q)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduction reduced from 3 to 2 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Rampage (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Ancient Spear cooldown reduction decreased from .75 to .5 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> Sonya is getting a bit too much value out of the
  combination of all the Ancient Spear talents, so we’re reducing the amount of
  cooldown reduction she gets to keep these from being the default choices.
  We’re also reducing the healing potential of Battle Rage at level 4 as it was
  providing a bit too much generic survivability for an early game talent.
  Finally, we’re increasing the damage bonus provided by Furious Blows to make
  it a more attractive damage option against the other two survivability
  talents.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="tyrael">Tyrael</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Justice for All (W)
<ul>
<li>Allied Shield bonus reduced from 100 to 75%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Tyrael:</strong> Fixed an issue causing some Mecha Tyrael skins to appear untextured.</li>
<li><strong>Johanna:</strong> Fixed an issue causing a placeholder sphere to appear when using Johanna’s Shield Glare ability with an Enforcer skin equipped.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Heroes can no longer cast Area-of-Effect abilities globally before the gates open.</li>
<li><strong>Malthael:</strong> Fixed an issue with the size of Death Shroud’s area of effect.</li>
<li><strong>Samuro:</strong> Fixed an issue with the Three Blade Style talent that prevented Mirror Images from gaining bonus health.</li>
<li><strong>Samuro:</strong> Fixed an issue causing the Quest Complete fanfare to play every time Mirror Images was cast after choosing the Way of Illusion talent.</li>
<li><strong>Valla:</strong> Fixed an issue causing the Punishment talent to deal less bonus damage than intended.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-03-19 PTR Patch Notes</title>
    <published>2018-03-19T17:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-03-19T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-19-ptr-patch-notes.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-19-ptr-patch-notes.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-ptr-patch-notes-march-19-2018">Heroes of the Storm PTR Patch Notes – March 19, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1494956881/patchlogo2017-05-16.jpg"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21594629" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21594629" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.31.0</small></div>

<p>Our next Heroes of the Storm patch has just hit the Public Test Realm and will
be available for playtesting until March 26. As always, if you encounter any
bugs during your PTR play sessions, please stop by the <a href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en/forum/20013840/">PTR Bug Report
forum</a> to let us know about
your experiences.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="starcraft-20th-anniversary">StarCraft 20th Anniversary</h3>

<p>Join us in celebrating StarCraft’s 20th anniversary with new StarCraft-themed
portraits you can earn just by logging into Heroes of the Storm from March 27
through April 23.</p>

<p><strong>StarCraft 20th Anniversary Portrait Rewards</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1521495761/protoss.jpg" alt="Protoss" title="Protoss" /> <img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1521495760/terran.jpg" alt="Terran" title="Terran" /> <img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1521495761/zerg.jpg" alt="Zerg" title="Zerg" /></p>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="new-hero-fenix">New Hero: Fenix</h3>

<p>As one of the greatest heroes in protoss history, Fenix’s deeds on the
battlefield are legendary. After falling to the zerg during the invasion of
Aiur, his body was recovered and implanted into a dragoon so he could continue
to fight. Not even death can stop Fenix from achieving glory and valor.</p>

<p><strong>Trait</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Shield Capacitor</strong>
<ul>
<li>Fenix has a permanent 800 Shield, which regenerates at 80 per second after not taking damage for 5 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Basic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Plasma Cutter (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Create a laser beam at the target point that circles around Fenix twice, dealing 150 damage to enemies hit and Slowing them by 25% for 4 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Switch Weapon Mode (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Activate to switch between Weapon Mode: Repeater Cannon and Weapon Mode: Phase Bomb.</li>
<li><strong>Weapon Mode: Phase Bomb</strong>
<ul>
<li>Basic Attacks have 1.5 increased range, deal 25% more damage, and splash to nearby enemies.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Weapon Mode: Repeater Cannon</strong>
<ul>
<li>Basic Attack speed increased by 150%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Warp (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Warp to targeted location, phasing out after 0.5 seconds, and arriving 0.75 seconds later.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Purification Salvo (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Channel for 1.5 seconds, sweeping a laser in front of Fenix that locks onto enemy Heroes. Once Channeling finishes, fire 5 missiles at each locked Hero, dealing 86 damage each. Deals 50% increased damage to Slowed targets.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Planet Cracker (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>After 0.5 seconds, Channel a powerful beam that spans across the battleground for 4 seconds, dealing 105 damage every 0.25 seconds to non-Structure enemies hit.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="art">Art</h3>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Heroes will no longer leave a behind a “ghost” that fades away after casting Hearthstone.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="user-interface">User Interface</h3>

<p><strong>In-Game UI</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Party Frames</strong>
<ul>
<li>Muting another player’s pings will now also mute any death timer pings that player issues by ALT + clicking the party frames UI at the top of the screen.</li>
<li>While in Undying form, Leoric’s party frame Health bar will display how much time remains before he respawns.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Score Screen (TAB)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Icons have replaced the column headers on the in-game score screen. Hover the mouse cursor over the icons for a brief description of each column.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Draft Mode</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Hero and player nameplates that appear beneath Hero portraits have swapped positions.
<ul>
<li>Hero names will now appear in the upper nameplate, and player names will appear in the lower nameplate.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Allied Hero names are now visible to teammates before they lock in their picks.
<ul>
<li>The opposing team’s Hero names will not appear until those players lock in their picks.</li>
<li>Spectators cannot see Hero names for either team until each player locks in their pick.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>The opposing team’s player names are no longer visible during a draft.
<ul>
<li>Spectators cannot see player names for either team until all players in the draft lobby have locked in their Hero picks.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="battlegrounds">Battlegrounds</h3>

<p><strong>Try Mode</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Two additional target dummies have been added to Try Mode to assist in testing Abilities and Talents that can hit multiple targets.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes Brawl</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>AzmoDUNK!</strong>
<ul>
<li>Each Gem turned in now grants 3 Taste for Blood stacks.</li>
<li>Killing a Hero with Globe of Annihilation now resets its cooldown and refunds its Mana cost.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> With AzmoDUNK, we want to really reward successful
  dunks. To do so, we’ve added a free throw after a successful kill with a
  Globe. This should allow for some really exciting hot streaks. We’ve also
  updated the Tomb mechanic to give stacks of Taste for Blood, allowing a team
  who plays the mechanic to build stacks quite a bit quicker.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="design">Design</h3>

<p><strong>Shields</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Armor will now mitigate bonus damage dealt to Shields by effects like Varian's Shattering Throw and Kel'Thuzad's Strip Shields.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="heroes">Heroes</h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><a href="#assassin">Assassin</a></th>
  <th><a href="#multiclass">Multiclass</a></th>
  <th><a href="#support">Support</a></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#tracer">Tracer</a></td>
  <td><a href="#varian">Varian</a></td>
  <td><a href="#li-li">Li Li</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="assassin">Assassin</h3>

<h4 id="tracer">Tracer</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Health increased from 1206 to 1350.</li>
<li>Health Regeneration increased from 5.0234 to 5.6250.</li>
<li>Basic Attack damage increased from 27 to 29.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Blink (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Charge cooldown increased from 6 to 8 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Melee (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 254 to 220.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Recall (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 26 to 30 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Pulse Bomb (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 420 to 360.</li>
<li>Secondary damage reduced from 210 to 180.</li>
<li>Scaling damage increased from 5.5% to 6%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Bullet Time (Q)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduction increased from 0.1 to 0.15 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Jumper (Q)
<ul>
<li>Additional functionality:
<ul>
<li>Now also increases the Blink’s cooldown by 2 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 10</strong>
<ul>
<li>Quantum Spike (R)
<ul>
<li>Bonus damage reduced from 10% to 8% maximum Health.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> As part of our ongoing effort to trim the frustration
  of playing against certain Heroes, we are making some tuning changes to
  Tracer. The general philosophy for these changes is threefold: reduce her
  overall mobility over time, reduce her burst damage, and increase the amount
  of time that she needs to stay in range of opponents in order to be effective.
  While we understand that reducing her burst damage via Melee and Pulse Bomb
  are significant nerfs to her power, we are compensating her by increasing her
  Health and Basic Attack damage. This should reward Tracer players who are able
  to bob and weave through opposing skillshots while staying on their target.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="multiclass">Multiclass</h3>

<h4 id="varian">Varian</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Health reduced from 2322 to 1850.</li>
<li>Health Regeneration reduced from 4.8375 to 3.8542.</li>
<li>Health scaling increased from 3% to 4% per level.</li>
<li>Basic Attack damage reduced from 91 to 74.</li>
<li>Basic Attack damage scaling increased from 3.5% to 4%.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Heroic Strike (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 140 to 125.</li>
<li>Damage scaling increased from 3.5% to 4% per level.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Lion’s Fang (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Added functionality:
<ul>
<li>Hitting an enemy heals Varian for 35 (+4% per level), increased to 140 against Heroes.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Parry (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased 8 to 10 seconds.</li>
<li>Mana cost increased from 15 to 20.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Overpower (W)
<ul>
<li>Damage bonus increased from 20% to 30%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Taunt (R)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 10.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Colossus Smash (R)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 10.</li>
<li>Armor reduction decreased from 25 to 20.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Twin Blades of Fury (R)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 10.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>New Talent: Lionheart (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Increases Lion’s Fang healing for damage dealt to Heroes by 50%.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Victory Rush (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Healing reduced from 400 to 350.</li>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 60 to 30 seconds.</li>
<li>Cooldown reduction granted per nearby Minion or Monster death reduced from 15 to 10 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Live by the Sword (W)
<ul>
<li>Removed.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 10</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shield Wall (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 4.</li>
<li>Now also reduces Parry’s cooldown by 5 seconds, but removes 1 charge.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Warbringer (E)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 4</li>
<li>Now also allows Varian to charge to allied Heroes.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li>Demoralizing Shout (Active)
<ul>
<li>Damage reduction increased from 25% to 40%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> We're making a simple change to Varian by moving his
  Heroic Abilities to Level 4, but this will have large impact on the way he
  feels during a game. By allowing Varian to get his Heroic Ability earlier, he
  can fulfill the role his team needs before one team develops a significant
  lead over the other. This increase in Varian’s early-game power justifies
  reducing some of the overwhelming power he gains after level 10, and creates a
  more even experience for Varian and his opponents throughout a game.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="support">Support</h3>

<h4 id="li-li">Li Li</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Wind Serpent (W)
<ul>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Reduces Cloud Serpent’s cooldown by 2 seconds.</li>
<li>Casting Cloud Serpent also launches Blinding Wind at an enemy near the target.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Hindering Winds (E)
<ul>
<li>Slow amount reduced from 30% to 25%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="collection">Collection</h3>

<p><strong>New Bundles</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The following new bundles are available for a limited time! Be sure to check out the latest <a href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en-us/blog/21619852">In-Development blog</a> for more details.
<ul>
<li>Fenix Heroic Bundle</li>
<li>StarCraft 20th Anniversary Bundle</li>
<li>Protoss 20th Anniversary Bundle</li>
<li>Terran 20th Anniversary Bundle</li>
<li>Zerg 20th Anniversary Bundle</li>
<li>Zergling Bundle</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Announcers</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fenix</li>
<li>Adjutant</li>
<li>Mira Han</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Skins</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Fenix</strong>
<ul>
<li>Rusted Fenix</li>
<li>Experimental Fenix</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Ruinwalker Fenix</strong>
<ul>
<li>Colossal Ruinwalker Fenix</li>
<li>Withered Ruinwalker Fenix</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Artanis</strong>
<ul>
<li>Zer’atai Artanis</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Azmodan</strong>
<ul>
<li>Infested Azmodan</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Brightwing</strong>
<ul>
<li>Primal Brightwing</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Dehaka</strong>
<ul>
<li>Feral Dehaka</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Gul’dan</strong>
<ul>
<li>Brooding Gul’dan</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Johanna</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shakuras Johanna</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Tassadar</strong>
<ul>
<li>Chosen Crypt King Tassadar</li>
<li>Exiled Crypt King Tassadar</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Mounts</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Celestial Ursa</strong>
<ul>
<li>This mount will replace the Celestial Raptor as a first-time gem purchase reward. Unlock it by purchasing gems for the first time after this patch has been released.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Umojan Cyber Ram</strong></li>
<li><strong>Zergling</strong>
<ul>
<li>Char Zergling</li>
<li>Kaldir Zergling</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Portraits and Sprays</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>We teamed up with Carbot Animations to create a ton of new HeroStorm-themed portraits and sprays in their signature art style! Catch a preview in the latest <a href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en-us/blog/21619852">In-Development blog</a>.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fixed a number of typo and tooltip errors across several aspects of the game.</li>
<li><strong>Loot Chests:</strong> Fixed a rare issue that could prevent players from receiving a Loot Chest on Hero level-up.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>A.I.</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Chromie:</strong> Fixed an issue preventing A.I. Chromie from casting Sand Blast.</li>
<li><strong>Gazlowe:</strong> A.I. Gazlowe will no longer interrupt its own Doubloon turn-ins on Blackhearts Bay in order to place Rock-It! Turrets.</li>
<li><strong>Leoric:</strong> A.I. Leoric will no longer remain stationary after activating Wraith Walk.</li>
<li><strong>Malfurion:</strong> A.I. Malfurion will no longer attempt to cast Entangling Roots on non-Heroic enemies.</li>
<li><strong>Medivh:</strong> A.I. Medivh wil no longer become stuck after attempting to use a Mine Entrance on Haunted Mines while in Raven Form.</li>
<li><strong>Murky:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause A.I. Murky to repeatedly place Egg in the same location, even if its existing Egg was undamaged.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Art</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Gazlowe:</strong> Dying and respawning after learning Robo-Goblin will no longer remove the player’s selected skin from the Robo-Goblin model.</li>
<li><strong>Malthael:</strong> Reaper's Mark visual effects will no longer persist if the target is killed just before Reaper’s Mark is applied.</li>
<li><strong>Nazeebo:</strong> Choosing the Superstition Talent while Nazeebo is dead will no longer cause Spell Shield visual effects to persist on the terrain after subsequent deaths.</li>
<li><strong>Loot Chests:</strong> The D.Haka portrait will no longer display placeholder art on the Loot Chest rewards screen.</li>
<li><strong>Mecha Tassadar:</strong> Attacking while using the Mecha Morph Mount will no longer cause Distortion Beam to visually originate above Mecha Tassadar’s head.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Battlegrounds</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Battlefield of Eternity:</strong> Destroying a Healing Fountain in the middle lane will no longer cause Minimap icons for Healing Fountains in other lanes to disappear.</li>
<li><strong>Braxis Holdout:</strong> Destroying a Healing Fountain will no longer cause Minimap icons for Healing Fountains in the top lane to disappear.</li>
<li><strong>Haunted Mines:</strong> Queueing movement commands during Hearthstone Channeling while in the Mines will no longer cancel Hearthstone.</li>
<li><strong>Volskaya Foundry:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Heroes who were piloting a Triglav Protector to become unresponsive after the Protector is destroyed by a Damage over Time effect.</li>
<li><strong>Warhead Junction:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Heroes to teleport back to the Hall of Storms after moving to a specific area of terrain before the game begins.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Abathur:</strong> Monstrosities will no longer deal area of effect damage on death if Abathur hasn’t learned the Volatile Mutation Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Alarak:</strong> Rite of Rak’shir can no longer be removed when Samuro casts Mirror Image or Chen casts Storm, Earth, Fire.</li>
<li><strong>Anub’arak:</strong> Cocoon will no longer trap Pilot-form D.Va if she has already successfully cast Call Mech.</li>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> After learning Oil Dispersal, Oil Spill’s targeting indicator now correctly increases in size to reflect the Ability’s new area of effect.</li>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> Casting Flame Stream on a target who is standing in an unignited Oil Spill will now correctly register as two Flame Stream hits, rather than one.</li>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> Unignited Oil Spills will no longer reduce enemy Structures’ Attack Speeds after learning the Nanomachine Coating Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> Flame Stream is no longer visible through the Fog of War when cast near the edge of the enemy team’s vision.</li>
<li><strong>Dehaka:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Drag visual effects to persist indefinitely if the Ability connected across unpathable terrain.</li>
<li><strong>D.Va:</strong> Self-Destruct’s charge percentage will now correctly reset to 0% between rounds during Heroes Brawls.</li>
<li><strong>Gall:</strong> Shove can no longer be cast while Cho is being pulled by Stitches’ Hook.</li>
<li><strong>Genji:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause enemy targeted Abilities to hit Genji rather than the intended target during Dragonblade.</li>
<li><strong>Greymane:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Razor Swipe’s area of effect and damage to become disjointed from Greymane’s location.</li>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Reactivating Dragon’s Arrow via the Play of the Game Talent after the Arrow has traveled beyond Warhead Junction’s playable area will no longer teleport Hanzo to an unreachable location.</li>
<li><strong>Illidan:</strong> Hitting two Heroes with Sweeping Strike at maximum range will now correctly apply the bonus damage granted by the Battered Assault Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Kel’Thuzad:</strong> Chilling Touch can now correctly deal damage to Gall’s Eye of Kilrogg.</li>
<li><strong>Kharazim:</strong> Seven-Sided Strike will now correctly target Stealth enemy Heroes who have been revealed.</li>
<li><strong>Leoric:</strong> Will no longer become permanently Unstoppable if he is affected by Stasis during Wraith Walk.</li>
<li><strong>Li Li:</strong> Casting Cloud Serpent on Pilot-form D.Va just before she casts Call Mech will no longer prevent the Serpent from following Mech-form D.Va.</li>
<li><strong>Lunara:</strong> Queued Leaping Strikes will no longer continue to target an enemy Hero who enters Stealth before the Heroic Ability actually fires.</li>
<li><strong>Malfurion:</strong> Entangling Roots will no longer affect non-Heroic targets.</li>
<li><strong>Ragnaros:</strong> Blind and Evasion effects will no longer cause Empower Sulfuras’s Ability Damage to miss.</li>
<li><strong>Rexxar:</strong> Completing the Hunter-Gatherer Talent’s quest now correctly grants bonus Armor to Misha.</li>
<li><strong>Rexxar:</strong> Misha, Focus! will now correctly grant Misha its passive 15% Movement Speed bonus.</li>
<li><strong>Samuro:</strong> Casting Mirror Image now correctly clears any Move commands that had been queued for the real Samuro.</li>
<li><strong>Stitches:</strong> Hook visual effects will no longer persist indefinitely if the target is thrown by Garrosh’s Wrecking Ball while being pulled toward Stitches.</li>
<li><strong>Stukov:</strong> Will no longer become unresponsive after attempting to cast Lurking Arm behind the allied Hall of Storms.</li>
<li><strong>The Lost Vikings:</strong> Spin to Win! visual effects are no longer visible through the Fog of War near the edge of the enemy team’s vision.</li>
<li><strong>Tracer:</strong> Can no longer cast Pulse Bomb while Channeling to launch a Nuke on Warhead Junction.</li>
<li><strong>Tyrande:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Sentinel’s visual effects to become slightly disjointed from the Ability’s path of travel.</li>
<li><strong>Uther:</strong> Devotion’s tooltip now more clearly communicates that allied Heroes affected by Uther’s Basic Abilities will gain Armor, rather than Heroes Healed by Uther’s Basic Abilities. This is a tooltip correction only; the Trait’s functionality has not been changed.</li>
<li><strong>Valeera:</strong> Activating Crippling Poison, Wound Poison, or Thistle Tea will no longer clear queued orders or Abilities.</li>
<li><strong>Valla:</strong> Fixed an issue that could prevent Hungering Arrow from seeking, or dealing damage to, targets after the first when cast at maximum range.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Sound</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Will no longer play an incorrect voiceover line to allies upon casting Hearthstone.</li>
<li><strong>Illidan:</strong> The volume for Illidan’s voiceover during The Hunt has been reduced to better match other game sounds.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-03-09 Hotfix Patch</title>
    <published>2018-03-12T17:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-03-12T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-09-hotfix-patch.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-09-hotfix-patch.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-hotfix-notes-march-9-2018">Heroes of the Storm Hotfix Notes – March 9, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1494956881/patchlogo2017-05-16.jpg"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21612976" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21612976" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.30.5</small></div>

<p>We’ve just released a new hotfix for Heroes of the Storm to apply a few bug
fixes and introduce a balance change.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="warrior">Warrior</h3>

<h4 id="sonya">Sonya</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Tough as Nails (Passive)</strong>
<ul>
<li>No longer immediately grants 3 Physical Armor stacks upon learning the Talent.</li>
<li>Physical Armor granted per stack reduced from 75 to 60.</li>
<li>Charge cooldown increased from 12 to 16 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Voice Chat:</strong> Fixed a backend issue affecting the Voice Chat service.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Medivh:</strong> Fixed an issue that prevented the Arcane Explosion Talent from dealing bonus damage if Force of Will had been cast on an allied Hero.</li>
<li><strong>Sonya:</strong> Being hit by beam Basic Attacks, such as Tassadar’s Distortion Beam, after learning the Tough as Nails Talent will no longer grant Sonya permanent Physical Armor.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-03-06 Patch Notes</title>
    <published>2018-03-12T17:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-03-12T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-06-patch-notes.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-06-patch-notes.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-patch-notes-march-6-2018">Heroes of the Storm Patch Notes – March 6, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1494956881/patchlogo2017-05-16.jpg"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21594628" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21594628" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.30.4</small></div>

<p>Our most recent Heroes of the Storm patch is now available for play, featuring
Hero updates for Sonya and Medivh, new Enforcer skins, and more!</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="art">Art</h3>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Nova:</strong> Precision Strike has received updated visual effects.</li>
<li><strong>Sgt. Hammer:</strong> Has received a custom Hearthstone animation.</li>
<li><strong>Thrall:</strong> After learning the Thunderstorm Talent, a UI indicator will now appear under the Health bar of Thrall’s most recent Chain Lightning target.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="design">Design</h3>

<p><strong>Trait Quests</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The following Hero Traits are now categorized as Repeatable Quests:
<ul>
<li><strong>Alarak: Sadism</strong>
<ul>
<li>Quest progress visual and sound effects will now play when earning Takedown credit.</li>
<li>Alarak’s Sadism Quest will now appear on the in-game Score Screen (TAB)</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Diablo: Black Soulstone</strong>
<ul>
<li>Quest progress and completion visual and sound effects will now play when Diablo gains Souls.</li>
<li>Quest completion will now appear in the Event Log on the left side of the screen.</li>
<li>Diablo’s Black Soulstone Quest will now appear in the in-game Score Screen (TAB).</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="heroes">Heroes</h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><a href="#specialist">Specialist</a></th>
  <th><a href="#support">Support</a></th>
  <th><a href="#warrior">Warrior</a></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#medivh">Medivh</a></td>
  <td><a href="#ana">Ana</a></td>
  <td><a href="#sonya">Sonya</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="specialist">Specialist</h3>

<h4 id="medivh">Medivh</h4>

<p>Medivh has received significant updates with today’s patch. Find his detailed
changes below, and then head to the <a href="https://battle.net/heroes/blog/21508381">Sonya and Medivh Gameplay Updates
blog</a> for more insight behind these
changes.</p>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Health scaling increased from 4% to 4.5% per level</li>
<li>Health Regeneration scaling increased from 4% to 4.5% per level</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Arcane Rift (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 200 to 170</li>
<li>Additional Functionality:
<ul>
<li><strong>Quest:</strong> Hit 40 enemy Heroes without dying.</li>
<li><strong>Reward:</strong> Permanently increase Arcane Rift’s damage by 75 and the cooldown reduction granted for hitting a Hero by 1 second</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Force of Will (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 5 to 8 seconds</li>
<li>Mana cost increased from 50 to 60</li>
<li>Upon expiration, allies are healed for 20% of the damage absorbed</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Portal (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 20 to 16 seconds</li>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 75 to 65 </li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Winds of Celerity (Z)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 13</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Portal Mastery (Active)
<ul>
<li>Additional Functionality:
<ul>
<li>Portals can now be cast while in Raven form</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Raven’s Intellect (Z)
<ul>
<li>Additional Functionality:
<ul>
<li>Now also increases Health regeneration by 75% while in Raven form</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Mana regeneration bonus reduced from 100% to 75%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Bird’s Eye View (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Mage Armor (E)
<ul>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>An ally now gains 25 Armor for 4 seconds the first time they enter a Portal</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Raven Familiar (E)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 7</li>
<li>Additional functionality:
<ul>
<li>Now also Slows enemies by 30% for 2.5 seconds.</li>
<li>A Raven now joins an ally each time they enter a Portal</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Dust of Appearance (Active)
<ul>
<li>Adjusted Functionality:
<ul>
<li>Permanently increases vision range in Raven Form by 25%.</li>
<li>Activate to greatly increase Medivh’s vision range for 5 seconds, and reveal enemy Heroes in the area for 8 seconds. Does not cancel Raven form</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>The Master’s Touch (Q)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Arcane Explosion (W)
<ul>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Deals 90 damage to nearby enemies when Force of Will expires. Also deals an additional 100% of damage taken, up to 365 bonus damage</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Explosion radius increased from 3 to 3.5</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Mystic Assault (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>If Arcane Rift hits an enemy Hero, Medivh’s next Basic Attack within 6 seconds deals 40% more damage and Heals for 40% of the damage dealt</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Force of Magic (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Preventing 268 or more damage with a single Force of Will grants Medivh 20% Spell Power for 12 seconds. This can stack up to 2 times</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Quickening (Q)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Astral Projection (E)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Circle of Protection (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16</li>
<li>Now applies a talented version of Force of Will to nearby allies</li>
<li>Radius increased from 2.5 to 3</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Enduring Will (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16</li>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>If Force of Will absorbs 268 damage, its cooldown is reduced to 3 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Reabsorption (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16</li>
<li>Increases Force of Will’s Healing to 50% of the damage taken</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Arcane Charge (Q)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 7</li>
<li>Damage bonus reduced from 30% to 15%</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Stable Portal (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 1</li>
<li>New Functionality:
<ul>
<li>Reduces Portal’s cooldown by 25% and increases Portal duration by 50%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Temporal Flux (Passive)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Basic Attacks reduce Medivh’s Heroic cooldown by 1 second. Hitting enemy Heroes with Arcane Rift reduces Medivh’s Heroic cooldown by 3 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li>Invisibility (Active) renamed to: Dust of Disappearance (Active)
<ul>
<li>No longer costs Mana</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><strong>LEVEL (TIER)</strong></th>
  <th><strong>Medivh Talents</strong></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><strong>1 (1)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Winds of Celerity (Z)</strong></td>
  <td>Raven’s Intellect (Z)</td>
  <td>Portal Mastery (Active)</td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>4 (2)</strong></td>
  <td>Mage Armor (E)</td>
  <td><strong>Raven Familiar (E)</strong></td>
  <td>Dust of Appearance (Active)</td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>7 (3)</strong></td>
  <td><em>Mystic Assault (Q)</em></td>
  <td>Arcane Explosion (W)</td>
  <td><em>Force of Magic (W)</em></td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>10 (4)</strong></td>
  <td>Poly Bomb (R)</td>
  <td>Ley Line Seal (R)</td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>13 (5)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Circle of Protection (W)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Enduring Will (W)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Reabsorption (W)</strong></td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>16 (6)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Arcane Charge (Q)</strong></td>
  <td><em>Temporal Flux (Q)</em></td>
  <td><strong>Stable Portal (E)</strong></td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>20 (7)</strong></td>
  <td>Glyph of Poly Bomb (R)</td>
  <td>Medivh Cheats! (R)</td>
  <td>Guardian of Tirisfal (Q)</td>
  <td>Arcane Brilliance (Active)</td>
  <td>Dust of Disappearance (Active)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<ul>
<li>(!) indicates a Questing Talent.</li>
<li><em>Italic text</em> indicates a <em>NEW</em> Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Bold</strong> text indicates a <strong>MOVED</strong> Talent.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="support">Support</h3>

<h4 id="ana">Ana</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Shrike (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Added functionality:
<ul>
<li>Ana Heals for 50% of Shrike damage dealt to Heroes</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Healing Dart (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Healing reduced from 237 to 215</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Biotic Grenade (W)</strong> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-06-patch-notes.html" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Range reduced from 15 to 12</span></li>
<li>Adjusted functionality:
<ul>
<li>Amplified Healing now only affects Ana’s Healing output</li>
<li>Amplified Healing duration increased from 3 to 4 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Nano Boost (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 50 to 60 seconds</li>
<li>Mana cost increased from 40 to 60</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Eye of Horus (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Self-cancelling no longer places the Ability on a 10 second cooldown</li>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 60 to 45 seconds</li>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 75 to 45</li>
<li>Number of shots reduced from 8 to 6</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Grenade Calibration (W)
<ul>
<li>Add base functionality</li>
<li>The amplified healing effect of Biotic Grenade now works on all healing</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Piercing Darts (E)
<ul>
<li>1st quest unlock
<ul>
<li>Range increase from 50 to 25%</li>
</ul></li>
<li>2nd quest unlock
<ul>
<li>Range increase from 50 to 25%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Detachable Box Magazine (Passive)
<ul>
<li>1st quest unlock
<ul>
<li>New functionality
<ul>
<li>The self-healing for Shrike now also applies to non-Heroes</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Aim Down Sights (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Shrike activation cooldown reduced from 10 to 3 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Air Strike (W) <a class="label label-warning" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-06-patch-notes.html" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Range increased from 200% to 275%</span></li>
<li>Airborne duration reduced from 4 to 3 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Debilitating Dart (Active)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 45 to 20 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Mind-Numbing Agent (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Spell Power reduction per Shrike stack decreased from 15% to 10%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> While Ana’s current win-rate is sitting above most
  other Healers, and North of 50%, we have made some changes to make her feel
  more meaningful in solo-Support compositions. Along with the addition to self-
  sustain through Shrike, we also took the opportunity to do some Talent
  balancing as well. While there are no major outliers in terms of win-rate, she
  definitely has some Talents that are overshadowing others in terms of pick-
  rates. We have tried to address the majority of these to hopefully open up
  some new strategic choices for Ana players. We really enjoyed the changes
  internally, and we’re excited to see what players can do with them.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="warrior">Warrior</h3>

<h4 id="sonya">Sonya</h4>

<p>Sonya has received significant updates with today’s patch. Find her detailed
changes below, and then head to the <a href="https://battle.net/heroes/blog/21508381">Sonya and Medivh Gameplay Updates
blog</a> for more insight behind these
changes.</p>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Block (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Furious Blow (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16</li>
<li>New functionality
<ul>
<li>Every fourth Seismic Slam deals 40% more damage and costs no Fury</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Tough as Nails (Passive)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Every 12 seconds gain a stack of Block that grants 75 Physical Armor against the next Hero Basic Attack. Stores up to 3 charges. Cooldown refreshes 200% faster while Fury is active</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Focused Attack (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Shattered Ground (W)
<ul>
<li>New Functionality:
<ul>
<li>Seismic Slam deals 75% damage to all targets hit and its splash damage travels 66% farther</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Mercenary Lord (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Battle Rage (Active)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Passively increases damage dealt to Mercenaries by 25%</li>
<li>Activate to Heal for 10% of Sonya’s maximum Health. 30 second charge cooldown. Stores up to 3 charges</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Follow Through (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Ferocious Healing (Active)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Shot of Fury (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 1</li>
<li>New Functionality:
<ul>
<li>Activate to instantly gain 50 Fury. 40 Second cooldown</li>
<li>After casting Seismic Slam, your next Basic Attack deals 40% more damage</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><span class="text-warning">Life Funnel (E)</span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-03-06-patch-notes.html" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Moved from Level 13</span></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Aftershock (W)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Spell Shield (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>No Escape (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16</li>
<li>Movement Speed bonus reduced from 25% to 20%</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Ruthless (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Whirlwind deals an additional 50 damage to Heroes below 33% Health. This damage does not generate additional Healing</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Imposing Presence (Active)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Giant Slammer (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Seismic Slam deals an additional 2% of Heroes’ maximum Health as damage</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Rampage (Passive)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Increases Basic Attack damage by 25%</li>
<li>Basic Attacks decrease the Ancient Spear’s cooldown 0.75 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li>Anger Management (R)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Nexus Blades (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Ignore Pain (Active)
<ul>
<li>Armor reduced from 75 to 60</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Composite Spear (Q)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 7</li>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Increases Ancient Spear’s range by 50%.</li>
<li>Hitting an enemy Hero with Ancient Spear grants 25 armor for 4 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Striding Giant (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Wrath of The Berserker increases maximum Health by 10% and grants the Striding Giant Ability while it is active</li>
<li>Striding Giant can be activated to become Unstoppable for 2 seconds. 30 second cooldown</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><strong>LEVEL (TIER)</strong></th>
  <th><strong>Sonya Talents</strong></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><strong>1 (1)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Furious Blow (W)</strong></td>
  <td>War Paint (Passive)</td>
  <td><em>Tough as Nails (Passive)</em></td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>4 (2)</strong></td>
  <td>Shattered Ground (W)</td>
  <td>Hurricane (E)</td>
  <td><em>Battle Rage (Active)</em></td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>7 (3)</strong></td>
  <td>Poisoned Spear (Q)</td>
  <td>Life Funnel (E)</td>
  <td><strong>Shot of Fury (Trait)</strong></td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>10 (4)</strong></td>
  <td>Leap (R)</td>
  <td>Wrath of the Berserker (R)</td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>13 (5)</strong></td>
  <td>Mystical Spear (Q)</td>
  <td><em>Ruthless (E)</em></td>
  <td><strong>No Escape (Trait)</strong></td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>16 (6)</strong></td>
  <td><em>Giant Slammer (W)</em></td>
  <td><em>Rampage (Passive)</em></td>
  <td>Nerves of Steel (Active)</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>20 (7)</strong></td>
  <td>Arreat Crater (R)</td>
  <td><em>Striding Giant (R)</em></td>
  <td><strong>Composite Spear (Q)</strong></td>
  <td>Ignore Pain (Active)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<ul>
<li>(!) indicates a Questing Talent.</li>
<li><em>Italic text</em> indicates a <em>NEW</em> Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Bold</strong> text indicates a <strong>MOVED</strong> Talent.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="collection">Collection</h3>

<p><strong>New Bundles</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The following new bundles are available for a limited time!
<ul>
<li>Enforcers Bundle</li>
<li>Enforcer Johanna Heroic Bundle</li>
<li>Paramedic Morales Heroic Bundle</li>
<li>Watchdog Greymane Heroic Bundle</li>
<li>Medivh Remastered Bundle</li>
<li>Sonya Remastered Bundle</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Skins</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Greymane</strong>
<ul>
<li>Watchdog Greymane</li>
<li>Arctic Watchdog Greymane</li>
<li>Desert Watchdog Greymane</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Johanna</strong>
<ul>
<li>Enforcer Johanna</li>
<li>Arctic Enforcer Johanna</li>
<li>Vigilante Enforcer Johanna</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Lt. Morales</strong>
<ul>
<li>Paramedic Morales</li>
<li>Covert Paramedic Morales</li>
<li>Fiery Paramedic Morales</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Azmodan</strong>
<ul>
<li>Competitive Azmodunk</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Lúcio</strong>
<ul>
<li>Vermelho Lúcio</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Medivh</strong>
<ul>
<li>Dark Medivh</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Sonya</strong>
<ul>
<li>Angelic Sonya</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Mounts</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>STORM Strider</strong>
<ul>
<li>Smart STORM Strider</li>
<li>Supercharged STORM Strider</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Lucky Piggy Bank</strong>
<ul>
<li>The Lucky Piggy Bank mount can be purchased for 7,000 gold.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Ranked Season Mount Rewards</strong>
<ul>
<li>The following Mounts have been awarded to players who reached Platinum in Hero League or Bronze in Team League:
<ul>
<li>Elemental Boar</li>
<li>Azure Elemental Boar</li>
<li>Verdant Elemental Boar</li>
</ul></li>
<li>The following Mounts have been awarded to players who reached Master or higher in Hero League or Team League:
<ul>
<li>Epic Elemental Boar</li>
<li>Epic Azure Elemental Boar</li>
<li>Epic Verdant Elemental Boar</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fixed a number of typo and tooltip errors across several aspects of the game.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Art</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Abathur:</strong> Fixed a pair of small holes in Xenotech Abathur’s model.</li>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> Talent icons for Adhesive Petroleum and Oil Dispersal now use different colors so they are easier to differentiate at a glance.</li>
<li><strong>Greymane:</strong> Greymane’s Health bar will no longer move during his victory animation.</li>
<li><strong>Greymane:</strong> The Doctor Wolf &amp; Stein skin’s Inner Beast visual effects no longer appear misaligned during Greymane’s Hearthstone animation.</li>
<li><strong>Sgt. Hammer:</strong> Neosteel Plating’s visual effects now correctly match Sgt. Hammer’s model while in Siege Mode.</li>
<li><strong>Tassadar:</strong> Moving while in the Mecha Tassadar Skin’s Mount form on Sky Temple will no longer cause flickering visual effects to appear on-screen.</li>
<li><strong>Valeera:</strong> After activating Crippling Poison and Wound Poison, visual effects on Valeera’s blades will no longer flicker while she is riding certain mounts.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Battlegrounds</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Mage Wars (Brawl):</strong> Kael’thas can now correctly cast Verdant Spheres as soon as its cooldown completes.</li>
<li><strong>Mercenaries:</strong> Fixed an issue in which neutral Mercenaries could spawn twice at their Mercenary Camp under specific circumstances.</li>
<li><strong>Try Mode:</strong> Zul’jin’s Headhunter Talent will now progress correctly after killing The Lost Vikings.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Brightwing:</strong> Soothing Mist will no longer Heal allies who are standing nearby while Brightwing is inside Anub’arak’s Cocoon, Lt. Morales’ Medivac, Stitches’ Gorge, or Zagara’s Devouring Maw.</li>
<li><strong>Brightwing:</strong> Phase Shift can no longer be cast on Allies who are in Stasis.</li>
<li><strong>D.Va:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Big Shot to deal no damage after learning the Pew! Pew! Pew! Talent and becoming affected by another damage or Spell Power reduction effect.</li>
<li><strong>Gall:</strong> Shadow Bolt Volley’s targeting reticle is no longer visible to enemies through the Fog of War.</li>
<li><strong>General:</strong> Fixed an issue that allowed certain Abilities to affect enemy Heroes in their own Hall of Storms:
<ul>
<li>Alarak – Telekinesis (W)</li>
<li>Brightwing – Emerald Wind (R)</li>
<li>Dehaka – Drag (Q)</li>
<li>Medivh – Ley Line Seal (R)</li>
<li>Stitches – Hook (Q)</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Casting Storm Bow with Quick Cast turned off will no longer prevent the player from issuing movement commands by holding down right-click.</li>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Issuing a Stop or Hold command will now correctly halt Hanzo’s movement and cancel Storm Bow’s primed state.</li>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Casting Storm Bow immediately after Dragon's Arrow will no longer cause Hanzo to become stuck in Storm Bow’s primed state.</li>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Striking an enemy Hero with Sonic Arrow just before they enter their Hall of Storms will no longer cause Sonic Arrow to display odd visual effects.</li>
<li><strong>Nazeebo:</strong> Using a mine entrance or exit on Haunted Mines during Gargantuan’s summoning animation will no longer cause Nazeebo to lose control of the Gargantuan.</li>
<li><strong>Raynor:</strong> Cooldown reduction granted by A Card to Play will no longer trigger twice after killing Leoric or Uther.</li>
<li><strong>Rexxar:</strong> Entering a Garden Terror while Misha is dead will no longer prevent Rexxar from issuing commands to Misha after she respawns.</li>
<li><strong>Samuro:</strong> <s>Can no longer swap places with a Mirror Image that is in the allied Hall of Storms.</s>
<ul>
<li>After some consideration, we believe this tactic can make for clever plays and have decided to revert this change.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Samuro:</strong> Mirror Images now correctly play Level Up and Quest Completion visual effects when Samuro levels up or completes a quest.</li>
<li><strong>Sgt. Hammer:</strong> Commands can now correctly be queued while Sgt. Hammer is returning to Tank Mode.</li>
<li><strong>Tassadar:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Basic Attacks in Archon form to deal splash damage twice to secondary attack targets after learning Prismatic Link.</li>
<li><strong>Tassadar:</strong> Completing the Templar’s Will quest and learning Twilight Archon will no longer grant extended range to Tassadar’s first Basic Attack in Twilight Archon form.</li>
<li><strong>Tracer:</strong> The Bullet Spray Talent now correctly increases the Melee’s radius by 40%.</li>
<li><strong>Tyrael:</strong> The remaining duration on bonus Armor granted by the Stalwart Angel Talent after using El’Druin’s Might to teleport will now correctly appear in the Buff Bar.</li>
<li><strong>Tyrande:</strong> The Darnassian Archery Talent’s Buff Bar icon now correctly displays the current number of stacks in addition to its duration.</li>
<li><strong>Zagara:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Heroes who were caught in the center of Devouring Maw to display their exit locations before Devouring Maw expired.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Sound</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Ana:</strong> Debilitating Dart activation is no longer audible when the player camera is far from Ana’s location.</li>
<li><strong>Falstad:</strong> Lightning Rod is no longer audible to enemies through the Fog of War.</li>
<li><strong>Greymane:</strong> Gilnean Cocktail will now correctly play sound effects when it hits a target in the Fog of War.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>User Interface</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Draft Mode:</strong> Using the voice volume control in a draft lobby will no longer prevent players from viewing teammates’ profiles using the right-click context menu.</li>
<li><strong>Minimap:</strong> Ping icons will no longer appear faded on the Minimap while shaders are set to medium.</li>
<li><strong>Score Screen:</strong> The in-game Score Screen will now correctly track quest progress for D.Va’s Crash Course Talent.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-02-26 PTR Patch Notes</title>
    <published>2018-02-26T18:55:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-02-26T18:55:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-02-26-ptr-patch-notes.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-02-26-ptr-patch-notes.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-ptr-patch-notes-february-26-2018">Heroes of the Storm PTR Patch Notes – February 26, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1494956881/patchlogo2017-05-16.jpg"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21509414" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21509414" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.30.4</small></div>

<p>Our next Heroes of the Storm patch has just hit the Public Test Realm and will
be available for playtesting until March 5. As always, if you encounter any
bugs or other issues during your PTR play sessions, please stop by the <a href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en/forum/20013840/">PTR
Bug Report forum</a> to let us
know about your experiences.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="art">Art</h3>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Nova:</strong> Precision Strike has received updated visual effects.</li>
<li><strong>Sgt. Hammer:</strong> Has received a custom Hearthstone animation.</li>
<li><strong>Thrall:</strong> After learning the Thunderstorm Talent, a UI indicator will now appear under the Health bar of Thrall’s most recent Chain Lightning target.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="design">Design</h3>

<p><strong>Trait Quests</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The following Hero Traits are now categorized as Repeatable Quests:
<ul>
<li><strong>Alarak: Sadism</strong>
<ul>
<li>Quest progress visual and sound effects will now play when earning Takedown credit.</li>
<li>Alarak’s Sadism Quest will now appear on the in-game Score Screen (TAB)</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Diablo: Black Soulstone</strong>
<ul>
<li>Quest progress and completion visual and sound effects will now play when Diablo gains Souls.</li>
<li>Quest completion will now appear in the Event Log on the left side of the screen.</li>
<li>Diablo’s Black Soulstone Quest will now appear in the in-game Score Screen (TAB).</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="heroes">Heroes</h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><a href="#specialist">Specialist</a></th>
  <th><a href="#support">Support</a></th>
  <th><a href="#warrior">Warrior</a></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#medivh">Medivh</a></td>
  <td><a href="#ana">Ana</a></td>
  <td><a href="#sonya">Sonya</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="specialist">Specialist</h3>

<h4 id="medivh">Medivh</h4>

<p>Medivh has received significant updates with today’s patch. Find his detailed
changes below, and then head to the <a href="https://battle.net/heroes/blog/21508381">Sonya and Medivh Gameplay Updates
blog</a> for more insight behind these
changes.</p>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Health scaling increased from 4% to 4.5% per level</li>
<li>Health Regeneration scaling increased from 4% to 4.5% per level</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Arcane Rift [Q]</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 200 to 170</li>
<li>Additional Functionality:
<ul>
<li><strong>Quest:</strong> Hit 40 enemy Heroes without dying.</li>
<li><strong>Reward:</strong> Permanently increase Arcane Rift’s damage by 75 and the cooldown reduction granted for hitting a Hero by 1 second</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Force of Will [W]</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 5 to 8 seconds</li>
<li>Mana cost increased from 50 to 60</li>
<li>Upon expiration, allies are healed for 20% of the damage absorbed</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Portal [E]</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 20 to 16 seconds</li>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 75 to 65 </li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Winds of Celerity [Z]
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 13</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Portal Mastery (Active)
<ul>
<li>Additional Functionality:
<ul>
<li>Portals can now be cast while in Raven form</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Raven’s Intellect (Z)
<ul>
<li>Additional Functionality:
<ul>
<li>Now also increases Health regeneration by 75% while in Raven form</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Mana regeneration bonus reduced from 100% to 75%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Bird’s Eye View (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Mage Armor [E]
<ul>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>An ally now gains 25 Armor for 4 seconds the first time they enter a Portal</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Raven Familiar [E]
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 7</li>
<li>Additional functionality:
<ul>
<li>Now also Slows enemies by 30% for 2.5 seconds.</li>
<li>A Raven now joins an ally each time they enter a Portal</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Dust of Appearance (Active)
<ul>
<li>Adjusted Functionality:
<ul>
<li>Permanently increases vision range in Raven Form by 25%.</li>
<li>Activate to greatly increase Medivh’s vision range for 5 seconds, and reveal enemy Heroes in the area for 8 seconds. Does not cancel Raven form</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>The Master’s Touch [Q]
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Arcane Explosion [W]
<ul>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Deals 90 damage to nearby enemies when Force of Will expires. Also deals an additional 100% of damage taken, up to 365 bonus damage</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Explosion radius increased from 3 to 3.5</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Mystic Assault [Q]</strong>
<ul>
<li>If Arcane Rift hits an enemy Hero, Medivh’s next Basic Attack within 6 seconds deals 40% more damage and Heals for 40% of the damage dealt</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Force of Magic [W]</strong>
<ul>
<li>Preventing 268 or more damage with a single Force of Will grants Medivh 20% Spell Power for 12 seconds. This can stack up to 2 times</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Quickening [Q]
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Astral Projection [E]
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Circle of Protection [W]
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16</li>
<li>Now applies a talented version of Force of Will to nearby allies</li>
<li>Radius increased from 2.5 to 3</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Enduring Will [W]
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16</li>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>If Force of Will absorbs 268 damage, its cooldown is reduced to 3 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Reabsorption [W]
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16</li>
<li>Increases Force of Will’s Healing to 50% of the damage taken</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Arcane Charge [Q]
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 7</li>
<li>Damage bonus reduced from 30% to 15%</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Stable Portal [W]
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 1</li>
<li>New Functionality:
<ul>
<li>Reduces Portal’s cooldown by 25% and increases Portal duration by 50%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Temporal Flux (Passive)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Basic Attacks reduce Medivh’s Heroic cooldown by 1 second. Hitting enemy Heroes with Arcane Rift reduces Medivh’s Heroic cooldown by 3 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li>Invisibility (Active) renamed to: Dust of Disappearance (Active)
<ul>
<li>No longer costs Mana</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><strong>LEVEL (TIER)</strong></th>
  <th><strong>Medivh Talents</strong></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><strong>1 (1)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Winds of Celerity [Z]</strong></td>
  <td>Raven’s Intellect [Z]</td>
  <td>Portal Mastery (Active)</td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>4 (2)</strong></td>
  <td>Mage Armor [E]</td>
  <td><strong>Raven Familiar [E]</strong></td>
  <td>Dust of Appearance (Active)</td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>7 (3)</strong></td>
  <td><em>Mystic Assault [Q]</em></td>
  <td>Arcane Explosion [W]</td>
  <td><em>Force of Magic [W]</em></td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>10 (4)</strong></td>
  <td>Poly Bomb [R]</td>
  <td>Ley Line Seal [R]</td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>13 (5)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Circle of Protection [W]</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Enduring Will [W]</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Reabsorption [W]</strong></td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>16 (6)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Arcane Charge [Q]</strong></td>
  <td><em>Temporal Flux [Q]</em></td>
  <td><strong>Stable Portal [E]</strong></td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>20 (7)</strong></td>
  <td>Glyph of Poly Bomb [R]</td>
  <td>Medivh Cheats! [R]</td>
  <td>Guardian of Tirisfal [Q]</td>
  <td>Arcane Brilliance (Active)</td>
  <td>Dust of Disappearance (Active)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<ul>
<li>(!) indicates a Questing Talent.</li>
<li><em>Italic text</em> indicates a <em>NEW</em> Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Bold</strong> text indicates a <strong>MOVED</strong> Talent.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="support">Support</h3>

<h4 id="ana">Ana</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Shrike (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Added functionality:
<ul>
<li>Ana Heals for 50% of Shrike damage dealt to Heroes</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Healing Dart [Q]</strong>
<ul>
<li>Healing reduced from 237 to 215</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Biotic Grenade [W]</strong>
<ul>
<li>Adjusted functionality:
<ul>
<li>Amplified Healing now only affects Ana’s Healing output</li>
<li>Amplified Healing duration increased from 3 to 4 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Nano Boost [R]</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 50 to 60 seconds</li>
<li>Mana cost increased from 40 to 60</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Eye of Horus [R]</strong>
<ul>
<li>Self-cancelling no longer places the Ability on a 10 second cooldown</li>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 60 to 45 seconds</li>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 75 to 45</li>
<li>Number of shots reduced from 8 to 6</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Grenade Calibration [W]
<ul>
<li>Add base functionality</li>
<li>The amplified healing effect of Biotic Grenade now works on all healing</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Piercing Darts [E]
<ul>
<li>1st quest unlock
<ul>
<li>Range increase from 50 to 25%</li>
</ul></li>
<li>2nd quest unlock
<ul>
<li>Range increase from 50 to 25%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Detachable Box Magazine (Passive)
<ul>
<li>1st quest unlock
<ul>
<li>New functionality
<ul>
<li>The self-healing for Shrike now also applies to non-Heroes</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Aim Down Sights (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Shrike activation cooldown reduced from 10 to 3 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Air Strike [W]
<ul>
<li>Airborne duration reduced from 4 to 3 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Debilitating Dart (Active)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 45 to 20 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Mind-Numbing Agent (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Spell Power reduction per Shrike stack decreased from 15% to 10%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="warrior">Warrior</h3>

<h4 id="sonya">Sonya</h4>

<p>Sonya has received significant updates with today’s patch. Find her detailed
changes below, and then head to the <a href="https://battle.net/heroes/blog/21508381">Sonya and Medivh Gameplay Updates
blog</a> for more insight behind these
changes.</p>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Block (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Furious Blow [W]
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16</li>
<li>New functionality
<ul>
<li>Every fourth Seismic Slam deals 40% more damage and costs no Fury</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Tough as Nails (Passive)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Every 12 seconds gain a stack of Block that grants 75 Physical Armor against the next Hero Basic Attack. Stores up to 3 charges. Cooldown refreshes 200% faster while Fury is active</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Focused Attack (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Shattered Ground [W]
<ul>
<li>New Functionality:
<ul>
<li>Seismic Slam deals 75% damage to all targets hit and its splash damage travels 66% farther</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Mercenary Lord (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Battle Rage (Active)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Passively increases damage dealt to Mercenaries by 25%</li>
<li>Activate to Heal for 10% of Sonya’s maximum Health. 30 second charge cooldown. Stores up to 3 charges</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Follow Through (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Ferocious Healing (Active)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Shot of Fury (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 1</li>
<li>New Functionality:
<ul>
<li>Activate to instantly gain 50 Fury. 40 Second cooldown</li>
<li>After casting Seismic Slam, your next Basic Attack deals 40% more damage</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Aftershock [W]
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Spell Shield (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>No Escape (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16</li>
<li>Movement Speed bonus reduced from 25% to 20%</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Ruthless [E]</strong>
<ul>
<li>Whirlwind deals an additional 50 damage to Heroes below 33% Health. This damage does not generate additional Healing</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Imposing Presence (Active)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Giant Slammer [W]</strong>
<ul>
<li>Seismic Slam deals an additional 2% of Heroes’ maximum Health as damage</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Rampage (Passive)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Increases Basic Attack damage by 25%</li>
<li>Basic Attacks decrease the Ancient Spear’s cooldown 0.75 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li>Anger Management [R]
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Nexus Blades (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Ignore Pain (Active)
<ul>
<li>Armor reduced from 75 to 60</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Composite Spear [Q]
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 7</li>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Increases Ancient Spear’s range by 50%.</li>
<li>Hitting an enemy Hero with Ancient Spear grants 25 armor for 4 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent: Striding Giant [R]</strong>
<ul>
<li>Wrath of The Berserker increases maximum Health by 10% and grants the Striding Giant Ability while it is active</li>
<li>Striding Giant can be activated to become Unstoppable for 2 seconds. 30 second cooldown</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><strong>LEVEL (TIER)</strong></th>
  <th><strong>Sonya Talents</strong></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><strong>1 (1)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Furious Blow [W]</strong></td>
  <td>War Paint (Passive)</td>
  <td><em>Tough as Nails (Passive)</em></td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>4 (2)</strong></td>
  <td>Shattered Ground [W]</td>
  <td>Hurricane [E]</td>
  <td><em>Battle Rage (Active)</em></td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>7 (3)</strong></td>
  <td>Poisoned Spear [Q]</td>
  <td>Life Funnel (E)</td>
  <td><strong>Shot of Fury (Trait)</strong></td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>10 (4)</strong></td>
  <td>Leap (R)</td>
  <td>Wrath of the Berserker (R)</td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>13 (5)</strong></td>
  <td>Mystical Spear [Q]</td>
  <td><em>Ruthless [E]</em></td>
  <td><strong>No Escape (Trait)</strong></td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>16 (6)</strong></td>
  <td><em>Giant Slammer [W]</em></td>
  <td><em>Rampage (Passive)</em></td>
  <td>Nerves of Steel (Active)</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>20 (7)</strong></td>
  <td>Arreat Crater [R]</td>
  <td><em>Striding Giant [R]</em></td>
  <td><strong>Composite Spear [Q]</strong></td>
  <td>Ignore Pain (Active)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<ul>
<li>(!) indicates a Questing Talent.</li>
<li><em>Italic text</em> indicates a <em>NEW</em> Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Bold</strong> text indicates a <strong>MOVED</strong> Talent.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="collection">Collection</h3>

<p><strong>New Bundles</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The following new bundles are available for a limited time!
<ul>
<li>Enforcers Bundle</li>
<li>Enforcer Johanna Heroic Bundle</li>
<li>Paramedic Morales Heroic Bundle</li>
<li>Watchdog Greymane Heroic Bundle</li>
<li>Medivh Remastered Bundle</li>
<li>Sonya Remastered Bundle</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Skins</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Greymane</strong>
<ul>
<li>Watchdog Greymane</li>
<li>Arctic Watchdog Greymane</li>
<li>Desert Watchdog Greymane</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Johanna</strong>
<ul>
<li>Enforcer Johanna</li>
<li>Arctic Enforcer Johanna</li>
<li>Vigilante Enforcer Johanna</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Lt. Morales</strong>
<ul>
<li>Paramedic Morales</li>
<li>Covert Paramedic Morales</li>
<li>Fiery Paramedic Morales</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Azmodan</strong>
<ul>
<li>Competitive Azmodunk</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Lúcio</strong>
<ul>
<li>Vermelho Lúcio</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Medivh</strong>
<ul>
<li>Dark Medivh</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Sonya</strong>
<ul>
<li>Angelic Sonya</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Mounts</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>STORM Strider</strong>
<ul>
<li>Smart STORM Strider</li>
<li>Supercharged STORM Strider</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Lucky Piggy Bank</strong>
<ul>
<li>The Lucky Piggy Bank mount can be purchased for 7,000 gold.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Ranked Season Mount Rewards</strong>
<ul>
<li>The following Mounts have been awarded to players who reached Platinum in Hero League or Bronze in Team League:
<ul>
<li>Elemental Boar</li>
<li>Azure Elemental Boar</li>
<li>Verdant Elemental Boar</li>
</ul></li>
<li>The following Mounts have been awarded to players who reached Master or higher in Hero League or Team League:
<ul>
<li>Epic Elemental Boar</li>
<li>Epic Azure Elemental Boar</li>
<li>Epic Verdant Elemental Boar</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fixed a number of typo and tooltip errors across several aspects of the game.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Art</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Abathur:</strong> Fixed a pair of small holes in Xenotech Abathur’s model.</li>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> Talent icons for Adhesive Petroleum and Oil Dispersal now use different colors so they are easier to differentiate at a glance.</li>
<li><strong>Greymane:</strong> Greymane’s Health bar will no longer move during his victory animation.</li>
<li><strong>Greymane:</strong> The Doctor Wolf &amp; Stein skin’s Inner Beast visual effects no longer appear misaligned during Greymane’s Hearthstone animation.</li>
<li><strong>Sgt. Hammer:</strong> Neosteel Plating’s visual effects now correctly match Sgt. Hammer’s model while in Siege Mode.</li>
<li><strong>Tassadar:</strong> Moving while in the Mecha Tassadar Skin’s Mount form on Sky Temple will no longer cause flickering visual effects to appear on-screen.</li>
<li><strong>Valeera:</strong> After activating Crippling Poison and Wound Poison, visual effects on Valeera’s blades will no longer flicker while she is riding certain mounts.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Battlegrounds</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Mage Wars (Brawl):</strong> Kael’thas can now correctly cast Verdant Spheres as soon as its cooldown completes.</li>
<li><strong>Mercenaries:</strong> Fixed an issue in which neutral Mercenaries could spawn twice at their Mercenary Camp under specific circumstances.</li>
<li><strong>Try Mode:</strong> Zul’jin’s Headhunter Talent will now progress correctly after killing The Lost Vikings.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Brightwing:</strong> Soothing Mist will no longer Heal allies who are standing nearby while Brightwing is inside Anub’arak’s Cocoon, Lt. Morales’ Medivac, Stitches’ Gorge, or Zagara’s Devouring Maw.</li>
<li><strong>Brightwing:</strong> Phase Shift can no longer be cast on Allies who are in Stasis.</li>
<li><strong>D.Va:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Big Shot to deal no damage after learning the Pew! Pew! Pew! Talent and becoming affected by another damage or Spell Power reduction effect.</li>
<li><strong>Gall:</strong> Shadow Bolt Volley’s targeting reticle is no longer visible to enemies through the Fog of War.</li>
<li><strong>General:</strong> Fixed an issue that allowed certain Abilities to affect enemy Heroes in their own Hall of Storms:
<ul>
<li>Alarak – Telekinesis [W]</li>
<li>Brightwing – Emerald Wind [R]</li>
<li>Dehaka – Drag [Q]</li>
<li>Medivh – Ley Line Seal [R]</li>
<li>Stitches – Hook [Q]</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Casting Storm Bow with Quick Cast turned off will no longer prevent the player from issuing movement commands by holding down right-click.</li>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Issuing a Stop or Hold command will now correctly halt Hanzo’s movement and cancel Storm Bow’s primed state.</li>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Casting Storm Bow immediately after Dragon's Arrow will no longer cause Hanzo to become stuck in Storm Bow’s primed state.</li>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Striking an enemy Hero with Sonic Arrow just before they enter their Hall of Storms will no longer cause Sonic Arrow to display odd visual effects.</li>
<li><strong>Nazeebo:</strong> Using a mine entrance or exit on Haunted Mines during Gargantuan’s summoning animation will no longer cause Nazeebo to lose control of the Gargantuan.</li>
<li><strong>Raynor:</strong> Cooldown reduction granted by A Card to Play will no longer trigger twice after killing Leoric or Uther.</li>
<li><strong>Rexxar:</strong> Entering a Garden Terror while Misha is dead will no longer prevent Rexxar from issuing commands to Misha after she respawns.</li>
<li><strong>Samuro:</strong> Can no longer swap places with a Mirror Image that is in the allied Hall of Storms.</li>
<li><strong>Samuro:</strong> Mirror Images now correctly play Level Up and Quest Completion visual effects when Samuro levels up or completes a quest.</li>
<li><strong>Sgt. Hammer:</strong> Commands can now correctly be queued while Sgt. Hammer is returning to Tank Mode.</li>
<li><strong>Tassadar:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Basic Attacks in Archon form to deal splash damage twice to secondary attack targets after learning Prismatic Link.</li>
<li><strong>Tassadar:</strong> Completing the Templar’s Will quest and learning Twilight Archon will no longer grant extended range to Tassadar’s first Basic Attack in Twilight Archon form.</li>
<li><strong>Tyrael:</strong> The remaining duration on bonus Armor granted by the Stalwart Angel Talent after using El’Druin’s Might to teleport will now correctly appear in the Buff Bar.</li>
<li><strong>Tyrande:</strong> The Darnassian Archery Talent’s Buff Bar icon now correctly displays the current number of stacks in addition to its duration.</li>
<li><strong>Zagara:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Heroes who were caught in the center of Devouring Maw to display their exit locations before Devouring Maw expired.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Sound</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Ana:</strong> Debilitating Dart activation is no longer audible when the player camera is far from Ana’s location.</li>
<li><strong>Falstad:</strong> Lightning Rod is no longer audible to enemies through the Fog of War.</li>
<li><strong>Greymane:</strong> Gilnean Cocktail will now correctly play sound effects when it hits a target in the Fog of War.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>User Interface</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Minimap:</strong> Ping icons will no longer appear faded on the Minimap while shaders are set to medium.</li>
<li><strong>Score Screen:</strong> The in-game Score Screen will now correctly track quest progress for D.Va’s Crash Course Talent.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-02-21 Balance Update</title>
    <published>2018-02-21T18:35:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-02-21T18:35:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-02-21-balance-update.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-02-21-balance-update.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-patch-notes-february-21-2018">Heroes of the Storm Patch Notes – February 21, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1485586192/balanceupdate.png"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21535475" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21535475" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.30.3</small></div>

<p>We’ve just released a patch to the live servers in order to implement Voice
Communication, as well as apply some balance updates and bug fixes.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="general">General</h3>

<p><strong>Voice Communication</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Voice Communication has been added to Heroes of the Storm! Read the <a href="https://battle.net/heroes/blog/21535471">Voice Communication blog</a> for more information about how to use it in-game.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="heroes">Heroes</h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><a href="#assassin">Assassin</a></th>
  <th><a href="#specialist">Specialist</a></th>
  <th><a href="#support">Support</a></th>
  <th><a href="#warrior">Warrior</a></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#maiev">Maiev</a></td>
  <td><a href="#xul">Xul</a></td>
  <td><a href="#tyrande">Tyrande</a></td>
  <td><a href="#sonya">Sonya</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#malthael">Malthael</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#thrall">Thrall</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#zeratul">Zeratul</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="assassin">Assassin</h3>

<h4 id="maiev">Maiev</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Health reduced from 2236 to 2150</li>
<li>Health Regeneration reduced from 4.66 to 4.48</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Vault of the Wardens (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 8 to 9 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Fan of Knives (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 170 to 162</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Armored Assault (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Damage bonus reduced from 25% to 20%</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Vengeful Knives (E)
<ul>
<li>Bonus damage per Hero hit increased from 1% to 1.2%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> The changes we released on <a href="https://battle.net/heroes/blog/21508378">January
  9</a> helped bring Maiev’s win-rate down
  to mortal levels, but she was still a bit too powerful, overall. Today’s
  changes are aimed at slightly lowering both her survivability and burst damage
  throughput. Our data is showing the majority of her Talents are in healthy
  spots, but we will keep an eye on them as players start adapting to certain
  playstyles.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="malthael">Malthael</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Soul Rip (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mana cost increased from 20 to 25</li>
<li>Healing reduced from 36 to 25 per target hit</li>
<li>Healing from Heroic targets increased from 3% to 4% of the Hero’s maximum Health</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Tormented Souls (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 100 to 80 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Die Alone (Q)
<ul>
<li>Damage bonus reduced from 75% to 50%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Soul Siphon (Q)</span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/heroesofthestorm/comments/7z7dcp/patch_notes_feb_21st_2018/dulvotd/" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Bonus healing from Heroic targets increased from 3.75% to 4.75% of the Hero's maximum Health</span></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Soul Collector (Q)
<ul>
<li>Bonus range reduced from 50% to 25%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> Malthael was designed to be powerful in the solo
  lane, but his dominance in the game’s early laning phase was unrivaled. We’re
  reducing this by making him heal less when Soul Ripping Minions, but
  increasing his Hero-only healing so that he can still keep himself alive in
  late-game team fights. We’re also reducing the power of Die Alone and
  increasing his Mana tension to taper some of his early game power. By
  increasing Soul Rip’s Mana usage, we’re also reducing some of the power
  Malthael had when double-soaking lanes (especially when combined with On a
  Pale Horse), as he tends to use Soul Rip twice as often when doing so. The
  overall goal is to reduce the power of a few particularly dominating builds,
  while making sure that he still feels powerful past the early game.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="thrall">Thrall</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Chain Lightning (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Bounce range increased by 20%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="zeratul">Zeratul</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Cleave (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage increased from 200 to 212</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Singularity Spike (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage increased from 228 to 240</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Void Prison (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 100 to 80</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Might of the Nerazim (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Basic Attack damage bonus reduced from 40% to 30%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> These tuning changes are meant to redistribute
  Zeratul’s damage while also giving him a slight buff. Zeratul should now be a
  bit stronger during the earlier portions of the game if he takes Might of the
  Nerazim, but should have less opportunity cost if he chooses to take Void
  Prison, instead.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="specialist">Specialist</h3>

<h4 id="xul">Xul</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Health increased from 1900 to 2000</li>
<li>Health Regeneration increased 3.957 to 4.168</li>
<li>Basic Attack damage increased from 104 to 110</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Raise Skeleton (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Skeletal Warrior Health reduced from 240 to 225</li>
<li>Skeletal Warrior damage reduced from 23 to 21</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Bone Prison (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 12 to 10 seconds</li>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 80 to 70</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Trag’Oul’s Essence (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mana restoration per Skeletal Warrior attack reduced from 0.5% to 0.2% of Xul’s maximum Mana</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> We like that Xul is a strong pushing Hero who has an
  identity as a great duo-lane soaker, but believe that his identity has been
  pushed too far into this role, and we would like to see him have more presence
  in team fights. We’re making adjustments to push him in this direction by
  buffing his base stats and toning down his split-push potential.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="support">Support</h3>

<h4 id="tyrande">Tyrande</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Light of Elune (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 12 to 11 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="warrior">Warrior</h3>

<h4 id="sonya">Sonya</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Basic Attack damage reduced from 88 to 84</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Poisoned Spear (Q)
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 125% to 100% of Ancient Spear’s damage.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nerves of Steel (Active)
<ul>
<li>Duration reduced from 5 to 3 seconds</li>
<li>Shield amount reduced from 30% to 25% of Maximum Health</li>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 70 to 60 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> We originally applied these adjustments in a <a href="https://battle.net/heroes/blog/21464985">patch
  on January 24</a>, but Sonya was so
  eager to get back into battle that she forgot to take them with her. We're
  giving these changes back to the Barbarian, and have (politely) asked her to
  remember to bring them along the next time she leaps into the fray.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Diablo:</strong> Lightning Breath sound effects will no longer stop playing before the Ability is finished channeling.</li>
<li><strong>Junkrat:</strong> Heroes killed by Concussion Mine will no longer respawn at their death location and then slide across the Battleground.</li>
<li><strong>Junkrat:</strong> Issuing movement commands during Rocket Ride will no longer cause Junkrat to become separated from his Mount.</li>
<li><strong>Junkrat:</strong> Movement commands that the player did not issue will no longer appear on the terrain in front of RIP-Tire’s model.</li>
<li><strong>Junkrat:</strong> Targeting unpathable terrain with Rocket Ride will no longer cause Total Mayhem Grenades to visually persist on the Battleground.</li>
<li><strong>Junkrat:</strong> Concussion Mine can no longer displace Leoric from Wraith Walk’s starting location if the Mine is detonated in the same moment that Wraith Walk ends.</li>
<li><strong>Li Li:</strong> After learning the Lightning Serpent Talent, Cloud Serpent attacks that are bouncing to additional targets when the Ability expires will now correctly deal damage.</li>
<li><strong>Lt. Morales:</strong> The tooltip for the Healing Beam icon next to Lt. Morales’ in-game portrait will now correctly display the Ability’s cooldown duration.</li>
<li><strong>Malfurion:</strong> An ally who is affected by multiple Regrowths will now be correctly healed by Moonfire and have Stuns, Roots, and Slows removed by Nature’s Cure.</li>
<li><strong>Movement Abilities:</strong> Certain movement-based Abilities, like Greymane’s Dark Flight or Chen’s Flying Kick, will no longer fail to move the Hero toward a target currently affected by Varian’s Taunt or Garrosh’s Warlord’s Challenge.</li>
<li><strong>Sgt. Hammer:</strong> Can now correctly deploy Biotic Emitters on Volskaya Foundry while in Siege Mode.</li>
<li><strong>The Butcher:</strong> Fixed an issue that prevented The Butcher from collecting Meat while piloting the Triglav Protector, Dragon Knight, or Garden Terror.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-02-14 Hotfix Patch</title>
    <published>2018-02-14T18:36:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-02-14T18:36:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-02-14-hotfix-patch.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-02-14-hotfix-patch.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-hotfix-notes-february-14-2018">Heroes of the Storm Hotfix Notes — February 14, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1494956881/patchlogo2017-05-16.jpg"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21514203" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21514203" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.30.2</small></div>

<p>We’ve just released a new Heroes of the Storm patch to apply a few bug fixes.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>Heroes, Talents, &amp; Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Genji:</strong> Fixed an issue preventing certain cleave attacks, such as Malthael’s Basic Attacks and Xul’s Cursed Strikes, from removing stacks of Genji’s Dodge.</li>
<li><strong>Ice Block:</strong> Fixed an issue allowing certain Abilities to be cast during Ice Block, including Jaina’s Ice Blink, Brightwing’s Storm Shield, and Malfurion’s Astral Communion.</li>
<li><strong>Jaina:</strong> The Wintermute Talent now correctly causes Jaina’s Water Elemental to mimic her Basic Abilities.</li>
<li><strong>Lunara:</strong> The Galloping Gait Talent no longer grants a permanent Movement Speed bonus.</li>
<li><strong>Tyrael:</strong> The Stalwart Angel Talent’s tooltip now displays the correct values for its duration and Armor bonus.</li>
<li><strong>Maiev:</strong> Casting Spirit of Vengeance just as a Core is destroyed will no longer cause the Spirit to cease animating.</li>
<li><strong>Maiev:</strong> Activating Naisha’s Memento will now correctly display an icon indicating its duration in the buff bar.</li>
<li><strong>Nova:</strong> Fixed an issue causing Holo Decoys to deal slightly more damage than intended after learning Lethal Decoy.</li>
<li><strong>Rehgar:</strong> The Rising Storm Talent will no longer increase Lightning Shield’s damage versus non-Heroic enemies.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-02-09 Balance Update</title>
    <published>2018-02-09T18:40:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-02-09T18:40:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-02-09-balance-update.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-02-09-balance-update.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-patch-notes-february-09-2018">HEROES OF THE STORM PATCH NOTES — FEBRUARY 09, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1485586192/balanceupdate.png"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21508378" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21508378" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.30.1</small></div>

<p>Our most recent Heroes of the Storm patch is now live containing balance
changes to Maiev, The Warden.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="assassin">Assassin</h3>

<h4 id="maiev">Maiev</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Basic Attack Damage reduced from 162 to 150</li>
<li>Base Maximum Health increased from 2150 to 2236</li>
<li>Health Regeneration increased from 4.48 to 4.66</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Fan of Knives (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage decreased from 180 to 170</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Vault of the Wardens (D)</strong>
<ul>
<li>No longer grants passive Armor</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Naisha’s Memento (Active)
<ul>
<li>Bounces no longer deal bonus damage</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Armored Assault (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Physical Damage bonus decreased from 35 to 25%</li>
<li>Now activates if Maiev has any amount of bonus Armor</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> Maiev has arrived in the Nexus and seems to be
  obliterating her foes (as she should) but is slightly deadlier than we
  intended. The Warden’s survivability is currently too high, which allows her
  to get tons of resets on Fan of Knives while ignoring enemy threats. To
  address this, we’re removing her armor gain from Vault of the Wardens, while
  slightly lowering her damage output so that she has to stick around in the
  fight a little longer to take down her opponents. After these changes, we’ll
  continue to keep an eye on Maiev to be sure that she has enough survivability
  to perform her melee Assassin role, without it feeling like her enemies have
  little-to-no options for counterplay</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-02-06 Patch Notes</title>
    <published>2018-02-06T17:25:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-02-06T17:25:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-02-06-patch-notes.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-02-06-patch-notes.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-patch-notes-february-6-2018">Heroes of the Storm Patch Notes - February 6, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1494956881/patchlogo2017-05-16.jpg"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21509171" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21509171" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.30.0</small></div>

<p>Our most recent Heroes of the Storm patch featuring Maiev, Voice Chat, and
balance updates is now available for play.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="lunar-festival-2018">Lunar Festival 2018</h3>

<p>Join us in celebrating Lunar Festival this year by completing matches in
Versus A.I., Quick Match, Unranked, or Ranked modes, and you’ll pick up some
sweet new loot! The event kicks off during the week of Tuesday, February 6,
and concludes on Monday, March 5, so be sure to complete the quests below
before Lunar Festival comes to an end.</p>

<p><strong>Quests and Rewards</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Part 1:</strong> Play 2 Games
<ul>
<li><strong>Reward:</strong> Cute Lunar Skyrocket Spray</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Part 2:</strong> Play 5 Games
<ul>
<li><strong>Reward:</strong> Lunar Warcrest Banner</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Part 3:</strong> Play 8 Games
<ul>
<li><strong>Reward:</strong> Cute Lunar Guardian Portrait</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Part 4:</strong> Play 10 Games
<ul>
<li><strong>Reward:</strong> Lunar Skyrocket Mount</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p>You can also stop by the <a href="http://battle.net/heroes/game/events/lunar-festival-2018">Lunar Festival 2018 mini-
site</a> to learn more
about the event and find out how you can earn ornate Lunar Festival 2018 Loot
Chests just by playing Heroes of the Storm!</p>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="new-hero-maiev">New Hero: Maiev</h3>

<p>Maiev Shadowsong stood watch over the imprisoned Betrayer for ten thousand
years, and hunted him relentlessly after he was released. Some say she’s
determined; others say she’s obsessed. Either way, she will stop at nothing to
ensure the security of her world.</p>

<p><strong>Trait</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Vault of the Wardens (D)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Leap into the air, becoming immune to all hostile effects for 0.75 seconds.</li>
<li>Passive: Maiev has 10 Armor.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Basic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Fan of Knives (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Deal 180 damage to enemies in a crescent area.</li>
<li>Hitting at least 2 enemy Heroes with Fan of Knives reduces its cooldown to 0.5 seconds, and refunds the Mana cost.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Umbral Bind (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Maiev’s next Basic Attack cleaves and applies a tether to enemy Heroes hit for 2.5 seconds. If a tethered Hero moves too far from Maiev, they are pulled toward her, dealing 110 damage and breaking the tether.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Spirit of Vengeance (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Send a shadow of Maiev outward that will return to its cast location, dealing 100 damage to enemies along both paths. Deals 100% more damage to enemy Heroes.</li>
<li>Reactivate to Blink to the shadow’s location.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Containment Disc (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Throw a glaive in the target direction. If an enemy Hero is hit, Containment Disk can be reactivated to remove their vision and Time Stop them for 4 seconds.</li>
<li>Containment Disc automatically activates 6 seconds after hitting a Hero.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Warden's Cage (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Summon 8 Warden Avatars as a cage around Maiev. After 1.5 seconds, enemy Heroes that come in contact with an Avatar re knocked to the center of the cage, and that Avatar is consumed. Warden Avatars last 7 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="user-interface">User Interface</h3>

<p><strong>Voice Chat</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>NOTE: While available in the PTR, Voice Chat will not be enabled on the live servers until a later date.</strong></li>
<li>Voice chat for Parties and Teams has been introduced to Heroes of the Storm.
<ul>
<li>By default, players will automatically join Party voice chat.</li>
<li>Team voice chat is opt-in, but can be toggled to auto-join in the Voice Chat settings. There is a team voice reminder dialog at the beginning of matches that is enabled by default, but can be disabled.</li>
<li>If Team voice auto-join is enabled and you are already in party voice, a confirmation dialog will appear that defaults to Join.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Voice settings can be adjusted in the Voice Chat tab of the Options menu.
<ul>
<li>A voice chat widget is also available in the top left of most screens. This widget lets you quickly change channels or join/leave voice channels.
<ul>
<li>This can be found in the Tab screen while in a match.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Microphone and speaker icons can be clicked on to mute/unmute.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Target Info Panel</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Target Info Panels have been introduced to allow players to investigate a unit's gameplay stats in real time.
<ul>
<li>The Target Info Panel will display in the top left of the screen after selecting a friendly or enemy target with left-click.
<ul>
<li>​The Target Info Panel can be repositioned by clicking and dragging to your desired location.
<ul>
<li>​Double-clicking the info panel will reset it to the default position.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>The Target Info Panel will display the following information:
<ul>
<li>Health &amp; Health Regen</li>
<li>Mana &amp; Mana Regen</li>
<li>Basic Attack Damage</li>
<li>Attacks per Second</li>
<li>Attack Range</li>
<li>Spell Power Modifier</li>
<li>Movement Speed</li>
<li>Physical &amp; Spell Armor</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Battleground Objective Counters</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>All Battlegrounds with turn-in mechanics (Blackheart’s Bay, Tomb of the Spider Queen, Booty Coffers Heroes Brawl) will now show a visual indicator when a team’s gathered objective count is high enough to complete a turn-in.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="art">Art</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Pings:</strong> Ping icons that appear overhead have received updated visual effects.</li>
<li><span class="text-warning"><strong>Mercenaries:</strong> Mage Knight's health bar has received updated visual effects.</span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://redd.it/7vre1u" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Abathur:</strong> A crown icon will now appear above Heroes’ Minimap portraits when they are affected by Abathur’s Symbiote.</li>
<li><strong>Ana:</strong> An overlay will now display for Heroes affected by Nano Boost.</li>
<li><strong>Archangel Diablo:</strong> Apocalypse visual effects that appear on the terrain have been updated to make them more obvious to players on both teams.</li>
<li><strong>Falstad:</strong> Hinterland Blast visual effects now more closely match the edges of its area of effect.</li>
<li><strong>Junkrat:</strong> Frag Launcher’s targeting reticle has received updated art.</li>
<li><strong>Leoric:</strong> Entomb’s targeting reticle has received updated art to better reflect the Ability’s shape.</li>
<li><strong>Li-Ming:</strong> Magic Missiles have received updated visual effects to make them more apparent.</li>
<li><span class="text-warning"><strong>Li-Ming:</strong> Arcane Orb visual effects now more closely match the edge of its area of effect.</span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://redd.it/7vre1u" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a></li>
<li><strong>Lt. Morales:</strong> An overlay will now display for Heroes affected by Stim Drone.</li>
<li><strong>Tychus:</strong> Minigun visual effects have been updated to make the Ability more apparent while it is active.</li>
<li><strong>Tychus:</strong> Overkill’s retargeting icon has received updated art.</li>
<li>The following heroes have received updated visual effects to coincide with Talent changes:
<ul>
<li>Greymane</li>
<li>Malthael</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="battlegrounds">Battlegrounds</h3>

<p><strong>Ranked Battleground Rotation</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Battleground rotation for Ranked Play is unchanged, and remains as follows:
<ul>
<li>Battlefield of Eternity</li>
<li>Braxis Holdout</li>
<li>Cursed Hollow</li>
<li>Dragon Shire</li>
<li>Infernal Shrines</li>
<li>Sky Temple</li>
<li>Tomb of the Spider Queen</li>
<li>Towers of Doom</li>
<li>Volskaya Foundry</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Volskaya Foundry</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Mercenary Pickups</strong>
<ul>
<li>Healing Pulse now acts as a totem, healing all Heroes in the area after being placed.</li>
<li>Turrets can now be placed instantly.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Triglav Protector</strong>
<ul>
<li>The Protector will gain 10 Armor and 25% increased damage if both the Pilot and Gunner seats are occupied</li>
<li>Base Health has been increased from 9500 to 10450</li>
<li>Health Scaling has been increased by 10%</li>
<li><strong>Pilot: Rocket Fist (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Duration of structure debuff effect has been increased from 2 to 4 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Gunner: Gatling Cannon (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Gatling Cannon will now fire immediately, instead of after a short delay</li>
<li>Gatling Cannon rounds will now travel 50% faster</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="heroes">Heroes</h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><a href="#assassin">Assassin</a></th>
  <th><a href="#support">Support</a></th>
  <th><a href="#warrior">Warrior</a></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#genji">Genji</a></td>
  <td><a href="#auriel">Auriel</a></td>
  <td><a href="#sonya">Sonya</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#greymane">Greymane</a></td>
  <td><a href="#lt-morales">Lt. Morales</a></td>
  <td><a href="#tyrael">Tyrael</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#hanzo">Hanzo</a></td>
  <td><a href="#rehgar">Rehgar</a></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#malthael">Malthael</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#maiev">Maiev</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="assassin">Assassin</h3>

<h4 id="genji">Genji</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Dragonblade (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 240 to 220</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li>The Dragon Becomes Me (R)
<ul>
<li>Bonus duration decreased from .75 second to .5 seconds per Hero hit</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="greymane">Greymane</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Gilnean Cocktail (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 70 to 55</li>
<li>Explosion area increased by ~15%</li>
<li>Initial damage reduced from 59 to 55</li>
<li>Spread damage reduced from 236 to 220</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Razor Swipe (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 135 to 126</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p>​<strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Perfect Aim (Q)
<ul>
<li>Mana refund for hitting a Hero reduced from 50 to 35</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Draught Overflow (Q)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Wizened Duelist (Passive)
<ul>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Every 6 Attacks against an enemy Hero increases Greymane’s Basic Attack damage by 1%, up to 30%. Gain triple benefit from attacking in Worgen form. Half of these bonuses are lost on death.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> We made these changes in an effort to increase
  Greymane’s build diversity. Gilnean Cocktail felt a little lackluster without
  its associated Talents, so made parts of them baseline. While you can still
  enhance Gilnean Cocktail through talents, we wanted it to feel like a valuable
  part of your kit if you choose a more Basic Attack-oriented build. We've also
  redesigned Wizened Duelist to be less of a feast or famine Quest by shifting
  its requirements to something that a Greymane in a losing game can still
  accomplish. This also has the added benefit of being a reward that can be
  accomplished regardless of the lethality of a game (since the average number
  of deaths can vary greatly between different levels of play).</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="hanzo">Hanzo</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Never Outmatched (W)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduction reduced from 4 to 2.5 seconds per Basic Attack</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Sharpened Arrowheads (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Armor reduction reduced from 4 to 2
<ul>
<li>Maximum stacks increased from 5 to 10, so that the maximum negative Armor remains 20</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Armor reduction duration reduced from 4 to 3 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="malthael">Malthael</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Basic Attacks now cleave in a radius of 3.25 in an arc in front of Malthael</li>
<li>Damage reduced from 117 to 82 </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Soul Rip (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Healing reduced from 44 to 36 per enemy hit</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Death’s Shroud (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Width increased from 2.25 to 3</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Reaper's Mark (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 2% to 1.75% of an enemy's maximum Health</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Tormented Souls (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>No longer applies Armor to Malthael</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Last Rites (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 75 to 65 seconds</li>
<li>Malthael can now also gain Quest credit if the enemy Hero dies within 1.5 seconds of Last Rites damage</li>
<li>Range increased from 4 to 5</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Die Alone (Q)
<ul>
<li>This now once again applies bonus damage if only 1 Hero is marked, even if multiple other non-Heroes are also marked</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Throwing Shade (E)
<ul>
<li>Reduced the hits needed to complete the quest from 20 to 15</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Black Harvest (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Quest completion requirement increased from 150 to 180 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Massacre (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16 to Level 7</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Touch of Death (Active)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 30 to 25 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Soul Siphon (Q)
<ul>
<li>Reduced the healing from 4% to 3.75% versus Heroes</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Ethereal Existence (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Maximum Physical Armor reduced from 40 to 30</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mortality (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 7 to Level 16</li>
<li>Damage increased from 4 to 6% of an enemy Hero's maximum Health</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li>Reaper of Souls (R)
<ul>
<li>Bonus duration increased from 1 to 2 seconds.</li>
<li>Hero Takedowns will now reset the duration instead of increasing it by 4 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> Malthael, while powerful, has relied heavily on
  Tormented Souls to apply his Reaper's Mark during team fights. By making his
  Basic Attacks cleave and increasing the usability of Death's Shroud, we're
  providing more ways to him to apply his Mark to multiple enemies. Not only
  does this increase his survivability and damage without relying solely on
  Tormented Souls, it also gives him more options to use Wraith Strike. We've
  also sought to increase the usability of Last Rites to make it a more enticing
  Heroic option. Lastly, the ability to apply Reaper's Mark reliably makes it
  much more powerful, so we've adjusted the tuning of its damage and associated
  Talents.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="maiev">Maiev</h4>

<ul>
<li><strong>Abilities</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>​Vault of the Wardens (D)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Passive Armor bonus reduced from 15 to 10</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="support">Support</h3>

<h4 id="auriel">Auriel</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning"><strong>Bestow Hope (D)</strong></span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/heroesofthestorm/comments/7vobh3/heroes_of_the_storm_patch_notes_february_6_2018/dtv4nw7/" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Hope generation from damage dealt to Heroes reduced from 50 to 40%</span></li>
</ul></li>
<li><span class="text-warning"><strong>Sacred Sweep (Q)</strong></span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/heroesofthestorm/comments/7vobh3/heroes_of_the_storm_patch_notes_february_6_2018/dtv4nw7/" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Center damage to non-Heroes increased from 171 to 180</span></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="lt-morales">Lt. Morales</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Safeguard (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Can no longer be cast on non-Heroic targets</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="rehgar">Rehgar</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning"><strong>Level 13</strong></span>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Earthliving Enchant (Q)</span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://redd.it/7z9hlf" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Additional healing no longer scales with level</span></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="warrior">Warrior</h3>

<h4 id="sonya">Sonya</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Basic Attack damage increased from 84 to 88</span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/heroesofthestorm/comments/7vtv2o/sonya_poisoned_spear_unnerfed/dtwgiyo/" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning"><strong>Level 7</strong></span>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Poisoned Spear (Q)</span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/heroesofthestorm/comments/7vtv2o/sonya_poisoned_spear_unnerfed/dtwgiyo/" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Damage increased from 100% to 125% of Ancient Spear’s damage.</span></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><span class="text-warning"><strong>Level 16</strong></span>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Nerves of Steel (Active)</span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/heroesofthestorm/comments/7vtv2o/sonya_poisoned_spear_unnerfed/dtwgiyo/" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Duration increased from 3 to 5 seconds</span></li>
<li><span class="text-warning">Shield amount increased from 25% to 30% of Maximum Health</span></li>
<li><span class="text-warning">Cooldown increased from 60 to 70 seconds</span></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="tyrael">Tyrael</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Salvation (W)
<ul>
<li>Healing on shield destruction increased from 125 to 140</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Ardent Restoration (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Healing increased from 12.5 to 13.75 per stack over 5 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Stalwart Armor (Q)
<ul>
<li>Armor reduced from 25 to 20</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="collection">Collection</h3>

<p>Head over to the latest <a href="http://battle.net/heroes/blog/21464984">In-Development
blog</a> to catch a preview of all the
new cosmetic items coming to the Nexus with this patch.</p>

<p><strong><span class="text-warning">Hero Price Reduction</span></strong></p>

<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Gul'dan’s prices have been reduced to 7,000 Gold and 625 Gems.</span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://twitter.com/Adunaiii/status/964320328456556544" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Bundles</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Maiev Heroic Bundle – Available until February 19, 2018</li>
<li>Lunar Festival 2018 Bundle – Available until March 5, 2018</li>
<li>Lunar Festival Classic Bundle – Available until March 5, 2018</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Announcer</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Maiev</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Skins</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Maiev</strong>
<ul>
<li>Darnassian Maiev</li>
<li>Dusk Maiev</li>
<li><strong>Hellwarden Maiev</strong>
<ul>
<li>Bonewarden Maiev</li>
<li>Dreadwarden Maiev</li>
<li>Hordewarden Maiev</li>
<li>Plaguewarden Maiev</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Kael’thas</strong>
<ul>
<li>Lunar Kael’thas</li>
<li>Jade Lunar Kael’thas</li>
<li>Heavenly Lunar Kael’thas</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Sylvanas</strong>
<ul>
<li>Lunar Sylvanas</li>
<li>Jade Lunar Sylvanas</li>
<li>Soaring Lunar Sylvanas</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Cassia</strong>
<ul>
<li>Lunar Cassia</li>
<li>Azure Lunar Cassia</li>
<li>Honored Lunar Cassia</li>
<li>Jade Lunar Cassia</li>
<li>Midnight Lunar Cassia</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Zul’jin</strong>
<ul>
<li>Lunar Zul’jin</li>
<li>Ancestral Lunar Zul’jin</li>
<li>Cruel Lunar Zul’jin</li>
<li>Jade Lunar Zul’jin</li>
<li>Ornamented Lunar Zul’jin</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Arthas</strong>
<ul>
<li>Royal Mystic Kingdoms Arthas</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Azmodan</strong>
<ul>
<li>Lunar Azmodan</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Genji</strong>
<ul>
<li>Lunar Genji</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Illidan</strong>
<ul>
<li>Dragon Lunar Illidan</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Jaina</strong>
<ul>
<li>Jade Lunar Jaina</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Li-Ming</strong>
<ul>
<li>Blossom Lunar Li-Ming</li>
<li>Heavenly Lunar Li-Ming</li>
<li>Imperial Lunar Li-Ming</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Mounts</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Lunar Skyrocket</strong> – Unlocked by completing the Lunar Festival 2018 event quest.
<ul>
<li>Golden Lunar Skyrocket – Purchasable using Gold</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Lunar Guardian</strong>
<ul>
<li>Jade Lunar Guardian</li>
<li>Marble Lunar Guardian</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fixed a number of typo and tooltip errors across several aspects of the game.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Art</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Jaina:</strong> Corrected some minor clipping affecting Arcanist Jaina’s clothing.</li>
<li><strong>Samuro:</strong> Shadows will no longer appear to flicker behind Monkey King Samuro on the post-match score screen. </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Battlegrounds</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Battlefield of Eternity:</strong> Fixed a visual issue that could cause the outlines generated by Natural Agility to dip below the terrain in certain locations.</li>
<li><strong>Braxis Holdout:</strong> Fixed an issue in which A.I. Heroes would pace near an enemy Gate rather than attack the Core.</li>
<li><strong>Garden of Terror:</strong> Fixed an issue in which Structures affected by Overgrowth could stop attacking indefinitely under specific circumstances.</li>
<li><strong>Blackheart’s Revenge Brawl:</strong> Damage will no longer interrupt channeling while Heroes are attempting to use teleportation portals.</li>
<li><strong>Escape from Braxis Brawl:</strong> Bosses can no longer push unpathable terrain created by Tyrael’s Holy Ground Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Try Mode:</strong> The effects of Ana’s Aim Down the Sights Talent are now correctly removed after using the Reset Talents Button.</li>
<li><strong>Try Mode:</strong> Sgt. Hammer’s bonus attack range, granted by the Graduating Range Talent, is now correctly removed after using the Reset Talents Button.</li>
<li><strong>Volskaya Foundry:</strong> Fixed an issue that allowed Junkrat to permanently displace and leash Fortification Camps.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Ana:</strong> Shrike Doses after the first will now correctly deal bonus damage when Ana is affected by increased Spell Power.</li>
<li><strong>Auriel:</strong> Basic Attack damage dealt by Auriel’s Bestow Hope target will no longer generate less than the intended amount of Energy.</li>
<li><strong>D.Va:</strong> A.I. Heroes will now attempt to flee the area surrounding D.Va’s Mech during Self-Destruct.</li>
<li><strong>Junkrat:</strong> Will no longer become separated from his rocket when issuing movement commands during Rocket Ride.</li>
<li><strong>Li Li:</strong> Blinding Wind will now correctly deal damage to neutral Mercenaries.</li>
<li><strong>Li-Ming:</strong> The Astral Presence icon is no longer missing its mouseover tooltip.</li>
<li><strong>Lunara:</strong> Leaping Strike can no longer be cast while Rooted.</li>
<li><strong>Rehgar:</strong> Fixed an issue preventing the Hunger of the Wolf Talent from applying bonus damage to Ghost Wolf attacks at level 16.</li>
<li><strong>Tassadar:</strong> The Psionic Echo Talent’s timer bar will now correctly appear next to the Archon timer when both are active at once.</li>
<li><strong>Valeera:</strong> The Cheap Shot tooltip appended to Blade Flurry after breaking Stealth now correctly states it will Blind the target.</li>
<li><strong>Zeratul:</strong> Blink will now correctly break invisibility.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Sound</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Valeera:</strong> Thistle Tea activation is no longer audible to nearby enemies while Valeera is in Stealth.</li>
<li><strong>Settings:</strong> Hero voice reactions are no longer audible when the Voices setting is disabled.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>User Interface</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Hotkeys:</strong> Basic Hotkeys can now be assigned to mouse buttons.</li>
<li><strong>Loading Screen:</strong> Removed an outdated loading screen tooltip relating to Tower Ammunition.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-01-29 PTR Patch Notes</title>
    <published>2018-01-29T18:59:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-29T18:59:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-01-29-ptr-patch-notes.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-01-29-ptr-patch-notes.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-ptr-patch-notes-january-29-2018">Heroes of the Storm PTR Patch Notes - January 29, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1494956881/patchlogo2017-05-16.jpg"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21387327" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21387327" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.30.0</small></div>

<p>Our next Heroes of the Storm patch has just hit the Public Test Realm and will
be available for playtesting until February 5. During this time, we kindly
request your assistance in trying out the new content before we officially
release the patch. As always, if you encounter any bugs or other issues during
your PTR play sessions, please stop by the <a href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en/forum/20013840/">PTR Bug Report
forum</a> to let us know about
your experiences.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="lunar-festival-2018">Lunar Festival 2018</h3>

<p>Join us in celebrating Lunar Festival this year by completing matches in
Versus A.I., Quick Match, Unranked, or Ranked modes, and you’ll pick up some
sweet new loot! The event kicks off during the week of Tuesday, February 6,
and concludes on Monday, March 5, so be sure to complete the quests below
before Lunar Festival comes to an end.</p>

<p><strong>Quests and Rewards</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Part 1:</strong> Play 2 Games
<ul>
<li><strong>Reward:</strong> Cute Lunar Skyrocket Spray</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Part 2:</strong> Play 5 Games
<ul>
<li><strong>Reward:</strong> Lunar Warcrest Banner</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Part 3:</strong> Play 8 Games
<ul>
<li><strong>Reward:</strong> Cute Lunar Guardian Portrait</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Part 4:</strong> Win 5 Games
<ul>
<li><strong>Reward:</strong> Lunar Skyrocket Mount</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p>You can also stop by the <a href="http://battle.net/heroes/game/events/Lunar-festival-2018">Lunar Festival 2018 mini-
site</a> to learn more
about the event and find out how you can earn ornate Lunar Festival 2018 Loot
Chests just by playing Heroes of the Storm!</p>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="new-hero-maiev">New Hero: Maiev</h3>

<p>Maiev Shadowsong stood watch over the imprisoned Betrayer for ten thousand
years, and hunted him relentlessly after he was released. Some say she’s
determined; others say she’s obsessed. Either way, she will stop at nothing to
ensure the security of her world.</p>

<p><strong>Trait</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Vault of the Wardens (D)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Leap into the air, becoming immune to all hostile effects for 0.75 seconds.</li>
<li>Passive: Maiev has 15 Armor.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Basic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Fan of Knives (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Deal 180 damage to enemies in a crescent area.</li>
<li>Hitting at least 2 enemy Heroes with Fan of Knives reduces its cooldown to 0.5 seconds, and refunds the Mana cost.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Umbral Bind (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Maiev’s next Basic Attack cleaves and applies a tether to enemy Heroes hit for 2.5 seconds. If a tethered Hero moves too far from Maiev, they are pulled toward her, dealing 110 damage and breaking the tether.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Spirit of Vengeance (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Send a shadow of Maiev outward that will return to its cast location, dealing 100 damage to enemies along both paths. Deals 100% more damage to enemy Heroes.</li>
<li>Reactivate to Blink to the shadow’s location.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Containment Disc (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Throw a glaive in the target direction. If an enemy Hero is hit, Containment Disk can be reactivated to remove their vision and Time Stop them for 4 seconds.</li>
<li>Containment Disc automatically activates 6 seconds after hitting a Hero.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Warden's Cage (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Summon 8 Warden Avatars as a cage around Maiev. After 1.5 seconds, enemy Heroes that come in contact with an Avatar re knocked to the center of the cage, and that Avatar is consumed. Warden Avatars last 7 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="user-interface">User Interface</h3>

<p><strong>Voice Chat</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>NOTE: While available in the PTR, Voice Chat will not be enabled on the live servers until a later date.</strong></li>
<li>Voice chat for Parties and Teams has been introduced to Heroes of the Storm.
<ul>
<li>By default, players will automatically join Party voice chat.</li>
<li>Team voice chat is opt-in, but can be toggled to auto-join in the Voice Chat settings. There is a team voice reminder dialog at the beginning of matches that is enabled by default, but can be disabled.</li>
<li>If Team voice auto-join is enabled and you are already in party voice, a confirmation dialog will appear that defaults to Join.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Voice settings can be adjusted in the Voice Chat tab of the Options menu.
<ul>
<li>A voice chat widget is also available in the top left of most screens. This widget lets you quickly change channels or join/leave voice channels.
<ul>
<li>This can be found in the Tab screen while in a match.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Microphone and speaker icons can be clicked on to mute/unmute.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Target Info Panel</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Target Info Panels have been introduced to allow players to investigate a unit's gameplay stats in real time.
<ul>
<li>The Target Info Panel will display in the top left of the screen after selecting a friendly or enemy target with left-click.
<ul>
<li>​The Target Info Panel can be repositioned by clicking and dragging to your desired location.
<ul>
<li>​Double-clicking the info panel will reset it to the default position.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>The Target Info Panel will display the following information:
<ul>
<li>Health &amp; Health Regen</li>
<li>Mana &amp; Mana Regen</li>
<li>Basic Attack Damage</li>
<li>Attacks per Second</li>
<li>Attack Range</li>
<li>Spell Power Modifier</li>
<li>Movement Speed</li>
<li>Physical &amp; Spell Armor</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Battleground Objective Counters</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>All Battlegrounds with turn-in mechanics (Blackheart’s Bay, Tomb of the Spider Queen, Booty Coffers Heroes Brawl) will now show a visual indicator when a team’s gathered objective count is high enough to complete a turn-in.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="art">Art</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Pings:</strong> Ping icons that appear overhead have received updated visual effects.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Abathur:</strong> A crown icon will now appear above Heroes’ Minimap portraits when they are affected by Abathur’s Symbiote.</li>
<li><strong>Ana:</strong> An overlay will now display for Heroes affected by Nano Boost.</li>
<li><strong>Archangel Diablo:</strong> Apocalypse visual effects that appear on the terrain have been updated to make them more obvious to players on both teams.</li>
<li><strong>Falstad:</strong> Hinterland Blast visual effects now more closely match the edges of its area of effect.</li>
<li><strong>Junkrat:</strong> Frag Launcher’s targeting reticle has received updated art.</li>
<li><strong>Leoric:</strong> Entomb’s targeting reticle has received updated art to better reflect the Ability’s shape.</li>
<li><strong>Li-Ming:</strong> Magic Missiles have received updated visual effects to make them more apparent.</li>
<li><strong>Lt. Morales:</strong> An overlay will now display for Heroes affected by Stim Drone.</li>
<li><strong>Tychus:</strong> Minigun visual effects have been updated to make the Ability more apparent while it is active.</li>
<li><strong>Tychus:</strong> Overkill’s retargeting icon has received updated art.</li>
<li>The following heroes have received updated visual effects to coincide with Talent changes:
<ul>
<li>Greymane</li>
<li>Malthael</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="battlegrounds">Battlegrounds</h3>

<p><strong>Ranked Battleground Rotation</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Battleground rotation for Ranked Play is unchanged, and remains as follows:
<ul>
<li>Battlefield of Eternity</li>
<li>Braxis Holdout</li>
<li>Cursed Hollow</li>
<li>Dragon Shire</li>
<li>Infernal Shrines</li>
<li>Sky Temple</li>
<li>Tomb of the Spider Queen</li>
<li>Towers of Doom</li>
<li>Volskaya Foundry</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Volskaya Foundry</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Triglav Protector</strong>
<ul>
<li>The Protector will gain 10 Armor and 25% increased damage if both the Pilot and Gunner seats are occupied</li>
<li>Base Health has been increased from 9500 to 10450</li>
<li>Health Scaling has been increased by 10%</li>
<li><strong>Pilot: Rocket Fist (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Duration of structure debuff effect has been increased from 2 to 4 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Gunner: Gatling Cannon (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Gatling Cannon will now fire immediately, instead of after a short delay</li>
<li>Gatling Cannon rounds will now travel 50% faster</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="heroes">Heroes</h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><a href="#assassin">Assassin</a></th>
  <th><a href="#warrior">Warrior</a></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#greymane">Greymane</a></td>
  <td><a href="#tyrael">Tyrael</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#malthael">Malthael</a></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="assassin">Assassin</h3>

<h4 id="greymane">Greymane</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Gilnean Cocktail (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 70 to 55</li>
<li>Explosion area increased by ~15%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p>​<strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Perfect Aim (Q)
<ul>
<li>Mana refund for hitting a Hero reduced from 50 to 35</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Draught Overflow (Q)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Wizened Duelist (Passive)
<ul>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Every 6 Attacks against an enemy Hero increases Greymane’s Basic Attack damage by 1%, up to 30%. Gain triple benefit from attacking in Worgen form. Half of these bonuses are lost on death.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> We made these changes in an effort to increase
  Greymane’s build diversity. Gilnean Cocktail felt a little lackluster without
  its associated Talents, so made parts of them baseline. While you can still
  enhance Gilnean Cocktail through talents, we wanted it to feel like a valuable
  part of your kit if you choose a more Basic Attack-oriented build. We've also
  redesigned Wizened Duelist to be less of a feast or famine Quest by shifting
  its requirements to something that a Greymane in a losing game can still
  accomplish. This also has the added benefit of being a reward that can be
  accomplished regardless of the lethality of a game (since the average number
  of deaths can vary greatly between different levels of play).</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="malthael">Malthael</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Basic Attacks now cleave in a radius of 3.25 in an arc in front of Malthael</li>
<li>Damage reduced from 117 to 82 </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Soul Rip (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Healing reduced from 44 to 36 per enemy hit</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Death’s Shroud (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Width increased from 2.25 to 3</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Reaper's Mark (Trait)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 2% to 1.75% of an enemy's maximum Health</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Tormented Souls (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>No longer applies Armor to Malthael</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Last Rites (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 75 to 65 seconds</li>
<li>Malthael can now also gain Quest credit if the enemy Hero dies within 1.5 seconds of Last Rites damage</li>
<li>Range increased from 4 to 5</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Die Alone (Q)
<ul>
<li>This now once again applies bonus damage if only 1 Hero is marked, even if multiple other non-Heroes are also marked</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Throwing Shade (E)
<ul>
<li>Reduced the hits needed to complete the quest from 20 to 15</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Black Harvest (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Quest completion requirement increased from 150 to 180 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Massacre (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16 to Level 7</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Touch of Death (Active)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 30 to 25 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Soul Siphon (Q)
<ul>
<li>Reduced the healing from 4% to 3.75% versus Heroes</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Ethereal Existence (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Maximum Physical Armor reduced from 40 to 30</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mortality (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 7 to Level 16</li>
<li>Damage increased from 4 to 6% of an enemy Hero's maximum Health</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> Malthael, while powerful, has relied heavily on
  Tormented Souls to apply his Reaper's Mark during team fights. By making his
  Basic Attacks cleave and increasing the usability of Death's Shroud, we're
  providing more ways to him to apply his Mark to multiple enemies. Not only
  does this increase his survivability and damage without relying solely on
  Tormented Souls, it also gives him more options to use Wraith Strike. We've
  also sought to increase the usability of Last Rites to make it a more enticing
  Heroic option. Lastly, the ability to apply Reaper's Mark reliably makes it
  much more powerful, so we've adjusted the tuning of its damage and associated
  Talents.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="warrior">Warrior</h3>

<h4 id="tyrael">Tyrael</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Salvation (W)
<ul>
<li>Healing on shield destruction increased from 125 to 140</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Ardent Restoration (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Healing increased from 12.5 to 13.75 per stack over 5 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Stalwart Armor (Q)
<ul>
<li>Armor reduced from 25 to 20</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="collection">Collection</h3>

<p>Head over to the latest <a href="http://battle.net/heroes/blog/21464984">In-Development
blog</a> to catch a preview of all the
new cosmetic items coming to the Nexus with this patch.</p>

<p><strong>New Bundles</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Maiev Heroic Bundle – Available until February 19, 2018</li>
<li>Lunar Festival 2018 Bundle – Available until March 5, 2018</li>
<li>Lunar Festival Classic Bundle – Available until March 5, 2018</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Announcer</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Maiev</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Skins</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Maiev</strong>
<ul>
<li>Darnassian Maiev</li>
<li>Dusk Maiev</li>
<li><strong>Hellwarden Maiev</strong>
<ul>
<li>Bonewarden Maiev</li>
<li>Dreadwarden Maiev</li>
<li>Hordewarden Maiev</li>
<li>Plaguewarden Maiev</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Kael’thas</strong>
<ul>
<li>Lunar Kael’thas</li>
<li>Jade Lunar Kael’thas</li>
<li>Heavenly Lunar Kael’thas</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Sylvanas</strong>
<ul>
<li>Lunar Sylvanas</li>
<li>Jade Lunar Sylvanas</li>
<li>Soaring Lunar Sylvanas</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Cassia</strong>
<ul>
<li>Lunar Cassia</li>
<li>Azure Lunar Cassia</li>
<li>Honored Lunar Cassia</li>
<li>Jade Lunar Cassia</li>
<li>Midnight Lunar Cassia</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Zul’jin</strong>
<ul>
<li>Lunar Zul’jin</li>
<li>Ancestral Lunar Zul’jin</li>
<li>Cruel Lunar Zul’jin</li>
<li>Jade Lunar Zul’jin</li>
<li>Ornamented Lunar Zul’jin</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Arthas</strong>
<ul>
<li>Royal Mystic Kingdoms Arthas</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Azmodan</strong>
<ul>
<li>Lunar Azmodan</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Genji</strong>
<ul>
<li>Lunar Genji</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Illidan</strong>
<ul>
<li>Dragon Lunar Illidan</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Jaina</strong>
<ul>
<li>Jade Lunar Jaina</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Li-Ming</strong>
<ul>
<li>Blossom Lunar Li-Ming</li>
<li>Heavenly Lunar Li-Ming</li>
<li>Imperial Lunar Li-Ming</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Mounts</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Lunar Skyrocket</strong> – Unlocked by completing the Lunar Festival 2018 event quest.
<ul>
<li>Golden Lunar Skyrocket – Purchasable using Gold</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Lunar Guardian</strong>
<ul>
<li>Jade Lunar Guardian</li>
<li>Marble Lunar Guardian</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fixed a number of typo and tooltip errors across several aspects of the game.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Art</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Jaina:</strong> Corrected some minor clipping affecting Arcanist Jaina’s clothing.</li>
<li><strong>Samuro:</strong> Shadows will no longer appear to flicker behind Monkey King Samuro on the post-match score screen. </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Battlegrounds</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Battlefield of Eternity:</strong> Fixed a visual issue that could cause the outlines generated by Natural Agility to dip below the terrain in certain locations.</li>
<li><strong>Braxis Holdout:</strong> Fixed an issue in which A.I. Heroes would pace near an enemy Gate rather than attack the Core.</li>
<li><strong>Garden of Terror:</strong> Fixed an issue in which Structures affected by Overgrowth could stop attacking indefinitely under specific circumstances.</li>
<li><strong>Blackheart’s Revenge Brawl:</strong> Damage will no longer interrupt channeling while Heroes are attempting to use teleportation portals.</li>
<li><strong>Escape from Braxis Brawl:</strong> Bosses can no longer push unpathable terrain created by Tyrael’s Holy Ground Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Try Mode:</strong> The effects of Ana’s Aim Down the Sights Talent are now correctly removed after using the Reset Talents Button.</li>
<li><strong>Try Mode:</strong> Sgt. Hammer’s bonus attack range, granted by the Graduating Range Talent, is now correctly removed after using the Reset Talents Button.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Ana:</strong> Shrike Doses after the first will now correctly deal bonus damage when Ana is affected by increased Spell Power.</li>
<li><strong>Auriel:</strong> Basic Attack damage dealt by Auriel’s Bestow Hope target will no longer generate less than the intended amount of Energy.</li>
<li><strong>D.Va:</strong> A.I. Heroes will now attempt to flee the area surrounding D.Va’s Mech during Self-Destruct.</li>
<li><strong>Junkrat:</strong> Will no longer become separated from his rocket when issuing movement commands during Rocket Ride.</li>
<li><strong>Li Li:</strong> Blinding Wind will now correctly deal damage to neutral Mercenaries.</li>
<li><strong>Li-Ming:</strong> The Astral Presence icon is no longer missing its mouseover tooltip.</li>
<li><strong>Lunara:</strong> Leaping Strike can no longer be cast while Rooted.</li>
<li><strong>Rehgar:</strong> Fixed an issue preventing the Hunger of the Wolf Talent from applying bonus damage to Ghost Wolf attacks at level 16.</li>
<li><strong>Tassadar:</strong> The Psionic Echo Talent’s timer bar will now correctly appear next to the Archon timer when both are active at once.</li>
<li><strong>Valeera:</strong> The Cheap Shot tooltip appended to Blade Flurry after breaking Stealth now correctly states it will Blind the target.</li>
<li><strong>Zeratul:</strong> Blink will now correctly break invisibility.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Sound</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Valeera:</strong> Thistle Tea activation is no longer audible to nearby enemies while Valeera is in Stealth.</li>
<li><strong>Settings:</strong> Hero voice reactions are no longer audible when the Voices setting is disabled.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>User Interface</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Hotkeys:</strong> Basic Hotkeys can now be assigned to mouse buttons.</li>
<li><strong>Loading Screen:</strong> Removed an outdated loading screen tooltip relating to Tower Ammunition.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-01-24 Balance Update</title>
    <published>2018-01-24T18:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-24T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-01-24-balance-update.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-01-24-balance-update.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-patch-notes-january-24-2018">Heroes of the Storm Patch Notes - January 24, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1485586192/balanceupdate.png"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21464985" target="_blank"></a><a href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21464985" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.29.9</small></div>

<p>We’ve just released a patch to the live servers in order to apply some balance
updates and bug fixes.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="heroes">Heroes</h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><a href="#assassin">Assassin</a></th>
  <th><a href="#specialist">Specialist</a></th>
  <th><a href="#support">Support</a></th>
  <th><a href="#warrior">Warrior</a></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#hanzo">Hanzo</a></td>
  <td><a href="#sgt-hammer">Sgt. Hammer</a></td>
  <td><a href="#brightwing">Brightwing</a></td>
  <td><a href="#blaze">Blaze</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#valeera">Valeera</a></td>
  <td><a href="#sylvanas">Sylvanas</a></td>
  <td><a href="#tyrande">Tyrande</a></td>
  <td><a href="#sonya">Sonya</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td></td>
  <td><a href="#xul">Xul</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<hr />

<h3 id="assassin">Assassin</h3>

<h4 id="hanzo">Hanzo</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Basic Attack Damage reduced from 176 to 173</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Storm Bow (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 297 to 291</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Scatter Arrow (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Ricochet damage reduced from 90 to 88</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Sharpened Arrowheads (W)
<ul>
<li>Decreased Armor reduction from 5 (to a maximum of 25) to 4 (to a maximum of 20)</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="valeera">Valeera</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Ambush (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Armor reduction duration increased from 4 to 5 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Vigor (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Passive energy regeneration increased from 2 to 2.5 per second.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Combat Readiness (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Physical Armor increased from 60 to 75</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Relentless Strikes (Q)
<ul>
<li>Sinister Strike energy reduction increased from 10 to 15</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mutilate (Q)
<ul>
<li>Damage bonus increased from 100% to 125%</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Fatal Finesse (W)
<ul>
<li>Damage gained per enemy Hero hit increased from 3 (to a maximum of 60) to 4 (to a maximum of 80)</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Blind (W)
<ul>
<li>Bonus blind duration increased from 2 to 2.5 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li>Adrenaline Rush (R)
<ul>
<li>Energy regeneration increased from 30 to 40 per second</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="specialist">Specialist</h3>

<h4 id="sgt-hammer">Sgt. Hammer</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Regenerative Bio-Steel (D)
<ul>
<li>Healing reduced from 15% to 10% of Sgt. Hammer’s Basic Attack damage dealt in Siege Mode.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Graduating Range (D)
<ul>
<li>Range reduced from 1.1 to 1 per stack, up to a maximum of 3</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="sylvanas">Sylvanas</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Base Maximum Health reduced from 1456 to 1425</li>
<li>Health Regen reduced from 3.04 to 2.97</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Shadow Dagger (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 10 to 11 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Lost Soul (W)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduction per Hero hit reduced from 1.25 to 1 second</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="xul">Xul</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Grim Scythe (Q)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduction per enemy hit increased from .75 to 1 second</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Jailors (E)
<ul>
<li>Bonus Attack and Movement Speed reduced from 50 to 40%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Harvest Vitality (W)
<ul>
<li>Heal increased from 60 to 70%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="support">Support</h3>

<h4 id="brightwing">Brightwing</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Base Maximum Health increased from 1395 to 1450</li>
<li>Health Regen increased from 2.91 to 3.02</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="tyrande">Tyrande</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Basic Attack Damage increased from 80 to 82</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="warrior">Warrior</h3>

<h4 id="blaze">Blaze</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Fortified Bunker (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Health increased from 1305 to 1435</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Combustion (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>There is now a .5 second window after casting where Combustion cannot be canceled (this is to prevent accidental canceling from rapid key presses)</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Feeding the Flame (Q)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduction increased from 1.5 to 2 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Incinerator Gauntlets (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Bonus damage increased from 50% to 70%</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Crossfire (Q)
<ul>
<li>Damage increased from 132 to 139</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Grill and Kill (W)
<ul>
<li>Damage bonus decreased from 25% to 20%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Suppressive Fire (Q) <a class="label label-warning" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-01-24-balance-update.html" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li>Spell Power reduction increased from 15% <span class="text-warning">(max 30%)</span> to 20% <span class="text-warning">(max 40%)</span> </li>
</ul></li>
<li>Nanomachine Coating (W)
<ul>
<li>Attack Speed slow now also applies to Oil Spills that are on fire</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Juggernaut Plating (Active)
<ul>
<li>Shield bonus increased from 100% to 125% of damage reduced</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="sonya">Sonya</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Basic Attack damage reduced from 88 to 84</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Poisoned Spear (Q)
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 125% to 100% of Ancient Spear’s damage.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Nerves of Steel (Active)
<ul>
<li>Duration reduced from 5 to 3 seconds</li>
<li>Shield amount reduced from 30% to 25% of Maximum Health</li>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 70 to 60 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fixed a number of inaccuracies and grammatical issues in tooltips across the game.</li>
<li><strong>Korean Client:</strong> Updated the loading screen to the Korean localized version.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> Fixed an issue that allowed Heroes to bypass the movement speed reduction from ignited Oil Spills if Blaze chose the Adhesive Petroleum talent.</li>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> Fixed an issue causing Stimpack and Pyromania voiceover lines to be heard globally.</li>
<li><strong>Tyrael:</strong> Fixed an issue preventing Tyrael from gaining stacks of Ardent Restoration from the damage dealt by the Burning Halo talent.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-01-16 Patch Notes</title>
    <published>2018-01-16T23:58:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-16T23:58:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-01-16-patch-notes.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-01-16-patch-notes.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-patch-notes-january-16-2018">HEROES OF THE STORM PATCH NOTES — JANUARY 16, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1494956881/patchlogo2017-05-16.jpg"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21349578" target="_blank"></a><a href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21349578" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.29.8</small></div>

<p>Our most recent Heroes of the Storm patch has arrived featuring significant
changes to Tyrael and a number of bug fixes.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="warrior">Warrior</h3>

<h4 id="tyrael">Tyrael</h4>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Tyrael will now face the target of his Basic Attack after attacking. This is a visual change, and does not directly affect gameplay</li>
<li>Passive Spell Armor has been removed</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Base Maximum Health increased from 2296 to 2468</li>
<li>Health Regeneration increased from 4.78 to 5.14</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>El’druin’s Might (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 50 to 45</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Righteousness (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 60 to 50</li>
<li>Allied Shield amount changed from a flat value to 40% of the Tyrael-only Shield value.
<ul>
<li>This is the same amount of Shields, but it makes it easier to understand new Talent interactions</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Smite (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Can now be cast while moving</li>
<li>Damage increased from 144 to 150</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Salvation (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 16</li>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Increase Righteousness’ Tyrael-only Shield amount by 25%. If the Shield is destroyed, heal Tyrael for 125 Health.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>(New) Justice for All (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Increases Righteousness’ allied shield value to 100% of the Tyrael-only Shield amount.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>(New) Ardent Restoration (Passive)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damaging an enemy Hero grants 2.5 Health per Second to Tyrael for 5 seconds. Stacks up to 10 times.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Protection in Death (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Even in Death (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Regeneration Master (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>(New) Stalwart Angel (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Tyrael gains 25 Armor while El'druin's Might is out, and for 3 seconds after teleporting.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>(New) Bound by Law (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Increases El’druin’s Might’s slow amount from 25 to 35%. Tyrael’s Basic Attacks increase the duration of the slow by 1 second, up to 4 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>(New) Divine Vigor (Passive)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damaging an enemy with Smite causes Tyrael's Basic Attacks to heal him for 50% of their damage for 4 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Vigorous Strike (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Purge Evil (E)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 1</li>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Every enemy Hero hit by Smite increases Tyrael's Basic Attack damage by 30% for 4 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Swift Retribution (E)
<ul>
<li>Movement Speed bonus increased from 10 to 20%</li>
<li>No longer increases the duration of Smite’s Movement Speed bonus</li>
<li>Added functionality:
<ul>
<li>Now also causes Smite’s friendly effect to increase Attack Speed by 25%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Angel’s Grace (Q)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Zealotry (W)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Follow Through (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Sword of Justice (Q)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 16</li>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Can teleport with El'druin's Might twice, returning to Tyrael’s original position.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Holy Ground (Q)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 16</li>
<li>Duration reduced from 4 to 3 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>(New) Law and Order (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Reduce the cooldown of Righteousness by 1 second for each enemy Hero hit by Smite. Righteousness increases the damage of your next Smite by 25% for each ally affected.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Burning Rage (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Angelic Absorption (W)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Angelic Might (E)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>(New) Burning Halo (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>El'druin and Tyrael deal 15 damage per second to nearby enemies. This damage is increased by 100% for Tyrael for 3 seconds after teleporting to El’Druin.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Horadric Reforging (Q)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 4</li>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Basic Attacks reduce the cooldown of El'druin's Might by 1.5 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>(New) Smite the Wicked (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Smite’s cooldown recharges 100% faster while El'druin is out and for 3 seconds after teleporting to El’Druin</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Blood for Blood (Active)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li><span class="text-warning">Blade of Justice (Q)</span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-01-16-patch-notes.html" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Removed</span></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>(New) Defense of the Angels (Active)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Activate to reduce all incoming damage by 40% for 5 seconds. Any time Tyrael or an ally shielded by Righteousness take damage, reduce the cooldown by 3 seconds. 120 second cooldown</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>(New) Seal of El’druin (Passive)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Every time Tyrael casts a Basic Ability, increase his Attack Speed by 50% for 3 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Nullification Shield (Active)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Nexus Blades (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> Fixed an issue allowing players to cast Flame Stream while dead if they entered a Bunker while dying.</li>
<li><strong>Blaze:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Heroes to enter permanent Stasis if they were killed just as they entered a Bunker.</li>
<li><strong>Hanzo &amp; Leoric:</strong> Fixed an issue causing Towers to spawn if Leoric was directly impacted by Sonic Arrow.</li>
<li><strong>Malfurion &amp; Stitches:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Heroes to become unplayable if Nature’s Cure was cast while they were affected by Stitches’ Gorge.</li>
<li><strong>Malfurion &amp; Zagara:</strong> Nature’s Cure can no longer cleanse Heroes of the Devouring Maw effect.</li>
<li><strong>Uther:</strong> The Well Met talent will no longer affect non-Heroic units.</li>
<li><strong>Valeera:</strong> The Strangle talent will no longer affect non-Heroic units.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-01-09 Patch Notes</title>
    <published>2018-01-09T18:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-09T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-01-09-patch-notes.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-01-09-patch-notes.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-patch-notes-january-9-2018">Heroes of the Storm Patch Notes — January 9, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1494956881/patchlogo2017-05-16.jpg"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21349574" target="_blank"></a><a href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21349574" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.29.7</small></div>

<p>Our next Heroes of the Storm patch has just arrived along with Blaze, Veteran
Firebat.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="new-hero-blaze">New Hero: Blaze</h3>

<p>Cpl. Miles "Blaze" Lewis has always been drawn to the flame, but it wasn't
until he joined up with Raynor's Raiders that he put his pyromania to good
use. He's seen his fair share of battles since then, and has never failed to
bring the heat.</p>

<p><strong>Trait</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Pyromania</strong>
<ul>
<li>Gain 25 Armor and deal 40 damage to nearby enemies every 0.5 seconds for 4 seconds. Each Hero hit by Flame Stream reduces Pyromania's cooldown by 5 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Basic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Flame Stream (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Fire two streams of flame that deal 83 damage to enemies hit. Flame Stream sets fire to Oil Spills it comes in contact with.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Oil Spill (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Vector Targeting. </li>
<li>Dispense a slick of oil that lasts for 5 seconds and Slows enemies that come in contact with it by 40%. Flame Stream can set Oil Spills on fire for 2.5 seconds, dealing 18 damage every 0.3 seconds to enemies inside. While on fire, Oil Spills no longer Slow enemies. Additionally, Blaze is Healed for 49 Health every 0.3 seconds while standing in flaming Oil Spills. Stores up to 2 charges.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Jet Propulsion (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>After 0.5 seconds, charge forward, colliding with the first enemy Hero hit, dealing 52 damage to them and nearby enemy Heroes. Enemies hit are also Stunned for 1.25 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Bunker Drop (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>After 0.5 seconds, deploy and enter a Bunker with 1300 Health. Blaze and his allies can enter and exit the Bunker at will. While in the Bunker, occupants gain access to Flamethrower, dealing 179 damage to enemies in a line. Exiting the Bunker grants 25 Armor for 2 seconds. Bunkers last 10 seconds, or until destroyed.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Combustion (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Channel up to 2.6 seconds. Once Channeling ends, nearby enemies are Slowed by 60% and take 48 damage every 0.5 seconds. Combustion's Slow and damage over time durations are extended the longer Blaze Channels, from 1 second up to 5 seconds. Blaze's Movement Speed is reduced by 50% while Channeling.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="art">Art</h3>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Malfurion has received updated visual effects to coincide with Talent changes.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="battlegrounds">Battlegrounds</h3>

<p><strong>Regeneration Globes</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Total Health regen over 5 seconds reduced from 11.7% Maximum Health to 9%</li>
<li>Total Mana regen over 5 seconds reduced from 7.8% Maximum Mana to 7%</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Mercenaries</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Hellbats</strong>
<ul>
<li>Defender
<ul>
<li>Armor Shred amount reduced from 5 to 4% per stack</li>
<li>Base Health reduced from 4275 to 3420</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Laner
<ul>
<li>Armor Shred amount reduced from 5 to 4% per stack</li>
<li>Base Health reduced from 4700 to 3760
<ul>
<li>Health Scaling (Minutes 1-5) reduced from 50 to 40</li>
<li>Health Scaling (Minutes 6-10) increased from 75 to 110</li>
<li>Health Scaling (Minutes 11 -15) increased from 100 to 150</li>
<li>Health Scaling (Minutes 16-20) increased from 125 to 235</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Knights</strong>
<ul>
<li>Defender Mage Knight
<ul>
<li>Spell Armor Aura amount increased from 15 to 20</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Laner Mage Knight
<ul>
<li>Spell Armor Aura amount reduced from 30 to 20</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Slime Boss (Warhead Junction)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Laner
<ul>
<li>Base Health amount reduced from 20000 to 16000
<ul>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 1-5) reduced from 630 to 500</li>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 6-10) increased from 945 to 1050</li>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 11 -15) increased from 1260 to 1400</li>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 16-20) increased from 1575 to 2250</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Base Basic Attack damage reduced from 400 to 320
<ul>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 1-5) reduced from 10 to 8</li>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 6-10) increased from 15 to 17</li>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 11 -15) increased from 20 to 23</li>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 16-20) increased from 25 to 38</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Base Spit impact damage reduced from 250 to 200
<ul>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 6-10) increased from 5 to 6.25%</li>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 11 -15) increased from 6 to 7.25%</li>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 16-20) increased from 6 to 8.25%</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Base Spit ‘Damage over Time’ damage reduced from 150 to 120
<ul>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 6-10) increased from 5 to 6.25%</li>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 11 -15) increased from 6 to 7.25%</li>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 16-20) increased from 6 to 8.25%</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Acid Trail Base damage reduced from 80 to 64
<ul>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 6-10) increased from 5 to 6.25%</li>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 11 -15) increased from 6 to 7.25%</li>
<li>Scaling (Minutes 16-20) increased from 6 to 8.25%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Forts</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Gate Tower Damage to Minions, Mercenaries, Monsters, and Heroes increased by 33%.</li>
<li>Fort Damage to Minions, Mercenaries, Monsters, and Heroes increased by 33%</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Keeps</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Gate Tower Damage to Minions, Mercenaries, Monsters, and Heroes increased by 33%</li>
<li>Keep Damage to Minions, Mercenaries, Monsters, and Heroes increased by 33%</li>
<li>Keep Health increased from 16,000 to 17,000</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Towers of Doom</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Altar respawn time increased from 90 to 110 seconds.</li>
</ul>

<p>​<strong>Battlefield of Eternity</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The initial stage of the first event will always be South vs North (Heaven South, Hell North)</li>
<li>The second stage of the first event will always be East vs West (Heaven East, Hell West)
<ul>
<li>All subsequent event stages will be randomized</li>
</ul></li>
<li>The Minimap will now indicate upcoming Immortal spawn locations 30 seconds after the game begins.
<ul>
<li>Subsequent Immortal indicators will appear on the Minimap shortly after a previously summoned Immortal has been defeated.</li>
<li>Swap locations will not appear on the Minimap when an Immortal has been reduced to 50% Health.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> As expected, our gameplay update for 2018 resulted in
  large changes to many of our game systems. While we’re overall happy with the
  direction of the update, there have been some unintended side effects that
  we’re hoping to remedy. We overestimated how much more powerful unlimited ammo
  would be for Structures, and as a result pushing mechanics have become too
  strong, resulting in lower game times on nearly all maps. We’re giving our
  towers some of their teeth back with this update, which should help teams hold
  pushes from Mercenary Camps and map events. We’re also making some tuning
  changes to some of our Mercenary Camps now that we have had some time to see
  how they have been performing. Hellbats and Knights in particular are pushing
  harder than we would like, so we’re reducing their power. We’re also taking a
  look at the Warhead Junction boss and reducing its early and mid-game pushing
  power, as right now it is too strong when combined with Nukes from the map
  event. Lastly, we are reducing the power of Regeneration Globes. While we like
  the new mini-game that Neutral Regen globes provide in the laning phase, we
  are not comfortable with how much they are currently benefitting the team that
  is ahead while they are pushing into a defending team. We’re also seeing
  players picking up more Regeneration Globes in general, so this will help to
  keep the game’s overall sustain in check. These are some hefty changes, and
  it’s likely that there will be more needed to be done over time as things
  continue to settle. We’ll be keeping an eye on things, and are prepared to
  make more updates as they’re needed.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>​<strong>Heroes Brawl</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Dodge Brawl</strong>
<ul>
<li>Chromie’s Health has been increased from 3 to 5</li>
<li>Ghost Chromies now display player names overhead</li>
<li>The in-game camera will now lock to Ghost Chromie until a new round begins</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Ranked Battleground Rotation</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Removed</strong>
<ul>
<li>​Warhead Junction</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>​Added</strong>
<ul>
<li>​Volskaya Foundry</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="heroes">Heroes</h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><a href="#assassin">Assassin</a></th>
  <th><a href="#support">Support</a></th>
  <th><a href="#warrior">Warrior</a></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#hanzo">Hanzo</a></td>
  <td><a href="#malfurion">Malfurion</a></td>
  <td><a href="#blaze">Blaze</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#nova">Nova</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td><a href="#garrosh">Garrosh</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#samuro">Samuro</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td><a href="#johanna">Johanna</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#valeera">Valeera</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#zeratul">Zeratul</a></td>
  <td></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<hr />

<h3 id="assassin">Assassin</h3>

<h4 id="hanzo">Hanzo</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Scatter Arrow (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Spread of Scatter Arrows narrowed by 20%</li>
<li>Damage reduced from 93 to 90</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Natural Agility (D)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 25 to 20 seconds</li>
<li>Range increased from 8 to 10</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shieldbreaker (Q)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Sharpened Arrowheads (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from level 20</li>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Hitting a Hero with Storm Bow or Basic Attacks reduces their Armor by 5 for 4 seconds, stacking up to 25.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mounted Archery (Z)
<ul>
<li>Bonus Movement Speed reduced from 30 to 20%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Giant Slayer (W)
<ul>
<li>Damage increased from 1.25 to 1.5% of enemy Hero’s Health</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>(New) Perfect Agility (D)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Gain a second charge of Natural Agility, and reduce the cooldown by 5 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> We’re reducing the spread of Scatter Arrows so that
  they’re more effective when opponents aren’t directly next to a wall, while
  also reducing the damage slightly to compensate. We’ve increased the range of
  Natural Agility so that it will jump over a wider variety of terrain. We’ve
  also removed Shieldbreaker because we found that it required a very specific
  set of circumstances to be effective, but it was extremely powerful in those
  rare situations. We’ve moved Sharpened Arrowheads to replace it while changing
  its functionality to be more consistent in all situations.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="nova">Nova</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Snipe (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 245 to 230</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Pinning Shot (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 105 to 100</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Precision Strike (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Damage reduced from 456 to 435</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Precision Sniper (Trait)</strong> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-01-09-patch-notes.html" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li>Damage per stack increased from 5 to 6%</li>
<li><span class="text-warning">Maximum stacks increased from 25 to 30%</span></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Perfect Shot (Q)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown refund for hitting Heroes increased from 2 to 3 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li>One in the Chamber (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Damage bonus reduced from 70 to 60%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Lethal Decoy (E)
<ul>
<li>Clone damage reduced from 40 to 35%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> It’s nice to see that the recent changes to Nova have
  been so widely embraced by players. However, with the addition of some new
  escape tools and her ability to have multiple clones out at once, we feel like
  her damage potential against single targets is still a bit too high. Our data
  is showing that her talent tree is in a very good spot balance wise (besides a
  couple outliers, which you see here) so we are also lowering her base output
  and compensating by increasing Precision Sniper’s damage.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="samuro">Samuro</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Base Maximum Health increased from 1650 to 1725</li>
<li>Health Regen increased from 3.4 to 3.6</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Mirror Image (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Image Health increased from 825 to 862.5</li>
<li>Image Health Regen increased from 1.7 to 1.8</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Deflection (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Armor increased from 25 to 30</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Burning Blade (W)
<ul>
<li>Damage bonus decreased from 65 to 50%</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Phantom Pain (W)
<ul>
<li>Damage bonus increased from 40 to 45%</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Crushing Blows (W)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduction increased from 1.5 to 1.75 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> Samuro’s rework has put him in a good position
  regarding his talent pick and win rates, as well as his overall performance.
  In addition to some talent tuning changes, we decided to slightly increase his
  Health to compensate for the fact that he now has to put himself into
  dangerous positions much more often to deal damage.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="valeera">Valeera</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Garrote (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Silence duration reduced from 2.75 to 2.5 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Crippling Poison (Active)
<ul>
<li>Slow reduced from 25 to 20%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Hemorrhage (E)
<ul>
<li>Damage bonus reduced from 50 to 30%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> We’re reducing the duration of Garrote’s Silence
  slightly so that all openers feel viable, and reducing the damage of
  Hemorrhage so that Valeera doesn’t have as much damage while also being able
  to shut down her target.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="zeratul">Zeratul</h4>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Move Unseen (Trait)
<ul>
<li>Movement Speed increased from 25 to 30%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Darkness Descends (Active)
<ul>
<li>Passive Attack Speed bonus increased from 10 to 20%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Warp Skirmisher (1)
<ul>
<li>Bonus Attack Damage increased from 30 to 40%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> Zeratul currently has the lowest win rate out of all
  of our Stealth characters, so we’re tuning up some of his underperforming
  talents. He traditionally has been a high performer as players learn to master
  him, so we will be keeping an eye on him over time to see if he needs any more
  changes.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="support">Support</h3>

<h4 id="malfurion">Malfurion</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Basic Attack Damage reduced from 64 to 60</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Regrowth (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 45 to 35</li>
<li>No longer has an initial heal effect</li>
<li>Heal amount per tick decreased from 27 to 20</li>
<li>Duration increased from 15 to 20 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Moonfire (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 15 to 10</li>
<li>Damage reduced from 100 to 90</li>
<li>Added functionality:
<ul>
<li>For every enemy Hero hit with Moonfire, instantly heal all targets with an active Regrowth for 140</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Entangling Roots (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>No longer affects non-Heroic targets</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Tranquility (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Duration reduced from 10 to 8 seconds</li>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 100 to 80 seconds</li>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 100 to 80</li>
<li>Added functionality:
<ul>
<li>All Heroes with an active Regrowth effect gain 10 Armor while in range of Tranquility</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shan’do’s Clarity (D)
<ul>
<li>Functionality changed:
<ul>
<li>The cooldown of Innervate regenerates 25% faster for each active Regrowth</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><span class="text-warning">Celestial Alignment (W)</span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://twitter.com/Adunaiii/status/948627344020983808" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Reveal duration bonus reduced from 3 to 1 second</span></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Scouting Drone (Active)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>New Talent – Nature’s Swiftness (Q)
<ul>
<li>Malfurion passively gains 5% Movement Speed for each active Regrowth</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Full Moonfire (W)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li><span class="text-warning">Elune's Grace (Passive)</span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://twitter.com/Adunaiii/status/948555042474348544" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Removed</span></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Strangling Vines (E)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 7</li>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Enemy Heroes rooted by Entangling Roots receive 25% less healing for 2 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent – Deep Roots (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Entangling Roots grow 25% larger and last 25% longer</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Tenacious Roots (E)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16</li>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Root duration is increased by 25%. If Malfurion becomes stunned, refresh the cooldown of Entangling Roots</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent – Nature’s Cure (Active)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Activate: Remove all stuns, roots and slows from allies with an active Regrowth. 45 second cooldown.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent – Wild Growth (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Every time your Moonfire hits an enemy Hero, increase the duration of all active Regrowths by 1 second</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shrink Ray (Active)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Life Seed (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Revitalize (Q)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Hindering Moonfire (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 7</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Ysera’s Gift (Q)
<ul>
<li>Bonus heal amount increased from 40 to 60%</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent – Moonlit Harmony (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Increase the heal of your Moonfire by 15% for every active Regrowth</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent – Nature's Balance (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Increase the area of Moonfire by 25% and the duration of Regrowth by 5 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li>Serenity (R)
<ul>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Every Hero hit with Moonfire lowers the cooldown of Tranquility by 3 seconds. While active, Tranquility's healing is increased by 10% for each active Regrowth</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Storm Shield (Active)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Rewind (Active)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Lunar Shower (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 7</li>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Hitting an enemy Hero reduces the cooldown of Moonfire by 1 second and ramps the damage of the next Moonfire by 20%, stacking up to 3 times</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent – Lifebloom (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Casting Regrowth on a player instantly heals them for 10% of their missing Health</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><strong>LEVEL (TIER)</strong></th>
  <th><strong>Malfurion Talents</strong></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><strong>1 (1)</strong></td>
  <td><em>Nature's Swiftness (Q)</em></td>
  <td>Celestial Attunement (W)</td>
  <td>Shan'do's Clarity (D)</td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>4 (2)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Strangling Vines (E)</strong></td>
  <td><em>Deep Roots (E)</em></td>
  <td>(!) Vengeful Roots (E)</td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>7 (3)</strong></td>
  <td><em>Wild Growth (Passive)</em></td>
  <td><strong>Tenacious Roots (E)</strong></td>
  <td><em>Nature's Cure (Active)</em></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>10 (4)</strong></td>
  <td>Tranquility</td>
  <td>Twilight Dream</td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>13 (5)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Hindering Moonfire (W)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Revitalize (D)</strong></td>
  <td>Ice Block (Active)</td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>16 (6)</strong></td>
  <td>Ysera's Gift (Q)</td>
  <td><em>Nature's Balance (Passive)</em></td>
  <td><em>Moonlit Harmony (Passive)</em></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>20 (7)</strong></td>
  <td>Serenity (R)</td>
  <td>Astral Communion (R)</td>
  <td><em>Lifebloom (Q)</em></td>
  <td><strong>Lunar Shower (W)</strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<ul>
<li>(!) indicates a Questing Talent.</li>
<li><em>Italic text</em> indicates a <em>NEW</em> Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Bold</strong> text indicates a <strong>MOVED</strong> Talent.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> While Malfurion has had many adjustments and talent
  shuffles over the past couple of years, his healing mechanics have stayed
  relatively straight-forward. The core kit changes in this rework are intended
  to make his gameplay a bit more active. Turning offensive pressure directly
  into healing output should reinvigorate Malfurion mains while also greatly
  raising his skill ceiling. We are very excited to see what you think and are
  actively listening for any and all feedback you have – Elune grant us
  strength!</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="warrior">Warrior</h3>

<h4 id="blaze">Blaze</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Fortified Bunker (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Health increased from 1300 to 1305</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="garrosh">Garrosh</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Groundbreaker (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Slow amount increased from 30 to 35%</li>
<li>Cooldown decreased from 8 to 7 seconds</li>
<li>Mana cost decreased from 35 to 30</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Wrecking Ball (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cooldown decreased from 14 to 12 seconds</li>
<li>Mana cost decreased from 65 to 60</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Warbreaker (Q)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduction decreased from 3 to 2 seconds</li>
<li>Damage increased from 50 to 55</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Unrivaled Strength (E)
<ul>
<li>Bonus damage reduced from 125 to 75%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Into the Fray (1)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown increased from 40 to 45 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Earthshaker (E)
<ul>
<li>Stun duration reduced from .6 to .5 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Mortal Combo (E)
<ul>
<li>Cooldown reduction decreased from 8 to 7 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Rough Landing (Q)
<ul>
<li>Slow bonus amount decreased from 20 to 15%</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p><em><strong>Developer Comment:</strong></em> While the changes to Groundbreaker have helped
  Garrosh feel better to play against, we believe he can use some help with his
  ability to peel for his team and control the battlefield. We’re also making
  some tuning changes to his talents to help their pick and win rates.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<h4 id="johanna">Johanna</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Falling Sword (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Johanna can no longer take damage or be targeted while initially casting Falling Sword​ </li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#heroes">Return</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="collection">Collection</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Items in the Collection have received updated UI colors to improve readability</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Bundle</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Blaze Heroic Bundle – Available until January 22, 2017</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Announcer</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Blaze</li>
<li>Tyrael</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Skins</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Blaze</strong>
<ul>
<li>Hazardous Blaze</li>
<li>Veteran Blaze</li>
<li><strong>Fel Reaver Blaze</strong>
<ul>
<li>Abominable Fel Reaver Blaze</li>
<li>Coldfire Fel Reaver Blaze</li>
<li>Infernal Fel Reaver Blaze</li>
<li>Smoldering Fel Reaver Blaze</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Probius</strong>
<ul>
<li>Ara Tribe Probius</li>
<li>Nerazim Probius</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fixed a number of typo and tooltip errors across several aspects of the game.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Art</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Abathur:</strong> Casting Ultimate Evolution will no longer cause visual effects to persist on the terrain at Abathur’s previous location.</li>
<li><strong>Valla:</strong> The color of Lavendar Deputy Valla’s scarf has been updated to match the rest of the skin.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Abathur:</strong> Locusts will now correctly retain their selected skins during Ultimate Evolution.</li>
<li><strong>Chen:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Chen to become unresponsive if Wandering Keg’s duration expired while the barrel was too close to unpathable terrain.</li>
<li><strong>Garrosh:</strong> Talent descriptions for Inner Rage and Brute Force will no longer swap when selecting either Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Hanzo:</strong> Enemies hit by Storm Bow with the Explosive Arrows Talent will no longer be ignored by the Piercing Arrows Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Junkrat:</strong> Total Mayhem will no longer trigger twice if Junkrat is killed by the secondary Basic Attack damaged granted by the Giant Killer Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Junkrat:</strong> Casting Rocket Ride will no longer cause an empty Health Bar to appear.</li>
<li><strong>Junkrat:</strong> Fixed an issue in which Ripper Air could grant cooldown reduction to Concussion Mine if a Summon, such as a Creep Tumor, Healing Ward, etc., was also hit when the Mine was detonated.</li>
<li><strong>Nazeebo:</strong> Gargantuan Stomp can no longer be cast while the Gargantuan is stunned or polymorphed.</li>
<li><strong>Nazeebo:</strong> Fixed an issue causing Vile Infection to deal bonus damage after choosing certain talents.</li>
<li><strong>Samuro:</strong> Illusion Master can no longer be cast while Samuro is airborne after being hit by an effects like Junkrat’s Concussion Mine detonation.</li>
<li><strong>Samuro:</strong> Issuing a Hold Position command to Samuro’s Mirror Images and then selecting one of them will no longer cause the others to cancel the Hold Position command.</li>
<li><strong>Zul’jin:</strong> Lacerate’s Talent icon is now correctly colored blue, rather than purple.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">2018-01-02 PTR Patch Notes</title>
    <published>2018-01-02T19:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-02T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <id>https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-01-02-ptr-patch-notes.html</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://heroespatchnotes.com/patch/2018-01-02-ptr-patch-notes.html"/>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="heroes-of-the-storm-ptr-notes-january-2-2018">Heroes of the Storm PTR Notes — January 2, 2018</h1>

<div><img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/heroespatches/image/upload/v1494956881/patchlogo2017-05-16.jpg"></div><div class="official-link"><a class="official" href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21353256" target="_blank"></a><a href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en/blog/21353256" target="_blank">Official Patch Notes</a> <small>v 2.29.7</small></div>

<p>Our next Heroes of the Storm patch has just hit the Public Test Realm and will
be available for playtesting until January 8. During this time, we kindly
request your assistance in trying out the new content before we officially
release the patch. Just like last time, if you encounter any bugs or other
issues during your PTR play sessions, please stop by the <a href="http://us.battle.net/heroes/en/forum/20013840/">PTR Bug Report
forum</a> to let us know about
your experiences.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="new-hero-blaze">New Hero: Blaze</h3>

<p>Cpl. Miles "Blaze" Lewis has always been drawn to the flame, but it wasn't
until he joined up with Raynor's Raiders that he put his pyromania to good
use. He's seen his fair share of battles since then, and has never failed to
bring the heat.</p>

<p><strong>Trait</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Pyromania</strong>
<ul>
<li>Gain 25 Armor and deal 40 damage to nearby enemies every 0.5 seconds for 4 seconds. Each Hero hit by Flame Stream reduces Pyromania's cooldown by 5 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Basic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Flame Stream (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Fire two streams of flame that deal 83 damage to enemies hit. Flame Stream sets fire to Oil Spills it comes in contact with.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Oil Spill (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Vector Targeting. </li>
<li>Dispense a slick of oil that lasts for 5 seconds and Slows enemies that come in contact with it by 40%. Flame Stream can set Oil Spills on fire for 2.5 seconds, dealing 18 damage every 0.3 seconds to enemies inside. While on fire, Oil Spills no longer Slow enemies. Additionally, Blaze is Healed for 49 Health every 0.3 seconds while standing in flaming Oil Spills. Stores up to 2 charges.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Jet Propulsion (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>After 0.5 seconds, charge forward, colliding with the first enemy Hero hit, dealing 52 damage to them and nearby enemy Heroes. Enemies hit are also Stunned for 1.25 seconds.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroic Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Bunker Drop (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>After 0.5 seconds, deploy and enter a Bunker with 1300 Health. Blaze and his allies can enter and exit the Bunker at will. While in the Bunker, occupants gain access to Flamethrower, dealing 179 damage to enemies in a line. Exiting the Bunker grants 25 Armor for 2 seconds. Bunkers last 10 seconds, or until destroyed.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Combustion (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Channel up to 2.6 seconds. Once Channeling ends, nearby enemies are Slowed by 60% and take 48 damage every 0.5 seconds. Combustion's Slow and damage over time durations are extended the longer Blaze Channels, from 1 second up to 5 seconds. Blaze's Movement Speed is reduced by 50% while Channeling.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="art">Art</h3>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Malfurion has received updated visual effects to coincide with Talent changes.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="battlegrounds">Battlegrounds</h3>

<p>​<strong>Battlefield of Eternity</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Minimap will now indicate upcoming Immortal spawn locations 30 seconds after the game begins.
<ul>
<li>Subsequent Immortal indicators will appear on the Minimap shortly after a previously summoned Immortal has been defeated.</li>
<li>Swap locations will not appear on the Minimap when an Immortal has been reduced to 50% Health.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p>​<strong>Heroes Brawl</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Dodge Brawl</strong>
<ul>
<li>Chromie’s Health has been increased from 3 to 5</li>
<li>Ghost Chromies now display player names overhead</li>
<li>The in-game camera will now lock to Ghost Chromie until a new round begins</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Ranked Battleground Rotation</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Battleground rotation for Ranked Play has not been changed.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="heroes">Heroes</h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><a href="#support">Support</a></th>
  <th><a href="#warrior">Warrior</a></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><a href="#malfurion">Malfurion</a></td>
  <td><a href="#johanna">Johanna</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<hr />

<h3 id="support">Support</h3>

<h4 id="malfurion">Malfurion</h4>

<p><strong>Stats</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Basic Attack Damage reduced from 64 to 60</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Regrowth (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 45 to 35</li>
<li>No longer has an initial heal effect</li>
<li>Heal amount per tick decreased from 27 to 20</li>
<li>Duration increased from 15 to 20 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Moonfire (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 15 to 10</li>
<li>Damage reduced from 100 to 90</li>
<li>Added functionality:
<ul>
<li>For every enemy Hero hit with Moonfire, instantly heal all targets with an active Regrowth for 140</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Entangling Roots (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>No longer affects non-Heroic targets</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Tranquility (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Duration reduced from 10 to 8 seconds</li>
<li>Cooldown reduced from 100 to 80 seconds</li>
<li>Mana cost reduced from 100 to 80</li>
<li>Added functionality:
<ul>
<li>All Heroes with an active Regrowth effect gain 10 Armor while in range of Tranquility</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Level 1</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shan’do’s Clarity (D)
<ul>
<li>Functionality changed:
<ul>
<li>The cooldown of Innervate regenerates 25% faster for each active Regrowth</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><span class="text-warning">Celestial Alignment (W)</span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://twitter.com/Adunaiii/status/948627344020983808" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Reveal duration bonus reduced from 3 to 1 second</span></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Scouting Drone (Active)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>New Talent – Nature’s Swiftness (Q)
<ul>
<li>Malfurion passively gains 5% Movement Speed for each active Regrowth</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 4</strong>
<ul>
<li>Full Moonfire (W)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li><span class="text-warning">Elune's Grace (Passive)</span> <a class="label label-warning" href="https://twitter.com/Adunaiii/status/948555042474348544" target="_blank">Undocumented <i class="fa fa-external-link"></i></a>
<ul>
<li><span class="text-warning">Removed</span></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Strangling Vines (E)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 7</li>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Enemy Heroes rooted by Entangling Roots receive 25% less healing for 2 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent – Deep Roots (E)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Entangling Roots grow 25% larger and last 25% longer</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 7</strong>
<ul>
<li>Tenacious Roots (E)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16</li>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Root duration is increased by 25%. If Malfurion becomes stunned, refresh the cooldown of Entangling Roots</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent – Nature’s Cure (Active)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Activate: Remove all stuns, roots and slows from allies with an active Regrowth. 45 second cooldown.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent – Wild Growth (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Every time your Moonfire hits an enemy Hero, increase the duration of all active Regrowths by 1 second</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 13</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shrink Ray (Active)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Life Seed (Passive)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Revitalize (Q)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 16</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Hindering Moonfire (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 7</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 16</strong>
<ul>
<li>Ysera’s Gift (Q)
<ul>
<li>Bonus heal amount increased from 40 to 60%</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent – Moonlit Harmony (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Increase the heal of your Moonfire by 15% for every active Regrowth</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent – Nature's Balance (W)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Increase the area of Moonfire by 25% and the duration of Regrowth by 5 seconds</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Level 20</strong>
<ul>
<li>Serenity (R)
<ul>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Every Hero hit with Moonfire lowers the cooldown of Tranquility by 3 seconds. While active, Tranquility's healing is increased by 10% for each active Regrowth</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Storm Shield (Active)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Rewind (Active)
<ul>
<li>Removed</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Lunar Shower (W)
<ul>
<li>Moved from Level 7</li>
<li>New functionality:
<ul>
<li>Hitting an enemy Hero reduces the cooldown of Moonfire by 1 second and ramps the damage of the next Moonfire by 20%, stacking up to 3 times</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>New Talent – Lifebloom (Q)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Casting Regrowth on a player instantly heals them for 10% of their missing Health</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
  <th><strong>LEVEL (TIER)</strong></th>
  <th><strong>Malfurion Talents</strong></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
  <td><strong>1 (1)</strong></td>
  <td><em>Nature's Swiftness (Q)</em></td>
  <td>Celestial Alignment (W)</td>
  <td>Shan'do's Clarity (D)</td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>4 (2)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Strangling Vines (E)</strong></td>
  <td><em>Deep Roots (E)</em></td>
  <td>(!) Vengeful Roots (E)</td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>7 (3)</strong></td>
  <td><em>Wild Growth (Passive)</em></td>
  <td><strong>Tenacious Roots (E)</strong></td>
  <td><em>Nature's Cure (Active)</em></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>10 (4)</strong></td>
  <td>Tranquility</td>
  <td>Twilight Dream</td>
  <td>—</td>
  <td>—</td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>13 (5)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Hindering Moonfire (W)</strong></td>
  <td><strong>Revitalize (D)</strong></td>
  <td>Ice Block (Active)</td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>16 (6)</strong></td>
  <td>Ysera's Gift (Q)</td>
  <td><em>Nature's Balance (Passive)</em></td>
  <td><em>Moonlit Harmony (Passive)</em></td>
  <td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
  <td><strong>20 (7)</strong></td>
  <td>Serenity (R)</td>
  <td>Astral Communion (R)</td>
  <td><em>Lifebloom (Q)</em></td>
  <td><strong>Lunar Shower (W)</strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<ul>
<li>(!) indicates a Questing Talent.</li>
<li><em>Italic text</em> indicates a <em>NEW</em> Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Bold</strong> text indicates a <strong>MOVED</strong> Talent.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="warrior">Warrior</h3>

<h4 id="johanna">Johanna</h4>

<p><strong>Abilities</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Falling Sword (R)</strong>
<ul>
<li>Johanna can no longer take damage or be targeted while initially casting Falling Sword​ </li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="collection">Collection</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Items in the Collection have received updated UI colors to improve readability</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Bundle</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Blaze Heroic Bundle – Available until January 22, 2017</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Announcer</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Blaze</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>New Skins</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Blaze</strong>
<ul>
<li>Hazardous Blaze</li>
<li>Veteran Blaze</li>
<li><strong>Fel Reaver Blaze</strong>
<ul>
<li>Abominable Fel Reaver Blaze</li>
<li>Coldfire Fel Reaver Blaze</li>
<li>Infernal Fel Reaver Blaze</li>
<li>Smoldering Fel Reaver Blaze</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Probius</strong>
<ul>
<li>Ara Tribe Probius</li>
<li>Nerazim Probius</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h3>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fixed a number of typo and tooltip errors across several aspects of the game.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Art</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Abathur:</strong> Casting Ultimate Evolution will no longer cause visual effects to persist on the terrain at Abathur’s previous location.</li>
<li><strong>Valla:</strong> The color of Lavendar Deputy Valla’s scarf has been updated to match the rest of the skin.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Heroes, Abilities, and Talents</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Abathur:</strong> Locusts will now correctly retain their selected skins during Ultimate Evolution.</li>
<li><strong>Chen:</strong> Fixed an issue that could cause Chen to become unresponsive if Wandering Keg’s duration expired while the barrel was too close to unpathable terrain.</li>
<li><strong>Garrosh:</strong> Talent descriptions for Inner Rage and Brute Force will no longer swap when selecting either Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Junkrat:</strong> Total Mayhem will no longer trigger twice if Junkrat is killed by the secondary Basic Attack damaged granted by the Giant Killer Talent.</li>
<li><strong>Junkrat:</strong> Casting Rocket Ride will no longer cause an empty Health Bar to appear.</li>
<li><strong>Junkrat:</strong> Fixed an issue in which Ripper Air could grant cooldown reduction to Concussion Mine if a Summon, such as a Creep Tumor, Healing Ward, etc., was also hit when the Mine was detonated.</li>
<li><strong>Nazeebo:</strong> Gargantuan Stomp can no longer be cast while the Gargantuan is Stunned or Polymorphed.</li>
<li><strong>Samuro:</strong> Illusion Master can no longer be cast while Samuro is airborne after being hit by effects like Junkrat’s Concussion Mine detonation.</li>
<li><strong>Samuro:</strong> Issuing a Hold Position command to Samuro’s Mirror Images and then selecting one of them will no longer cause the others to cancel the Hold Position command.</li>
<li><strong>Zul’jin:</strong> Lacerate’s Talent icon is now correctly colored blue, rather than purple.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Return to Top</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
</feed>